{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Data entities - Public sector\ndescription: This article provides a list of the data entities that are available for Public sector.\nauthor: kfend\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: reference\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer\n# ms.devlang: \n# ms.reviewer: 51\nms.search.scope: AX 7.0.0, Operations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 96313\nms.assetid: 688cf2da-b57a-434c-895d-e822316e7ea9\nms.search.region: Global\nms.search.industry: Public sector\nms.author: kfend\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Data entities - Public sector\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThis article provides a list of the data entities that are available for Public sector.\n\nAvailable data entities\n-----------------------\n\nThe setup for a public sector company uses the same data packages as the setup for a commercial company. However, it also uses additional packages that contain the data entities for public sector–specific features. The sequence in the following table refers to the packages that are described in other related data entity articles, and also contains details for the public sector–specific data entities. Additionally, the heading for each subsection contains a hyperlink to the corresponding related article. Note that, unless otherwise stated, any warnings and notes in the linked articles also pertain to Public sector.\n\n\n**[System administration](data-entities-system-administration.md) and [Global address book](data-entities-global-address-book.md)**\n\n| Suggested sequence | Package                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                       |\n|--------------------|-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| 1                  | 01.1.001 SYS – Currencies                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                     |\n| 2                  | 01.1.002.SYS – System parameters                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                              |\n| 3                  | 01.1.003 SYS – Address basic setup for legal entities                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                         |\n| 4                  | 01.1.004 SYS – Address prerequisites for legal entities                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                       |\n| 5                  | 01.1.005 SYS – Address setup Note: The issue that is related to failing records in the Cities entity won’t occur for public sector data.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                      |\n| 6                  | 01.1.006 SYS – Legal entities                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                 |\n| 7                  | 01.1.007 SYS – Operating units                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                |\n| 8                  | 01.1.008 SYS – Organization hierarchies Note: Export is Organization Hierarchy – Published, and import is Organization Hierarchy. Each hierarchy must be published manually. To manually publish a hierarchy, click Organization administration > Organizations > Organization hierarchies, and select Budget planning. On the Action Pane, click View > Edit > Keep working on this draft, and then click OK. Verify that the hierarchy is accurate, and then click Publish. Enter the current date, and then click Publish. |\n| 9                  | 01.1.009 SYS – Units                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                          |\n| 10                 | 01.1.010 SYS – Number sequences Note: Some number sequence record files will fail. These records are linked to the companies other than PSUS.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                 |\n| 11                 | 01.1.011 SYS – Organizational calendar                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        |\n| 12                 | 01.1.012 SYS – System users                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                   |\n| 13                 | 01.1.013 SYS – Document types                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                 |\n| 14                 | 02.1.001 GAB – Teams                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                          |\n| 15                 | 02.1.002 GAB – Post address setup                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                             |\n\n**[Workflow](data-entities-workflow.md)**\n\n| Suggested sequence | Package                |\n|--------------------|------------------------|\n| 16                 | 02.1.003 WF – Workflow |\n\n**[General ledger](data-entities-general-ledger.md) and [Bank](data-entities-bank.md)**\n06.1.001 PubSect – Funds\n\n| Suggested sequence | Entity name | Area           | Entity type | Dependency | Comments                                                                    |\n|--------------------|-------------|----------------|-------------|------------|-----------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| 17                 | Fund types  | General ledger | Setup       | None       | Categorization of funds. Categorization is typically completed by function. |\n| 18                 | Fund        | General ledger | Setup       | Fund types |                                                                             |\n \n| Suggested sequence | Package                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                       |\n|--------------------|-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| 19                 | 03.1.001 GL – Chart of accounts – Shared. Note: Activate financial dimensions, and then import the Financial dimension sets data entity again. To activate financial dimensions, click General ledger > Chart of accounts > Dimensions > Financial dimensions, and select Close on pop up. On the Action Pane, click Activate, and then, on the Activate financial dimensions page, click Activate. The posting type must be added to the Sales tax payable and Use tax payable main accounts. Click General ledger > Chart of accounts > Accounts > Main accounts, and open account 24800. On the Posting validation FastTab, in the Posting type field, select Sales tax. Repeat for this procedure for main account 24801. |\n| 20                 | 03.1.002 GL – Account structures – Shared. There is a known issue on export in PSUS for the Advanced rule structure allowed values and Account structure allowed values data entities. No values are exported for these two data entities. The package on Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS) has been modified.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                      |\n| 21                 | 03.1.003 GL – Fiscal calendar – Shared                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        |\n| 22                 | 03.1.004 GL – Ledger setup. If you’re using demo data, records will fail in the Ledger fiscal calendar period data entity because of closed periods that can’t be reopened.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                   |\n| 23                 | 03.1.005 GL – Ledger journals. Records will fail in the Journal names data entity until the Bank accounts data entity is imported. After the bank accounts are imported, import the Journal names data entity again.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                          |\n\n06.1.002 PubSect – Posting definition setup\nIf you’re using demo data, some records will fail in the Posting definition entry data entity because of a known issue.\n\n| Suggested sequence | Entity name                                   | Area           | Entity type | Dependency                       | Comments                                                                                                                                                                                                                     |\n|--------------------|-----------------------------------------------|----------------|-------------|----------------------------------|------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| 24                 | Posting definition                            | General ledger | Setup       | None                             |                                                                                                                                                                                                                              |\n| 25                 | Posting definition entry                      | General ledger | Setup       | Posting definition               | The lines that are associated with each posting definition                                                                                                                                                                   |\n| 26                 | Transaction posting definition Bank           | General ledger | Setup       | Posting definition               | The association of the posting definition with the Bank module                                                                                                                                                               |\n| 27                 | Transaction posting definition General ledger | General ledger | Setup       | Posting definition               | The association of the posting definition with the General ledger module                                                                                                                                                     |\n| 28                 | Transaction posting definition Payable        | General ledger | Setup       | Posting definition               | The association of the posting definition with the Payable module                                                                                                                                                            |\n| 29                 | Transaction posting definition Purchasing     | General ledger | Setup       | Posting definition               | The association of the posting definition with the Purchasing module                                                                                                                                                         |\n| 30                 | Transaction posting definition Receivable     | General ledger | Setup       | Posting definition               | The association of the posting definition with the Receivable module                                                                                                                                                         |\n| 31                 | Transaction posting definition Budget         | General ledger | Setup       | Posting definition, Budget Setup | The association of the posting definition with the Budget module. Note: Budget setup is a dependency for the Transactional posting definition budget. Therefore, this data entity is included with the Budget setup package. |\n\n\n| Suggested sequence | Package                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                         |\n|--------------------|-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| 32                 | 03.1.006 GL – Allocations                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                       |\n| 33                 | 03.1.007 BANK – Bank setup                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                      |\n| 34                 | 03.1.008 BANK – Bank accounts. Note: If you’re using demo data, remove NSFJournalName from the Bank accounts data entity import file, and re-import Journal names. Then, on the Payment management tab, in the NSF payment journal field for bank accounts PSUS Oper and PSUS Payrol, select CustPay. NSFJournalName has been removed from the Bank accounts data entity in the package on LCS. |\n| 35                 | Re-import 03.1.005 – Ledger journals                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            |\n\n06.8.001 PubSect – Advanced ledger entry lines\nIf you’re using demo data, many records will fail because of dependencies on Project. After the Project master data entity is imported, import the Advanced ledger entry lines data entity again.\n\nBecause of a known issue with demo data, the posting definition isn’t attached to many lines. The package on LCS has been modified.\n\n| Suggested sequence | Entity name                 | Area           | Entity type | Dependency                                | Comments                                                                              |\n|--------------------|-----------------------------|----------------|-------------|-------------------------------------------|---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| 36                 | Advanced ledger entry lines | General ledger | Transaction | General ledger setup, Posting definitions | The general ledger entry that is source document–enabled and uses posting definitions |\n\n**[Human resources](data-entities-human-resources.md)**\n\n| Suggested sequence | Package                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                  |\n|--------------------|------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| 37                 | 05.1.001 HR – Foundation setup                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                           |\n| 38                 | 05.1.002 HR – Competencies                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                               |\n| 39                 | 05.1.003 HR – Jobs                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                       |\n| 40                 | 05.1.004 – Pay                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                           |\n| 41                 | 05.1.005 HR – Employees                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                  |\n| 42                 | 05.1.006 HR – Contractor                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                 |\n| 43                 | 05.1.011 HR – Benefits. Pay cycle and Pay period are dependencies for this entity, but payroll DEs aren’t available. Manually generate the pay periods for the pay cycle, and then re-import Calculation frequency pay period.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                           |\n| 44                 | 05.1.007 HR – Positions                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                  |\n| 45                 | 05.1.008 HR – Worker details                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                             |\n| 46                 | 05.1.009 HR – Compensation                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                               |\n| 47                 | 05.1.010 HR – Absence                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    |\n| 48                 | 05.1.012 HR – Performance                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                |\n| 49                 | 05.1.013 HR – Courses. If you receive a record that has Fail in the Courses data entity, import this data entity after you import vendors. Note: There is a known demo data issue with the Course types data entity. The package on LCS has been modified.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                               |\n| 50                 | 05.1.014 HR – Recruitment. You must manually start the recruitment projects. Click Human resources > Recruitment > Recruitment projects > Recruitment projects, and select the Bookkeeper project. Then, on the Action Pane, click Recruitment project status. Repeat this procedure for each project, and then import Applications again. Note: Records will fail in the Applicants data entity because of a known issue that is related to effective and expiration dates. Records will also fail in the Applications data entity because of dependency on the Applicants data entity. |\n| 51                 | 05.1.015 HR – Employee related associations. Note: See the comment for the Employee fixed compensation data entity in the Data entities: Human resources article. If you’re using demo data, the Injury and illness incidents data entity will fail. The package on LCS has been modified.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                               |\n| 52                 | 05.1.016 HR – Human resources parameters. Note: If you’re using demo data, the Human resources parameters data entity will fail. The package on LCS has been modified.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                   |\n| 53                 | 05.1.017 HR – Shared human resources parameters. Note: If you’re using demo data, the Shared human resources parameters data entity will fail. The package on LCS has been modified.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                     |\n\n**[Accounts payable and taxes](data-entities-accounts-payable-taxes.md)**\n\n| Suggested sequence | Package                                                                                                                                                                                                                             |\n|--------------------|-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| 54                 | 10.1.001 AP – AP and AR shared setup                                                                                                                                                                                                |\n| 55                 | 10.1.002 AP – Vendor payment setup                                                                                                                                                                                                  |\n| 56                 | 10.1.003 AP – Vendor attributes                                                                                                                                                                                                     |\n| 57                 | 10.1.006 Tax – Sales tax setup. Note: Some records in Sales tax authorities and Sales tax period setup will fail because of dependencies on Vendors. You should re-import this package after the Vendors package has been imported. |\n| 58                 | 10.1.007 Tax – Sales tax code groups. Note: Some records in this package will fail because of dependencies on Vendors. You should re-import this package after the Vendors package has been imported.                               |\n| 59                 | 10.1.004 AP – Vendors                                                                                                                                                                                                               |\n| 60                 | 06.1.003 PubSect – Vendor certification types                                                                            \n|\n\n| Suggested sequence | Entity name                | Area             | Entity type | Dependency | Comments                                                                                                   |\n|--------------------|----------------------------|------------------|-------------|------------|------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| 61                 | Vendor certification types | Accounts payable | Setup       | None       | Vendor attribute that are related to specific functions that are performed or certifications that are held |\n\n\n| Suggested sequence | Package                                        |\n|--------------------|------------------------------------------------|\n| 62                 | Re-import 10.1.006 Tax – Sales tax setup       |\n| 63                 | Re-import 10.1.007 Tax – Sales tax code groups |\n| 64                 | Re-import 05.1.013 HR – Courses                |\n| 65                 | 10.1.005 AP – AP Parameters                    |\n| 66                 | 10.1.008 Tax – Sales tax parameters            |\n\n**[Accounts receivable](data-entities-accounts-receivable.md)**\n\nIf you’re implementing Accounts receivable but aren't using Accounts payable, you should use the 10.1.001 AP and AR shared setup package. For details about that package, see [Data entities: Accounts payable and taxes](data-entities-accounts-payable-taxes.md).\n\n| Suggested sequence | Package                                                                                                                                                                          |\n|--------------------|----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| 67                 | 11.1.001 AR – Customer payment setup                                                                                                                                             |\n| 68                 | 11.1.002 AR – Customer attributes                                                                                                                                                |\n| 69                 | 11.1.003 AR – Customers                                                                                                                                                          |\n| 70                 | 11.1.004 AR – Accounts receivable parameters                                                                                                                                     |\n| 71                 | 06.1.004 PubSect – Billing classification and codes. Note: Records will fail because of dependencies on Interest codes and Collection. The package on LCS has not been modified. |\n\n| Suggested sequence | Entity name                                    | Area                | Entity type | Dependency                                                       | Comments                                                                                                                       |\n|--------------------|------------------------------------------------|---------------------|-------------|------------------------------------------------------------------|--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| 72                 | Billing classification                         | Accounts Receivable | Setup       | Interest codes US and Collection letters                         | Setup data for classifying details such as the main account, to make it easier to create a group and, in turn, vendor invoices |\n| 73                 | Billing code with billing code version         | Accounts Receivable | Setup       | Billing classification, Interest codes US and Collection letters | The component details that make up the billing classification                                                                  |\n| 74                 | Billing classification with billing code       | Accounts Receivable | Setup       | Billing classification, Billing code                             |                                                                                                                                |\n| 75                 | Billing code custom field                      | Accounts Receivable | Setup       | Billing code                                                     |                                                                                                                                |\n| 76                 | Billing code with accounting distribution      | Accounts Receivable | Setup       | Billing code                                                     |                                                                                                                                |\n| 77                 | Billing codes with billing code customer field | Accounts Receivable | Setup       | Billing code                                                     |                                                                                                                                |\n| 78                 | Billing code with billing code rate            | Accounts Receivable | Setup       | Billing code                                                     |                                                                                                                                |\n\n\n**[Budgeting](data-entities-budgeting.md)**\nAll General ledger data entities and the setup are a prerequisite for importing Budgeting data entities. For more information about General ledger data entities, and to confirm that the setup is completed, see Data entities: General ledger.\n\n| Suggested sequence | Package                               |\n|--------------------|---------------------------------------|\n| 79                 | 12.1.001 BUD – Ledger budget setup    |\n| 80                 | 12.1.002 BUD – Budget control setup   |\n| 81                 | 12.8.001 BUD – Budget account entries |\n\n\n**[Budget planning](data-entities-budget-plan.md)**\n\n| Suggested sequence | Package                                                                                                                                                             |\n|--------------------|---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| 82                 | 12.1.003 BUD – Budget planning setup. A demo data issue will cause records to fail in the Budget plan stage rule data entity. The package on LCS has been modified. |\n| 83                 | 12.01.004 BUD – Forecast position                                                                                                                                   |\n\n\n**[Costing](data-entities-costing.md)**\n\n| Suggested sequence | Package                      |\n|--------------------|------------------------------|\n| 84                 | 15.1.001 COS – Costing setup |\n\n**[Inventory management](data-entities-inventory-management.md)**\n\n| Suggested sequence | Package                             |\n|--------------------|-------------------------------------|\n| 85                 | 19.1.001 INV – Site setup           |\n| 86                 | 19.1.002 INV – Warehouse setup      |\n| 87                 | 19.1.003 INV – Group setup          |\n| 88                 | 19.1.004 INV – Journal setup        |\n| 89                 | 19.1.005 INV – Packing setup        |\n| 90                 | 19.1.006 INV – Posting definitions  |\n| 91                 | 19.1.008 INV – Inventory parameters |\n| 92                 | 19.1.007 INV – Price discount setup |\n| 93                 | 19.4.001 INV – Charge groups        |\n\n**[Fixed assets](data-entities-fixed-assets.md)**\n\n| Suggested sequence | Package                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                           |\n|--------------------|---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| 94                 | 16.01.001 FA – Fixed assets attributes                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            |\n| 95                 | 16.01.002 FA – Fixed assets setup. Note: On the Fixed asset parameters data entity, unmap DefaultValueModelID. If you’re using demo data, records in the Fixed asset value model data entity will fail because of missing depreciation profiles. The package on LCS has been modified for import. |\n| 96                 | 16.01.003 FA – Fixed assets. Note: If you’re using demo data, records in the Fixed asset value model data entity will fail because of missing depreciation profiles. The package on LCS has been modified for import.                                                                             |\n\n**[Product information management](data-entities-product-information-management.md)**\n\n| Suggested sequence | Package                                                                                                                                                                                                                |\n|--------------------|------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| 97                 | 24.1.001 PIM – Dimension groups                                                                                                                                                                                        |\n| 98                 | 24.1.002 PIM – Product variant groups                                                                                                                                                                                  |\n| 99                 | 24.1.003 PIM – Size assignments                                                                                                                                                                                        |\n| 100                | 24.1.004 PIM – Color assignments                                                                                                                                                                                       |\n| 101                | 24.1.005 PIM – Style assignments                                                                                                                                                                                       |\n| 102                | 24.1.006 PIM – Category setup. Note: Before you proceed, confirm that product categories are accurately set up.                                                                                                        |\n| 103                | 24.1.007 PIM – Attribute types                                                                                                                                                                                         |\n| 104                | 24.1.008 PIM – Product attributes. Note: If you’re using demo data, records in the Product attributes data entity will fail because of missing depreciation profiles. The package on LCS has been modified for import. |\n| 105                | 24.4.001 PIM – Attribute groups                                                                                                                                                                                        |\n| 106                | 24.4.002 PIM – Products – Shared                                                                                                                                                                                       |\n| 107                | 24.4.003 PIM – Product UOM conversion                                                                                                                                                                                  |\n| 108                | 24.4.004 PIM – Product variants                                                                                                                                                                                        |\n| 109                | 24.4.005 PIM – Released product creation. Note: This is used if Products fails.                                                                                                                                        |\n| 110                | 24.4.006 PIM – Released products                                                                                                                                                                                       |\n| 111                | 24.4.007 PIM – Released product variants                                                                                                                                                                               |\n| 112                | 24.4.008 PIM – Category attributes                                                                                                                                                                                     |\n| 113                | 24.4.009 PIM – Attribute values                                                                                                                                                                                        |\n\n**[Procurement and sourcing](data-entities-procurement-sourcing.md)**\n\n| Suggested sequence | Package                                                                                                                                                                                                                          |\n|--------------------|----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| 114                | 23.1.001 PRO – Summary parameters                                                                                                                                                                                                |\n| 115                | 23.1.002 PRO – Purchase order setup                                                                                                                                                                                              |\n| 116                | 23.1.003 PRO – Distribution setup                                                                                                                                                                                                |\n| 117                | 23.1.004 PRO – Form setup                                                                                                                                                                                                        |\n| 118                | 23.1.005 PRO – Prices discounts setup                                                                                                                                                                                            |\n| 119                | 23.1.006 PRO – External item setup                                                                                                                                                                                               |\n| 120                | 23.1.007 PRO – Vendor setup                                                                                                                                                                                                      |\n| 121                | 23.1.008 PRO – Supp item setup                                                                                                                                                                                                   |\n| 122                | 23.1.009 PRO – Rebate setup                                                                                                                                                                                                      |\n| 123                | 23.1.010 PRO – Price tol setup                                                                                                                                                                                                   |\n| 124                | 23.1.011 PRO – Discount groups setup                                                                                                                                                                                             |\n| 125                | 23.1.012 PRO – Policies setup. Note: The Procurement type document default values data entity will fail because a dependent data entity, Return actions, is missing. The package on LCS has been modified to make import easier. |\n| 126                | 23.1.013 PRO – Purchase agreement classification                                                                                                                                                                                 |\n\n06.1.005 PubSect – PO commitment\n\n| Suggested sequence | Entity name      | Area        | Entity type | Dependency | Comments                                     |\n|--------------------|------------------|-------------|-------------|------------|----------------------------------------------|\n| 127                | Confirming PO    | Procurement | Setup       | None       | Description of the types of PO confirmations |\n| 128                | Commitment lines | Procurement | Setup       | None       |                                              |\n\n\n| Suggested sequence | Package                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                         |\n|--------------------|-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| 129                | 23.4.001 PRO – Charges setup                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    |\n| 130                | 23.4.002 PRO – Purchase agreements. Note: Before you import the package, reset the number sequence for Purchase agreement ID to 1, and then unmap PurchaseAgreementID.                                                                                                                          |\n| 131                | 23.4.003 PRO – Purchase agreement lines                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                         |\n| 132                | 23.8.001 PRO – Purchase orders. Note: Before you import the package, reset the number sequence for the Purchase order ID to 1, and unmap ReasonCode. Some records will fail because of a Project dependency. Re-import this package after you import the Project master data entity dependency. |\n| 133                | 23.8.002 PRO – Purchase order lines. Note: If you’re using demo data, records will fail due to Project and Fixed assets dependencies. Re-import this package after you import Project master and all Fixed asset packages.                                                                      |\n\n**[Project accounting](data-entities-project-accounting.md)**\n\n| Suggested sequence | Package                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                  |\n|--------------------|----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| 134                | 26.1.001 PA – Projects setup                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                             |\n| 135                | 26.1.002 PA – Journals setup                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                             |\n| 136                | 26.1.003 PA – Estimates setup                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            |\n| 137                | 26.1.004 PA – Forms setup                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                |\n| 138                | 26.1.005 PA – Resourcing setup. Note: Review the warnings in the “Resourcing setup” section in the Data entities: Project accounting article.                                                                                                                                                                                                            |\n| 139                | 26.1.006 PA – Project periods                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            |\n| 140                | 26.1.007 PA – Categories, posting, and line property. Note: If you’re using demo data, records will fail in the Line property setup because of a dependency on Projects. Re-import this package after you’ve imported the Project master data entity.                                                                                                    |\n| 141                | 26.1.008 PA – Forecasts setup                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            |\n| 142                | 26.1.009 PA – Retention setup                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            |\n|                    | Important: Before you proceed with additional data import, you must manually set up Project management and accounting parameters, because that information is required in order to complete the remaining steps.                                      |\n| 143                | 26.1.010 PA – Grants setup                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                               |\n| 144                | 26.1.011 PA – Project contracts. Note: Records will fail in Project funding source data entity because of a dependency on Grants. You must manually set up Grants from demo data by using the components that were imported in 26.1.010 PA – Grants setup. Records will fail in Project funding rule because of a dependency on Project funding sources. |\n| 145                | 26.1.012 PA – Inventory project consumption setup                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        |\n| 146                | 26.1.013 PA – Projects master. Review the warnings in the section for the Project master data entity in the Data entities: Project accounting article.                                                                                                                                                                                                   |\n| 147                | Re-import 26.1.007 PA – Categories, posting, and line property                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                           |\n| 148                | 26.1.014 PA – Validation setup. Review the warnings in the section for the Validation setup data entity in the Data entities: Project accounting article.                                                                                                                                                                                                |\n| 149                | 26.1.015 PA – Pricing setup                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                              |\n| 150                | 26.1.016 PA – Indirect costs setup                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                       |\n| 151                | 26.8.001 – Project beginning balance. Review the warnings in the section for the Project beginning balance data entity in the Data entities: Project accounting article.                                                                                                                                                                                 |\n| 152                | 26.8.002 – Project hour and fee journal transactions. Review the warnings in the section for the Project hour and fee journal transactions data entity in the Data entities: Project accounting article.                                                                                                                                                 |\n| 153                | Re-import 06.8.001 PubSect – Advanced ledger entry lines                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                 |\n| 154                | Re-import 23.8.001 PRO – Purchase orders                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                 |\n| 155                | Re-import 23.8.002 PRO – Purchase order lines                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            |\n\nSee also\n--------\n\n[Data entities and packages framework](data-entities-data-packages.md)\n\n[Data entities](data-entities.md)\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,658],"nodes":[{"content":"Data entities - Public sector","nodes":[{"pos":[0,29],"content":"Data entities - Public sector","nodes":[{"content":"Data entities - Public sector","pos":[0,29]}]}],"pos":[27,57],"yaml":true},{"content":"This article provides a list of the data entities that are available for Public sector.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,87],"content":"This article provides a list of the data entities that are available for Public sector.","nodes":[{"content":"This article provides a list of the data entities that are available for Public sector.","pos":[0,87]}]}],"pos":[70,158],"yaml":true}],"content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Data entities - Public sector\ndescription: This article provides a list of the data entities that are available for Public sector.\nauthor: kfend\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: reference\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer\n# ms.devlang: \n# ms.reviewer: 51\nms.search.scope: AX 7.0.0, Operations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 96313\nms.assetid: 688cf2da-b57a-434c-895d-e822316e7ea9\nms.search.region: Global\nms.search.industry: Public sector\nms.author: kfend\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n","yamlblock":true},{"pos":[666,695],"content":"Data entities - Public sector","linkify":"Data entities - Public sector","nodes":[{"content":"Data entities - Public sector","pos":[0,29]}]},{"content":"This article provides a list of the data entities that are available for Public sector.","pos":[741,828]},{"pos":[830,853],"content":"Available data entities","linkify":"Available data entities","nodes":[{"content":"Available data entities","pos":[0,23]}]},{"content":"The setup for a public sector company uses the same data packages as the setup for a commercial company.","pos":[879,983]},{"content":"However, it also uses additional packages that contain the data entities for public sector–specific features.","pos":[984,1093]},{"content":"The sequence in the following table refers to the packages that are described in other related data entity articles, and also contains details for the public sector–specific data entities.","pos":[1094,1282]},{"content":"Additionally, the heading for each subsection contains a hyperlink to the corresponding related article.","pos":[1283,1387]},{"content":"Note that, unless otherwise stated, any warnings and notes in the linked articles also pertain to Public sector.","pos":[1388,1500]},{"pos":[1503,1634],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>System administration<ept id=\"p2\">](data-entities-system-administration.md)</ept> and <bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt>Global address book<ept id=\"p3\">](data-entities-global-address-book.md)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**[System administration](data-entities-system-administration.md) and [Global address book](data-entities-global-address-book.md)**"},{"content":"Suggested sequence","pos":[1638,1656]},{"content":"Package","pos":[1659,1666]},{"content":"1","pos":[2708,2709]},{"content":"01.1.001 SYS – Currencies","pos":[2729,2754]},{"content":"2","pos":[3243,3244]},{"content":"01.1.002.SYS – System parameters","pos":[3264,3296]},{"content":"3","pos":[3778,3779]},{"content":"01.1.003 SYS – Address basic setup for legal entities","pos":[3799,3852]},{"content":"4","pos":[4313,4314]},{"content":"01.1.004 SYS – Address prerequisites for legal entities","pos":[4334,4389]},{"content":"5","pos":[4848,4849]},{"content":"01.1.005 SYS – Address setup Note: The issue that is related to failing records in the Cities entity won’t occur for public sector data.","pos":[4869,5005]},{"content":"6","pos":[5383,5384]},{"content":"01.1.006 SYS – Legal entities","pos":[5404,5433]},{"content":"7","pos":[5918,5919]},{"content":"01.1.007 SYS – Operating units","pos":[5939,5969]},{"content":"8","pos":[6453,6454]},{"content":"01.1.008 SYS – Organization hierarchies Note: Export is Organization Hierarchy – Published, and import is Organization Hierarchy.","pos":[6474,6603]},{"content":"Each hierarchy must be published manually.","pos":[6604,6646]},{"content":"To manually publish a hierarchy, click Organization administration &gt; Organizations &gt; Organization hierarchies, and select Budget planning.","pos":[6647,6785],"source":" To manually publish a hierarchy, click Organization administration > Organizations > Organization hierarchies, and select Budget planning."},{"content":"On the Action Pane, click View &gt; Edit &gt; Keep working on this draft, and then click OK.","pos":[6786,6872],"source":" On the Action Pane, click View > Edit > Keep working on this draft, and then click OK."},{"content":"Verify that the hierarchy is accurate, and then click Publish.","pos":[6873,6935]},{"content":"Enter the current date, and then click Publish.","pos":[6936,6983]},{"content":"9","pos":[6988,6989]},{"content":"01.1.009 SYS – Units","pos":[7009,7029]},{"content":"10","pos":[7523,7525]},{"content":"01.1.010 SYS – Number sequences Note: Some number sequence record files will fail.","pos":[7544,7626]},{"content":"These records are linked to the companies other than PSUS.","pos":[7627,7685]},{"content":"11","pos":[8058,8060]},{"content":"01.1.011 SYS – Organizational calendar","pos":[8079,8117]},{"content":"12","pos":[8593,8595]},{"content":"01.1.012 SYS – System users","pos":[8614,8641]},{"content":"13","pos":[9128,9130]},{"content":"01.1.013 SYS – Document types","pos":[9149,9178]},{"content":"14","pos":[9663,9665]},{"content":"02.1.001 GAB – Teams","pos":[9684,9704]},{"content":"15","pos":[10198,10200]},{"content":"02.1.002 GAB – Post address setup","pos":[10219,10252]},{"pos":[10732,10773],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Workflow<ept id=\"p2\">](data-entities-workflow.md)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**[Workflow](data-entities-workflow.md)**"},{"content":"Suggested sequence","pos":[10777,10795]},{"content":"Package","pos":[10798,10805]},{"content":"16","pos":[10873,10875]},{"content":"02.1.003 WF – Workflow","pos":[10894,10916]},{"pos":[10920,11032],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>General ledger<ept id=\"p2\">](data-entities-general-ledger.md)</ept> and <bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt>Bank<ept id=\"p3\">](data-entities-bank.md)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> 06.1.001 PubSect – Funds","source":"**[General ledger](data-entities-general-ledger.md) and [Bank](data-entities-bank.md)**\n06.1.001 PubSect – Funds"},{"content":"Suggested sequence","pos":[11036,11054]},{"content":"Entity name","pos":[11057,11068]},{"content":"Area","pos":[11071,11075]},{"content":"Entity type","pos":[11088,11099]},{"content":"Dependency","pos":[11102,11112]},{"content":"Comments","pos":[11115,11123]},{"content":"17","pos":[11354,11356]},{"content":"Fund types","pos":[11375,11385]},{"content":"General ledger","pos":[11389,11403]},{"content":"Setup","pos":[11406,11411]},{"content":"None","pos":[11420,11424]},{"content":"Categorization of funds.","pos":[11433,11457]},{"content":"Categorization is typically completed by function.","pos":[11458,11508]},{"content":"18","pos":[11513,11515]},{"content":"Fund","pos":[11534,11538]},{"content":"General ledger","pos":[11548,11562]},{"content":"Setup","pos":[11565,11570]},{"content":"Fund types","pos":[11579,11589]},{"content":"Suggested sequence","pos":[11674,11692]},{"content":"Package","pos":[11695,11702]},{"content":"19","pos":[13128,13130]},{"content":"03.1.001 GL – Chart of accounts – Shared.","pos":[13149,13190]},{"content":"Note: Activate financial dimensions, and then import the Financial dimension sets data entity again.","pos":[13191,13291]},{"content":"To activate financial dimensions, click General ledger &gt; Chart of accounts &gt; Dimensions &gt; Financial dimensions, and select Close on pop up.","pos":[13292,13431],"source":" To activate financial dimensions, click General ledger > Chart of accounts > Dimensions > Financial dimensions, and select Close on pop up."},{"content":"On the Action Pane, click Activate, and then, on the Activate financial dimensions page, click Activate.","pos":[13432,13536]},{"content":"The posting type must be added to the Sales tax payable and Use tax payable main accounts.","pos":[13537,13627]},{"content":"Click General ledger &gt; Chart of accounts &gt; Accounts &gt; Main accounts, and open account 24800.","pos":[13628,13720],"source":" Click General ledger > Chart of accounts > Accounts > Main accounts, and open account 24800."},{"content":"On the Posting validation FastTab, in the Posting type field, select Sales tax.","pos":[13721,13800]},{"content":"Repeat for this procedure for main account 24801.","pos":[13801,13850]},{"content":"20","pos":[13855,13857]},{"content":"03.1.002 GL – Account structures – Shared.","pos":[13876,13918]},{"content":"There is a known issue on export in PSUS for the Advanced rule structure allowed values and Account structure allowed values data entities.","pos":[13919,14058]},{"content":"No values are exported for these two data entities.","pos":[14059,14110]},{"content":"The package on Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS) has been modified.","pos":[14111,14188]},{"content":"21","pos":[14582,14584]},{"content":"03.1.003 GL – Fiscal calendar – Shared","pos":[14603,14641]},{"content":"22","pos":[15309,15311]},{"content":"03.1.004 GL – Ledger setup.","pos":[15330,15357]},{"content":"If you’re using demo data, records will fail in the Ledger fiscal calendar period data entity because of closed periods that can’t be reopened.","pos":[15358,15501]},{"content":"23","pos":[16036,16038]},{"content":"03.1.005 GL – Ledger journals.","pos":[16057,16087]},{"content":"Records will fail in the Journal names data entity until the Bank accounts data entity is imported.","pos":[16088,16187]},{"content":"After the bank accounts are imported, import the Journal names data entity again.","pos":[16188,16269]},{"pos":[16762,16925],"content":"06.1.002 PubSect – Posting definition setup If you’re using demo data, some records will fail in the Posting definition entry data entity because of a known issue.","source":"06.1.002 PubSect – Posting definition setup\nIf you’re using demo data, some records will fail in the Posting definition entry data entity because of a known issue."},{"content":"Suggested sequence","pos":[16929,16947]},{"content":"Entity name","pos":[16950,16961]},{"content":"Area","pos":[16998,17002]},{"content":"Entity type","pos":[17015,17026]},{"content":"Dependency","pos":[17029,17039]},{"content":"Comments","pos":[17064,17072]},{"content":"24","pos":[17649,17651]},{"content":"Posting definition","pos":[17670,17688]},{"content":"General ledger","pos":[17718,17732]},{"content":"Setup","pos":[17735,17740]},{"content":"None","pos":[17749,17753]},{"content":"25","pos":[18009,18011]},{"content":"Posting definition entry","pos":[18030,18054]},{"content":"General ledger","pos":[18078,18092]},{"content":"Setup","pos":[18095,18100]},{"content":"Posting definition","pos":[18109,18127]},{"content":"The lines that are associated with each posting definition","pos":[18144,18202]},{"content":"26","pos":[18369,18371]},{"content":"Transaction posting definition Bank","pos":[18390,18425]},{"content":"General ledger","pos":[18438,18452]},{"content":"Setup","pos":[18455,18460]},{"content":"Posting definition","pos":[18469,18487]},{"content":"The association of the posting definition with the Bank module","pos":[18504,18566]},{"content":"27","pos":[18729,18731]},{"content":"Transaction posting definition General ledger","pos":[18750,18795]},{"content":"General ledger","pos":[18798,18812]},{"content":"Setup","pos":[18815,18820]},{"content":"Posting definition","pos":[18829,18847]},{"content":"The association of the posting definition with the General ledger module","pos":[18864,18936]},{"content":"28","pos":[19089,19091]},{"content":"Transaction posting definition Payable","pos":[19110,19148]},{"content":"General ledger","pos":[19158,19172]},{"content":"Setup","pos":[19175,19180]},{"content":"Posting definition","pos":[19189,19207]},{"content":"The association of the posting definition with the Payable module","pos":[19224,19289]},{"content":"29","pos":[19449,19451]},{"content":"Transaction posting definition Purchasing","pos":[19470,19511]},{"content":"General ledger","pos":[19518,19532]},{"content":"Setup","pos":[19535,19540]},{"content":"Posting definition","pos":[19549,19567]},{"content":"The association of the posting definition with the Purchasing module","pos":[19584,19652]},{"content":"30","pos":[19809,19811]},{"content":"Transaction posting definition Receivable","pos":[19830,19871]},{"content":"General ledger","pos":[19878,19892]},{"content":"Setup","pos":[19895,19900]},{"content":"Posting definition","pos":[19909,19927]},{"content":"The association of the posting definition with the Receivable module","pos":[19944,20012]},{"content":"31","pos":[20169,20171]},{"content":"Transaction posting definition Budget","pos":[20190,20227]},{"content":"General ledger","pos":[20238,20252]},{"content":"Setup","pos":[20255,20260]},{"content":"Posting definition, Budget Setup","pos":[20269,20301]},{"content":"The association of the posting definition with the Budget module.","pos":[20304,20369]},{"content":"Note: Budget setup is a dependency for the Transactional posting definition budget.","pos":[20370,20453]},{"content":"Therefore, this data entity is included with the Budget setup package.","pos":[20454,20524]},{"content":"Suggested sequence","pos":[20531,20549]},{"content":"Package","pos":[20552,20559]},{"content":"32","pos":[21349,21351]},{"content":"03.1.006 GL – Allocations","pos":[21370,21395]},{"content":"33","pos":[21758,21760]},{"content":"03.1.007 BANK – Bank setup","pos":[21779,21805]},{"content":"34","pos":[22167,22169]},{"content":"03.1.008 BANK – Bank accounts.","pos":[22188,22218]},{"content":"Note: If you’re using demo data, remove NSFJournalName from the Bank accounts data entity import file, and re-import Journal names.","pos":[22219,22350]},{"content":"Then, on the Payment management tab, in the NSF payment journal field for bank accounts PSUS Oper and PSUS Payrol, select CustPay.","pos":[22351,22481]},{"content":"NSFJournalName has been removed from the Bank accounts data entity in the package on LCS.","pos":[22482,22571]},{"content":"35","pos":[22576,22578]},{"content":"Re-import 03.1.005 – Ledger journals","pos":[22597,22633]},{"content":"06.8.001 PubSect – Advanced ledger entry lines If you’re using demo data, many records will fail because of dependencies on Project.","pos":[22984,23116],"source":"06.8.001 PubSect – Advanced ledger entry lines\nIf you’re using demo data, many records will fail because of dependencies on Project."},{"content":"After the Project master data entity is imported, import the Advanced ledger entry lines data entity again.","pos":[23117,23224]},{"content":"Because of a known issue with demo data, the posting definition isn’t attached to many lines.","pos":[23226,23319]},{"content":"The package on LCS has been modified.","pos":[23320,23357]},{"content":"Suggested sequence","pos":[23361,23379]},{"content":"Entity name","pos":[23382,23393]},{"content":"Area","pos":[23412,23416]},{"content":"Entity type","pos":[23429,23440]},{"content":"Dependency","pos":[23443,23453]},{"content":"Comments","pos":[23487,23495]},{"content":"36","pos":[23793,23795]},{"content":"Advanced ledger entry lines","pos":[23814,23841]},{"content":"General ledger","pos":[23844,23858]},{"content":"Transaction","pos":[23861,23872]},{"content":"General ledger setup, Posting definitions","pos":[23875,23916]},{"content":"The general ledger entry that is source document–enabled and uses posting definitions","pos":[23919,24004]},{"pos":[24008,24063],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Human resources<ept id=\"p2\">](data-entities-human-resources.md)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**[Human resources](data-entities-human-resources.md)**"},{"content":"Suggested sequence","pos":[24067,24085]},{"content":"Package","pos":[24088,24095]},{"content":"37","pos":[25255,25257]},{"content":"05.1.001 HR – Foundation setup","pos":[25276,25306]},{"content":"38","pos":[25849,25851]},{"content":"05.1.002 HR – Competencies","pos":[25870,25896]},{"content":"39","pos":[26443,26445]},{"content":"05.1.003 HR – Jobs","pos":[26464,26482]},{"content":"40","pos":[27037,27039]},{"content":"05.1.004 – Pay","pos":[27058,27072]},{"content":"41","pos":[27631,27633]},{"content":"05.1.005 HR – Employees","pos":[27652,27675]},{"content":"42","pos":[28225,28227]},{"content":"05.1.006 HR – Contractor","pos":[28246,28270]},{"content":"43","pos":[28819,28821]},{"content":"05.1.011 HR – Benefits.","pos":[28840,28863]},{"content":"Pay cycle and Pay period are dependencies for this entity, but payroll DEs aren’t available.","pos":[28864,28956]},{"content":"Manually generate the pay periods for the pay cycle, and then re-import Calculation frequency pay period.","pos":[28957,29062]},{"content":"44","pos":[29413,29415]},{"content":"05.1.007 HR – Positions","pos":[29434,29457]},{"content":"45","pos":[30007,30009]},{"content":"05.1.008 HR – Worker details","pos":[30028,30056]},{"content":"46","pos":[30601,30603]},{"content":"05.1.009 HR – Compensation","pos":[30622,30648]},{"content":"47","pos":[31195,31197]},{"content":"05.1.010 HR – Absence","pos":[31216,31237]},{"content":"48","pos":[31789,31791]},{"content":"05.1.012 HR – Performance","pos":[31810,31835]},{"content":"49","pos":[32383,32385]},{"content":"05.1.013 HR – Courses.","pos":[32404,32426]},{"content":"If you receive a record that has Fail in the Courses data entity, import this data entity after you import vendors.","pos":[32427,32542]},{"content":"Note: There is a known demo data issue with the Course types data entity.","pos":[32543,32616]},{"content":"The package on LCS has been modified.","pos":[32617,32654]},{"content":"50","pos":[32977,32979]},{"content":"05.1.014 HR – Recruitment.","pos":[32998,33024]},{"content":"You must manually start the recruitment projects.","pos":[33025,33074]},{"content":"Click Human resources &gt; Recruitment &gt; Recruitment projects &gt; Recruitment projects, and select the Bookkeeper project.","pos":[33075,33192],"source":" Click Human resources > Recruitment > Recruitment projects > Recruitment projects, and select the Bookkeeper project."},{"content":"Then, on the Action Pane, click Recruitment project status.","pos":[33193,33252]},{"content":"Repeat this procedure for each project, and then import Applications again.","pos":[33253,33328]},{"content":"Note: Records will fail in the Applicants data entity because of a known issue that is related to effective and expiration dates.","pos":[33329,33458]},{"content":"Records will also fail in the Applications data entity because of dependency on the Applicants data entity.","pos":[33459,33566]},{"content":"51","pos":[33571,33573]},{"content":"05.1.015 HR – Employee related associations.","pos":[33592,33636]},{"content":"Note: See the comment for the Employee fixed compensation data entity in the Data entities: Human resources article.","pos":[33637,33753]},{"content":"If you’re using demo data, the Injury and illness incidents data entity will fail.","pos":[33754,33836]},{"content":"The package on LCS has been modified.","pos":[33837,33874]},{"content":"52","pos":[34165,34167]},{"content":"05.1.016 HR – Human resources parameters.","pos":[34186,34227]},{"content":"Note: If you’re using demo data, the Human resources parameters data entity will fail.","pos":[34228,34314]},{"content":"The package on LCS has been modified.","pos":[34315,34352]},{"content":"53","pos":[34759,34761]},{"content":"05.1.017 HR – Shared human resources parameters.","pos":[34780,34828]},{"content":"Note: If you’re using demo data, the Shared human resources parameters data entity will fail.","pos":[34829,34922]},{"content":"The package on LCS has been modified.","pos":[34923,34960]},{"pos":[35352,35425],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Accounts payable and taxes<ept id=\"p2\">](data-entities-accounts-payable-taxes.md)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**[Accounts payable and taxes](data-entities-accounts-payable-taxes.md)**"},{"content":"Suggested sequence","pos":[35429,35447]},{"content":"Package","pos":[35450,35457]},{"content":"54","pos":[35935,35937]},{"content":"10.1.001 AP – AP and AR shared setup","pos":[35956,35992]},{"content":"55","pos":[36188,36190]},{"content":"10.1.002 AP – Vendor payment setup","pos":[36209,36243]},{"content":"56","pos":[36441,36443]},{"content":"10.1.003 AP – Vendor attributes","pos":[36462,36493]},{"content":"57","pos":[36694,36696]},{"content":"10.1.006 Tax – Sales tax setup.","pos":[36715,36746]},{"content":"Note: Some records in Sales tax authorities and Sales tax period setup will fail because of dependencies on Vendors.","pos":[36747,36863]},{"content":"You should re-import this package after the Vendors package has been imported.","pos":[36864,36942]},{"content":"58","pos":[36947,36949]},{"content":"10.1.007 Tax – Sales tax code groups.","pos":[36968,37005]},{"content":"Note: Some records in this package will fail because of dependencies on Vendors.","pos":[37006,37086]},{"content":"You should re-import this package after the Vendors package has been imported.","pos":[37087,37165]},{"content":"59","pos":[37200,37202]},{"content":"10.1.004 AP – Vendors","pos":[37221,37242]},{"content":"60","pos":[37453,37455]},{"content":"06.1.003 PubSect – Vendor certification types","pos":[37474,37519]},{"content":"Suggested sequence","pos":[37601,37619]},{"content":"Entity name","pos":[37622,37633]},{"content":"Area","pos":[37651,37655]},{"content":"Entity type","pos":[37670,37681]},{"content":"Dependency","pos":[37684,37694]},{"content":"Comments","pos":[37697,37705]},{"content":"61","pos":[38015,38017]},{"content":"Vendor certification types","pos":[38036,38062]},{"content":"Accounts payable","pos":[38065,38081]},{"content":"Setup","pos":[38084,38089]},{"content":"None","pos":[38098,38102]},{"content":"Vendor attribute that are related to specific functions that are performed or certifications that are held","pos":[38111,38217]},{"content":"Suggested sequence","pos":[38224,38242]},{"content":"Package","pos":[38245,38252]},{"content":"62","pos":[38368,38370]},{"content":"Re-import 10.1.006 Tax – Sales tax setup","pos":[38389,38429]},{"content":"63","pos":[38440,38442]},{"content":"Re-import 10.1.007 Tax – Sales tax code groups","pos":[38461,38507]},{"content":"64","pos":[38512,38514]},{"content":"Re-import 05.1.013 HR – Courses","pos":[38533,38564]},{"content":"65","pos":[38584,38586]},{"content":"10.1.005 AP – AP Parameters","pos":[38605,38632]},{"content":"66","pos":[38656,38658]},{"content":"10.1.008 Tax – Sales tax parameters","pos":[38677,38712]},{"pos":[38727,38790],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Accounts receivable<ept id=\"p2\">](data-entities-accounts-receivable.md)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**[Accounts receivable](data-entities-accounts-receivable.md)**"},{"content":"If you’re implementing Accounts receivable but aren't using Accounts payable, you should use the 10.1.001 AP and AR shared setup package.","pos":[38792,38929]},{"content":"For details about that package, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Data entities: Accounts payable and taxes<ept id=\"p1\">](data-entities-accounts-payable-taxes.md)</ept>.","pos":[38930,39051],"source":" For details about that package, see [Data entities: Accounts payable and taxes](data-entities-accounts-payable-taxes.md)."},{"content":"Suggested sequence","pos":[39055,39073]},{"content":"Package","pos":[39076,39083]},{"content":"67","pos":[39459,39461]},{"content":"11.1.001 AR – Customer payment setup","pos":[39480,39516]},{"content":"68","pos":[39661,39663]},{"content":"11.1.002 AR – Customer attributes","pos":[39682,39715]},{"content":"69","pos":[39863,39865]},{"content":"11.1.003 AR – Customers","pos":[39884,39907]},{"content":"70","pos":[40065,40067]},{"content":"11.1.004 AR – Accounts receivable parameters","pos":[40086,40130]},{"content":"71","pos":[40267,40269]},{"content":"06.1.004 PubSect – Billing classification and codes.","pos":[40288,40340]},{"content":"Note: Records will fail because of dependencies on Interest codes and Collection.","pos":[40341,40422]},{"content":"The package on LCS has not been modified.","pos":[40423,40464]},{"content":"Suggested sequence","pos":[40470,40488]},{"content":"Entity name","pos":[40491,40502]},{"content":"Area","pos":[40540,40544]},{"content":"Entity type","pos":[40562,40573]},{"content":"Dependency","pos":[40576,40586]},{"content":"Comments","pos":[40643,40651]},{"content":"72","pos":[41078,41080]},{"content":"Billing classification","pos":[41099,41121]},{"content":"Accounts Receivable","pos":[41148,41167]},{"content":"Setup","pos":[41170,41175]},{"content":"Interest codes US and Collection letters","pos":[41184,41224]},{"content":"Setup data for classifying details such as the main account, to make it easier to create a group and, in turn, vendor invoices","pos":[41251,41377]},{"content":"73","pos":[41382,41384]},{"content":"Billing code with billing code version","pos":[41403,41441]},{"content":"Accounts Receivable","pos":[41452,41471]},{"content":"Setup","pos":[41474,41479]},{"content":"Billing classification, Interest codes US and Collection letters","pos":[41488,41552]},{"content":"The component details that make up the billing classification","pos":[41555,41616]},{"content":"74","pos":[41686,41688]},{"content":"Billing classification with billing code","pos":[41707,41747]},{"content":"Accounts Receivable","pos":[41756,41775]},{"content":"Setup","pos":[41778,41783]},{"content":"Billing classification, Billing code","pos":[41792,41828]},{"content":"75","pos":[41990,41992]},{"content":"Billing code custom field","pos":[42011,42036]},{"content":"Accounts Receivable","pos":[42060,42079]},{"content":"Setup","pos":[42082,42087]},{"content":"Billing code","pos":[42096,42108]},{"content":"76","pos":[42294,42296]},{"content":"Billing code with accounting distribution","pos":[42315,42356]},{"content":"Accounts Receivable","pos":[42364,42383]},{"content":"Setup","pos":[42386,42391]},{"content":"Billing code","pos":[42400,42412]},{"content":"77","pos":[42598,42600]},{"content":"Billing codes with billing code customer field","pos":[42619,42665]},{"content":"Accounts Receivable","pos":[42668,42687]},{"content":"Setup","pos":[42690,42695]},{"content":"Billing code","pos":[42704,42716]},{"content":"78","pos":[42902,42904]},{"content":"Billing code with billing code rate","pos":[42923,42958]},{"content":"Accounts Receivable","pos":[42972,42991]},{"content":"Setup","pos":[42994,42999]},{"content":"Billing code","pos":[43008,43020]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Budgeting<ept id=\"p2\">](data-entities-budgeting.md)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> All General ledger data entities and the setup are a prerequisite for importing Budgeting data entities.","pos":[43206,43354],"source":"**[Budgeting](data-entities-budgeting.md)**\nAll General ledger data entities and the setup are a prerequisite for importing Budgeting data entities."},{"content":"For more information about General ledger data entities, and to confirm that the setup is completed, see Data entities: General ledger.","pos":[43355,43490]},{"content":"Suggested sequence","pos":[43494,43512]},{"content":"Package","pos":[43515,43522]},{"content":"79","pos":[43620,43622]},{"content":"12.1.001 BUD – Ledger budget setup","pos":[43641,43675]},{"content":"80","pos":[43683,43685]},{"content":"12.1.002 BUD – Budget control setup","pos":[43704,43739]},{"content":"81","pos":[43746,43748]},{"content":"12.8.001 BUD – Budget account entries","pos":[43767,43804]},{"pos":[43809,43860],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Budget planning<ept id=\"p2\">](data-entities-budget-plan.md)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**[Budget planning](data-entities-budget-plan.md)**"},{"content":"Suggested sequence","pos":[43864,43882]},{"content":"Package","pos":[43885,43892]},{"content":"82","pos":[44242,44244]},{"content":"12.1.003 BUD – Budget planning setup.","pos":[44263,44300]},{"content":"A demo data issue will cause records to fail in the Budget plan stage rule data entity.","pos":[44301,44388]},{"content":"The package on LCS has been modified.","pos":[44389,44426]},{"content":"83","pos":[44431,44433]},{"content":"12.01.004 BUD – Forecast position","pos":[44452,44485]},{"pos":[44620,44659],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Costing<ept id=\"p2\">](data-entities-costing.md)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**[Costing](data-entities-costing.md)**"},{"content":"Suggested sequence","pos":[44663,44681]},{"content":"Package","pos":[44684,44691]},{"content":"84","pos":[44771,44773]},{"content":"15.1.001 COS – Costing setup","pos":[44792,44820]},{"pos":[44824,44889],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Inventory management<ept id=\"p2\">](data-entities-inventory-management.md)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**[Inventory management](data-entities-inventory-management.md)**"},{"content":"Suggested sequence","pos":[44893,44911]},{"content":"Package","pos":[44914,44921]},{"content":"85","pos":[45015,45017]},{"content":"19.1.001 INV – Site setup","pos":[45036,45061]},{"content":"86","pos":[45076,45078]},{"content":"19.1.002 INV – Warehouse setup","pos":[45097,45127]},{"content":"87","pos":[45137,45139]},{"content":"19.1.003 INV – Group setup","pos":[45158,45184]},{"content":"88","pos":[45198,45200]},{"content":"19.1.004 INV – Journal setup","pos":[45219,45247]},{"content":"89","pos":[45259,45261]},{"content":"19.1.005 INV – Packing setup","pos":[45280,45308]},{"content":"90","pos":[45320,45322]},{"content":"19.1.006 INV – Posting definitions","pos":[45341,45375]},{"content":"91","pos":[45381,45383]},{"content":"19.1.008 INV – Inventory parameters","pos":[45402,45437]},{"content":"92","pos":[45442,45444]},{"content":"19.1.007 INV – Price discount setup","pos":[45463,45498]},{"content":"93","pos":[45503,45505]},{"content":"19.4.001 INV – Charge groups","pos":[45524,45552]},{"pos":[45563,45612],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Fixed assets<ept id=\"p2\">](data-entities-fixed-assets.md)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**[Fixed assets](data-entities-fixed-assets.md)**"},{"content":"Suggested sequence","pos":[45616,45634]},{"content":"Package","pos":[45637,45644]},{"content":"94","pos":[46246,46248]},{"content":"16.01.001 FA – Fixed assets attributes","pos":[46267,46305]},{"content":"95","pos":[46561,46563]},{"content":"16.01.002 FA – Fixed assets setup.","pos":[46582,46616]},{"content":"Note: On the Fixed asset parameters data entity, unmap DefaultValueModelID.","pos":[46617,46692]},{"content":"If you’re using demo data, records in the Fixed asset value model data entity will fail because of missing depreciation profiles.","pos":[46693,46822]},{"content":"The package on LCS has been modified for import.","pos":[46823,46871]},{"content":"96","pos":[46876,46878]},{"content":"16.01.003 FA – Fixed assets.","pos":[46897,46925]},{"content":"Note: If you’re using demo data, records in the Fixed asset value model data entity will fail because of missing depreciation profiles.","pos":[46926,47061]},{"content":"The package on LCS has been modified for import.","pos":[47062,47110]},{"pos":[47190,47275],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Product information management<ept id=\"p2\">](data-entities-product-information-management.md)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**[Product information management](data-entities-product-information-management.md)**"},{"content":"Suggested sequence","pos":[47279,47297]},{"content":"Package","pos":[47300,47307]},{"content":"97","pos":[47759,47761]},{"content":"24.1.001 PIM – Dimension groups","pos":[47780,47811]},{"content":"98","pos":[47999,48001]},{"content":"24.1.002 PIM – Product variant groups","pos":[48020,48057]},{"content":"99","pos":[48239,48241]},{"content":"24.1.003 PIM – Size assignments","pos":[48260,48291]},{"content":"100","pos":[48479,48482]},{"content":"24.1.004 PIM – Color assignments","pos":[48500,48532]},{"content":"101","pos":[48719,48722]},{"content":"24.1.005 PIM – Style assignments","pos":[48740,48772]},{"content":"102","pos":[48959,48962]},{"content":"24.1.006 PIM – Category setup.","pos":[48980,49010]},{"content":"Note: Before you proceed, confirm that product categories are accurately set up.","pos":[49011,49091]},{"content":"103","pos":[49199,49202]},{"content":"24.1.007 PIM – Attribute types","pos":[49220,49250]},{"content":"104","pos":[49439,49442]},{"content":"24.1.008 PIM – Product attributes.","pos":[49460,49494]},{"content":"Note: If you’re using demo data, records in the Product attributes data entity will fail because of missing depreciation profiles.","pos":[49495,49625]},{"content":"The package on LCS has been modified for import.","pos":[49626,49674]},{"content":"105","pos":[49679,49682]},{"content":"24.4.001 PIM – Attribute groups","pos":[49700,49731]},{"content":"106","pos":[49919,49922]},{"content":"24.4.002 PIM – Products – Shared","pos":[49940,49972]},{"content":"107","pos":[50159,50162]},{"content":"24.4.003 PIM – Product UOM conversion","pos":[50180,50217]},{"content":"108","pos":[50399,50402]},{"content":"24.4.004 PIM – Product variants","pos":[50420,50451]},{"content":"109","pos":[50639,50642]},{"content":"24.4.005 PIM – Released product creation.","pos":[50660,50701]},{"content":"Note: This is used if Products fails.","pos":[50702,50739]},{"content":"110","pos":[50879,50882]},{"content":"24.4.006 PIM – Released products","pos":[50900,50932]},{"content":"111","pos":[51119,51122]},{"content":"24.4.007 PIM – Released product variants","pos":[51140,51180]},{"content":"112","pos":[51359,51362]},{"content":"24.4.008 PIM – Category attributes","pos":[51380,51414]},{"content":"113","pos":[51599,51602]},{"content":"24.4.009 PIM – Attribute values","pos":[51620,51651]},{"pos":[51838,51907],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Procurement and sourcing<ept id=\"p2\">](data-entities-procurement-sourcing.md)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**[Procurement and sourcing](data-entities-procurement-sourcing.md)**"},{"content":"Suggested sequence","pos":[51911,51929]},{"content":"Package","pos":[51932,51939]},{"content":"114","pos":[52411,52414]},{"content":"23.1.001 PRO – Summary parameters","pos":[52432,52465]},{"content":"115","pos":[52661,52664]},{"content":"23.1.002 PRO – Purchase order setup","pos":[52682,52717]},{"content":"116","pos":[52911,52914]},{"content":"23.1.003 PRO – Distribution setup","pos":[52932,52965]},{"content":"117","pos":[53161,53164]},{"content":"23.1.004 PRO – Form setup","pos":[53182,53207]},{"content":"118","pos":[53411,53414]},{"content":"23.1.005 PRO – Prices discounts setup","pos":[53432,53469]},{"content":"119","pos":[53661,53664]},{"content":"23.1.006 PRO – External item setup","pos":[53682,53716]},{"content":"120","pos":[53911,53914]},{"content":"23.1.007 PRO – Vendor setup","pos":[53932,53959]},{"content":"121","pos":[54161,54164]},{"content":"23.1.008 PRO – Supp item setup","pos":[54182,54212]},{"content":"122","pos":[54411,54414]},{"content":"23.1.009 PRO – Rebate setup","pos":[54432,54459]},{"content":"123","pos":[54661,54664]},{"content":"23.1.010 PRO – Price tol setup","pos":[54682,54712]},{"content":"124","pos":[54911,54914]},{"content":"23.1.011 PRO – Discount groups setup","pos":[54932,54968]},{"content":"125","pos":[55161,55164]},{"content":"23.1.012 PRO – Policies setup.","pos":[55182,55212]},{"content":"Note: The Procurement type document default values data entity will fail because a dependent data entity, Return actions, is missing.","pos":[55213,55346]},{"content":"The package on LCS has been modified to make import easier.","pos":[55347,55406]},{"content":"126","pos":[55411,55414]},{"content":"23.1.013 PRO – Purchase agreement classification","pos":[55432,55480]},{"content":"06.1.005 PubSect – PO commitment","pos":[55660,55692]},{"content":"Suggested sequence","pos":[55696,55714]},{"content":"Entity name","pos":[55717,55728]},{"content":"Area","pos":[55736,55740]},{"content":"Entity type","pos":[55750,55761]},{"content":"Dependency","pos":[55764,55774]},{"content":"Comments","pos":[55777,55785]},{"content":"127","pos":[55956,55959]},{"content":"Confirming PO","pos":[55977,55990]},{"content":"Procurement","pos":[55996,56007]},{"content":"Setup","pos":[56010,56015]},{"content":"None","pos":[56024,56028]},{"content":"Description of the types of PO confirmations","pos":[56037,56081]},{"content":"128","pos":[56086,56089]},{"content":"Commitment lines","pos":[56107,56123]},{"content":"Procurement","pos":[56126,56137]},{"content":"Setup","pos":[56140,56145]},{"content":"None","pos":[56154,56158]},{"content":"Suggested sequence","pos":[56218,56236]},{"content":"Package","pos":[56239,56246]},{"content":"129","pos":[56844,56847]},{"content":"23.4.001 PRO – Charges setup","pos":[56865,56893]},{"content":"130","pos":[57157,57160]},{"content":"23.4.002 PRO – Purchase agreements.","pos":[57178,57213]},{"content":"Note: Before you import the package, reset the number sequence for Purchase agreement ID to 1, and then unmap PurchaseAgreementID.","pos":[57214,57344]},{"content":"131","pos":[57470,57473]},{"content":"23.4.003 PRO – Purchase agreement lines","pos":[57491,57530]},{"content":"132","pos":[57783,57786]},{"content":"23.8.001 PRO – Purchase orders.","pos":[57804,57835]},{"content":"Note: Before you import the package, reset the number sequence for the Purchase order ID to 1, and unmap ReasonCode.","pos":[57836,57952]},{"content":"Some records will fail because of a Project dependency.","pos":[57953,58008]},{"content":"Re-import this package after you import the Project master data entity dependency.","pos":[58009,58091]},{"content":"133","pos":[58096,58099]},{"content":"23.8.002 PRO – Purchase order lines.","pos":[58117,58153]},{"content":"Note: If you’re using demo data, records will fail due to Project and Fixed assets dependencies.","pos":[58154,58250]},{"content":"Re-import this package after you import Project master and all Fixed asset packages.","pos":[58251,58335]},{"pos":[58408,58469],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Project accounting<ept id=\"p2\">](data-entities-project-accounting.md)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**[Project accounting](data-entities-project-accounting.md)**"},{"content":"Suggested sequence","pos":[58473,58491]},{"content":"Package","pos":[58494,58501]},{"content":"134","pos":[59213,59216]},{"content":"26.1.001 PA – Projects setup","pos":[59234,59262]},{"content":"135","pos":[59583,59586]},{"content":"26.1.002 PA – Journals setup","pos":[59604,59632]},{"content":"136","pos":[59953,59956]},{"content":"26.1.003 PA – Estimates setup","pos":[59974,60003]},{"content":"137","pos":[60323,60326]},{"content":"26.1.004 PA – Forms setup","pos":[60344,60369]},{"content":"138","pos":[60693,60696]},{"content":"26.1.005 PA – Resourcing setup.","pos":[60714,60745]},{"content":"Note: Review the warnings in the “Resourcing setup” section in the Data entities: Project accounting article.","pos":[60746,60855]},{"content":"139","pos":[61063,61066]},{"content":"26.1.006 PA – Project periods","pos":[61084,61113]},{"content":"140","pos":[61433,61436]},{"content":"26.1.007 PA – Categories, posting, and line property.","pos":[61454,61507]},{"content":"Note: If you’re using demo data, records will fail in the Line property setup because of a dependency on Projects.","pos":[61508,61622]},{"content":"Re-import this package after you’ve imported the Project master data entity.","pos":[61623,61699]},{"content":"141","pos":[61803,61806]},{"content":"26.1.008 PA – Forecasts setup","pos":[61824,61853]},{"content":"142","pos":[62173,62176]},{"content":"26.1.009 PA – Retention setup","pos":[62194,62223]},{"content":"Important: Before you proceed with additional data import, you must manually set up Project management and accounting parameters, because that information is required in order to complete the remaining steps.","pos":[62564,62772]},{"content":"143","pos":[62814,62817]},{"content":"26.1.010 PA – Grants setup","pos":[62835,62861]},{"content":"144","pos":[63184,63187]},{"content":"26.1.011 PA – Project contracts.","pos":[63205,63237]},{"content":"Note: Records will fail in Project funding source data entity because of a dependency on Grants.","pos":[63238,63334]},{"content":"You must manually set up Grants from demo data by using the components that were imported in 26.1.010 PA – Grants setup.","pos":[63335,63455]},{"content":"Records will fail in Project funding rule because of a dependency on Project funding sources.","pos":[63456,63549]},{"content":"145","pos":[63554,63557]},{"content":"26.1.012 PA – Inventory project consumption setup","pos":[63575,63624]},{"content":"146","pos":[63924,63927]},{"content":"26.1.013 PA – Projects master.","pos":[63945,63975]},{"content":"Review the warnings in the section for the Project master data entity in the Data entities: Project accounting article.","pos":[63976,64095]},{"content":"147","pos":[64294,64297]},{"content":"Re-import 26.1.007 PA – Categories, posting, and line property","pos":[64315,64377]},{"content":"148","pos":[64664,64667]},{"content":"26.1.014 PA – Validation setup.","pos":[64685,64716]},{"content":"Review the warnings in the section for the Validation setup data entity in the Data entities: Project accounting article.","pos":[64717,64838]},{"content":"149","pos":[65034,65037]},{"content":"26.1.015 PA – Pricing setup","pos":[65055,65082]},{"content":"150","pos":[65404,65407]},{"content":"26.1.016 PA – Indirect costs setup","pos":[65425,65459]},{"content":"151","pos":[65774,65777]},{"content":"26.8.001 – Project beginning balance.","pos":[65795,65832]},{"content":"Review the warnings in the section for the Project beginning balance data entity in the Data entities: Project accounting article.","pos":[65833,65963]},{"content":"152","pos":[66144,66147]},{"content":"26.8.002 – Project hour and fee journal transactions.","pos":[66165,66218]},{"content":"Review the warnings in the section for the Project hour and fee journal transactions data entity in the Data entities: Project accounting article.","pos":[66219,66365]},{"content":"153","pos":[66514,66517]},{"content":"Re-import 06.8.001 PubSect – Advanced ledger entry lines","pos":[66535,66591]},{"content":"154","pos":[66884,66887]},{"content":"Re-import 23.8.001 PRO – Purchase orders","pos":[66905,66945]},{"content":"155","pos":[67254,67257]},{"content":"Re-import 23.8.002 PRO – Purchase order lines","pos":[67275,67320]},{"pos":[67623,67631],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[67642,67712],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Data entities and packages framework<ept id=\"p1\">](data-entities-data-packages.md)</ept>","source":"[Data entities and packages framework](data-entities-data-packages.md)"},{"pos":[67714,67747],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Data entities<ept id=\"p1\">](data-entities.md)</ept>","source":"[Data entities](data-entities.md)"}]}