{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,69],"content":"Advanced bank reconciliation overview","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Advanced bank reconciliation overview","pos":[0,37]}]},{"pos":[83,304],"content":"Advanced bank reconciliation allows you to import electronic bank statements and automatically reconcile with bank transactions in Microsoft Dynamics AX.  This article will explain the set up processes for reconciliation.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Advanced bank reconciliation allows you to import electronic bank statements and automatically reconcile with bank transactions in Microsoft Dynamics AX.  This article will explain the set up processes for reconciliation.","pos":[0,221],"nodes":[{"content":"Advanced bank reconciliation allows you to import electronic bank statements and automatically reconcile with bank transactions in Microsoft Dynamics AX.","pos":[0,153]},{"content":"This article will explain the set up processes for reconciliation.","pos":[155,221]}]}]},{"pos":[813,850],"content":"Advanced bank reconciliation overview","linkify":"Advanced bank reconciliation overview","nodes":[{"content":"Advanced bank reconciliation overview","pos":[0,37]}]},{"content":"Advanced bank reconciliation allows you to import electronic bank statements and automatically reconcile with bank transactions in Microsoft Dynamics AX.","pos":[852,1005]},{"content":"This article will explain the set up processes for reconciliation.","pos":[1007,1073]},{"content":"There are a number of pieces that must be set up before using the advanced bank reconciliation functionality.","pos":[1077,1186]},{"content":"For more information about setting up bank statement import, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Set up the bank statement import process<ept id=\"p1\">](set-up-advanced-bank-reconciliation-import-process.md)</ept>.","pos":[1187,1350],"source":" For more information about setting up bank statement import, see [Set up the bank statement import process](set-up-advanced-bank-reconciliation-import-process.md)."},{"content":"Requirements for set up of the reconciliation process are detailed below.","pos":[1352,1425]},{"pos":[1430,1447],"content":"Transaction codes","linkify":"Transaction codes","nodes":[{"content":"Transaction codes","pos":[0,17]}]},{"content":"Transaction codes can be used as part of the bank reconciliation matching rules.","pos":[1448,1528]},{"content":"Transaction codes will help to match only the same types of transactions between Dynamics AX and your bank statement.","pos":[1530,1647]},{"content":"In order to do this type of matching, you must first define transaction types used for bank transactions from Dynamics AX, then map those types to statement transaction codes used by your bank.","pos":[1649,1842]},{"content":"Transaction types for Dynamics AX bank transactions are defined on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Bank transaction type<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[1844,1946],"source":"  Transaction types for Dynamics AX bank transactions are defined on the **Bank transaction type** page."},{"content":"This is also where you define the main account to be used for postings associated with that transaction type.","pos":[1948,2057]},{"content":"Once your Dynamics AX bank transaction codes are defined, you then map those to the transaction codes used in your electronic bank statements.","pos":[2058,2200]},{"content":"This mapping process is done using the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Transaction code mapping<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[2202,2275],"source":"  This mapping process is done using the **Transaction code mapping** page."},{"content":"Transaction code mapping is completed separately for each bank account.","pos":[2277,2348]},{"pos":[2353,2390],"content":"Matching rules and matching rule sets","linkify":"Matching rules and matching rule sets","nodes":[{"content":"Matching rules and matching rule sets","pos":[0,37]}]},{"content":"Matching rules allow you to define criteria for automatic reconciliation between Dynamics AX bank transactions and bank statement transactions.","pos":[2391,2534]},{"content":"Set up of matching rules is done on <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Reconciliation matching rules<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[2536,2611],"source":"  Set up of matching rules is done on **Reconciliation matching rules** page."},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Set up bank reconciliation matching rules<ept id=\"p1\">](set-up-bank-reconciliation-matching-rules.md)</ept>.","pos":[2613,2729],"source":"  For more information, see [Set up bank reconciliation matching rules](set-up-bank-reconciliation-matching-rules.md)."},{"content":"Matching rule sets are used to define a group of matching rules that are run in sequence during the bank reconciliation process.","pos":[2730,2858]},{"content":"Matching rule sets are configured on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Reconciliation matching rule sets<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[2860,2944],"source":"  Matching rule sets are configured on the **Reconciliation matching rule sets** page."},{"pos":[2949,2984],"content":"Cash and bank management parameters","linkify":"Cash and bank management parameters","nodes":[{"content":"Cash and bank management parameters","pos":[0,35]}]},{"content":"There are a number of parameters specific to the advanced bank reconciliation process on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cash and bank management parameters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[2985,3123],"source":"There are a number of parameters specific to the advanced bank reconciliation process on the **Cash and bank management parameters** page."},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Show statement line amount in debit/credit<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> changes the view of amounts on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Bank statement<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page.","pos":[3125,3235],"source":"  The **Show statement line amount in debit/credit** changes the view of amounts on the **Bank statement** page."},{"content":"If this option is selected, the bank statement transaction amounts will be shown in separate debit and credit columns.","pos":[3237,3355]},{"content":"If not selected, the bank statement transaction amounts will be shown in a single amount column with the appropriate sign.","pos":[3357,3479]},{"content":"The validation options set on the parameters page override the selections set on matching rules.","pos":[3480,3576]},{"content":"For example, you cannot manually or automatically match documents beyond the date difference set on the parameters page.","pos":[3578,3698]},{"content":"Also, if the option to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Validate transaction type mapping<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> is selected, the transaction types must be mapped between the Dynamics AX bank transaction and bank statement transaction in order for the transactions to be manually or automatically matched.","pos":[3700,3953],"source":"  Also, if the option to **Validate transaction type mapping** is selected, the transaction types must be mapped between the Dynamics AX bank transaction and bank statement transaction in order for the transactions to be manually or automatically matched."},{"content":"You also must configure the necessary number sequences on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cash and bank management parameters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[3954,4061],"source":" You also must configure the necessary number sequences on the **Cash and bank management parameters** page."},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Number sequences<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, set number sequence codes for the Download <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>ID, Statement ID, Reconcile ID, and Bank reconciliation<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> references.","pos":[4063,4210],"source":"  On the **Number sequences** tab, set number sequence codes for the Download **ID, Statement ID, Reconcile ID, and Bank reconciliation** references."},{"pos":[4215,4250],"content":"Bank account reconciliation options","linkify":"Bank account reconciliation options","nodes":[{"content":"Bank account reconciliation options","pos":[0,35]}]},{"content":"You must first enable Advanced bank reconciliation for the bank account.","pos":[4251,4323]},{"content":"A number of additional options are available on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Bank account<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page once the Advanced bank reconciliation functionality is enabled.","pos":[4325,4462],"source":"  A number of additional options are available on the **Bank account** page once the Advanced bank reconciliation functionality is enabled."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Use bank statements as confirmation of electronic payment<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> functionality integrates the bank reconciliation functionality with electronic payment statuses.","pos":[4463,4621],"source":"**Use bank statements as confirmation of electronic payment** functionality integrates the bank reconciliation functionality with electronic payment statuses."},{"content":"When this is enabled, a bank document will automatically be created for the electronic payment status is set to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Sent<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[4623,4744],"source":"  When this is enabled, a bank document will automatically be created for the electronic payment status is set to **Sent**."},{"content":"In addition, the status of an electronic payment will be updated from <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Sent<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Received<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> after the payment is matched, reconciled, and posted.","pos":[4746,4894],"source":"  In addition, the status of an electronic payment will be updated from **Sent** to **Received** after the payment is matched, reconciled, and posted."},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Bank account name in statements<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field is the name used for the bank account on your electronic bank statements.","pos":[4895,5014],"source":" The **Bank account name in statements** field is the name used for the bank account on your electronic bank statements."},{"content":"This name is used when determining what transactions to import for a bank account from a statement that may contain information for multiple bank accounts.","pos":[5016,5171]},{"content":"The option to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Reconcile after import<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> will automatically validate the bank statement, create a new bank reconciliation and worksheet, and run the Default matching rule set.","pos":[5172,5347],"source":" The option to **Reconcile after import** will automatically validate the bank statement, create a new bank reconciliation and worksheet, and run the Default matching rule set."},{"content":"This functionality automates the process up to the point of the transactions that must be manually matched.","pos":[5349,5456]},{"content":"The setting on the bank account will default when importing.","pos":[5458,5518]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Matching rule for manual matching<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> is the matching rule that you want to be used when manually matching transactions in the reconciliation worksheet.","pos":[5519,5675],"source":" The **Matching rule for manual matching** is the matching rule that you want to be used when manually matching transactions in the reconciliation worksheet."},{"content":"This rule is run when selecting an unmatched bank statement transaction, and it will give you a suggestion for a matching Dynamics AX transaction.","pos":[5677,5823]},{"content":"Since you will verify the match before it is completed, this rule can be more general than the automated rules.","pos":[5825,5936]},{"content":"For example, your manual matching rule could match only the amount.","pos":[5938,6005]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Reversal rule for manual matching<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> is the matching rule that you want to be used to match an original bank statement line and a reversal bank statement line in the reconciliation worksheet.","pos":[6006,6202],"source":" The **Reversal rule for manual matching** is the matching rule that you want to be used to match an original bank statement line and a reversal bank statement line in the reconciliation worksheet."},{"content":"Similar to the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Matching rule for manual matching<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, you will verify the match before it is completed and so this rule can be more general than the automated rules.","pos":[6204,6369],"source":"  Similar to the **Matching rule for manual matching**, you will verify the match before it is completed and so this rule can be more general than the automated rules."}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Advanced bank reconciliation overview\ndescription: Advanced bank reconciliation allows you to import electronic bank statements and automatically reconcile with bank transactions in Microsoft Dynamics AX.  This article will explain the set up processes for reconciliation.  \nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 2016-07-11 15 - 58 - 27\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \n# ms.reviewer: 101\nms.search.scope: AX 7.0.0, Operations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 98303\nms.assetid: 9826ed58-cadc-43e8-bed8-27055d2cc0b5\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: saraschi\nms.dyn365.intro: Feb-16\nms.dyn365.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Advanced bank reconciliation overview\n\nAdvanced bank reconciliation allows you to import electronic bank statements and automatically reconcile with bank transactions in Microsoft Dynamics AX.  This article will explain the set up processes for reconciliation.  \n\nThere are a number of pieces that must be set up before using the advanced bank reconciliation functionality. For more information about setting up bank statement import, see [Set up the bank statement import process](set-up-advanced-bank-reconciliation-import-process.md).  Requirements for set up of the reconciliation process are detailed below.\n\n## Transaction codes\nTransaction codes can be used as part of the bank reconciliation matching rules.  Transaction codes will help to match only the same types of transactions between Dynamics AX and your bank statement.  In order to do this type of matching, you must first define transaction types used for bank transactions from Dynamics AX, then map those types to statement transaction codes used by your bank.  Transaction types for Dynamics AX bank transactions are defined on the **Bank transaction type** page.  This is also where you define the main account to be used for postings associated with that transaction type. Once your Dynamics AX bank transaction codes are defined, you then map those to the transaction codes used in your electronic bank statements.  This mapping process is done using the **Transaction code mapping** page.  Transaction code mapping is completed separately for each bank account.\n\n## Matching rules and matching rule sets\nMatching rules allow you to define criteria for automatic reconciliation between Dynamics AX bank transactions and bank statement transactions.  Set up of matching rules is done on **Reconciliation matching rules** page.  For more information, see [Set up bank reconciliation matching rules](set-up-bank-reconciliation-matching-rules.md). Matching rule sets are used to define a group of matching rules that are run in sequence during the bank reconciliation process.  Matching rule sets are configured on the **Reconciliation matching rule sets** page.\n\n## Cash and bank management parameters\nThere are a number of parameters specific to the advanced bank reconciliation process on the **Cash and bank management parameters** page.  The **Show statement line amount in debit/credit** changes the view of amounts on the **Bank statement** page.  If this option is selected, the bank statement transaction amounts will be shown in separate debit and credit columns.  If not selected, the bank statement transaction amounts will be shown in a single amount column with the appropriate sign. The validation options set on the parameters page override the selections set on matching rules.  For example, you cannot manually or automatically match documents beyond the date difference set on the parameters page.  Also, if the option to **Validate transaction type mapping** is selected, the transaction types must be mapped between the Dynamics AX bank transaction and bank statement transaction in order for the transactions to be manually or automatically matched. You also must configure the necessary number sequences on the **Cash and bank management parameters** page.  On the **Number sequences** tab, set number sequence codes for the Download **ID, Statement ID, Reconcile ID, and Bank reconciliation** references.\n\n## Bank account reconciliation options\nYou must first enable Advanced bank reconciliation for the bank account.  A number of additional options are available on the **Bank account** page once the Advanced bank reconciliation functionality is enabled. **Use bank statements as confirmation of electronic payment** functionality integrates the bank reconciliation functionality with electronic payment statuses.  When this is enabled, a bank document will automatically be created for the electronic payment status is set to **Sent**.  In addition, the status of an electronic payment will be updated from **Sent** to **Received** after the payment is matched, reconciled, and posted. The **Bank account name in statements** field is the name used for the bank account on your electronic bank statements.  This name is used when determining what transactions to import for a bank account from a statement that may contain information for multiple bank accounts. The option to **Reconcile after import** will automatically validate the bank statement, create a new bank reconciliation and worksheet, and run the Default matching rule set.  This functionality automates the process up to the point of the transactions that must be manually matched.  The setting on the bank account will default when importing. The **Matching rule for manual matching** is the matching rule that you want to be used when manually matching transactions in the reconciliation worksheet.  This rule is run when selecting an unmatched bank statement transaction, and it will give you a suggestion for a matching Dynamics AX transaction.  Since you will verify the match before it is completed, this rule can be more general than the automated rules.  For example, your manual matching rule could match only the amount. The **Reversal rule for manual matching** is the matching rule that you want to be used to match an original bank statement line and a reversal bank statement line in the reconciliation worksheet.  Similar to the **Matching rule for manual matching**, you will verify the match before it is completed and so this rule can be more general than the automated rules.\n\n"}