{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,91],"content":"Install the modern report design templates | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Install the modern report design templates | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,59]}]},{"pos":[105,323],"content":"This articles describes how to install the modern report design templates in the application suite. You can use these samples to create graphically rich business documents that have flexible header and footer branding.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"This articles describes how to install the modern report design templates in the application suite. You can use these samples to create graphically rich business documents that have flexible header and footer branding.","pos":[0,218],"nodes":[{"content":"This articles describes how to install the modern report design templates in the application suite.","pos":[0,99]},{"content":"You can use these samples to create graphically rich business documents that have flexible header and footer branding.","pos":[100,218]}]}]},{"pos":[747,789],"content":"Install the modern report design templates","linkify":"Install the modern report design templates","nodes":[{"content":"Install the modern report design templates","pos":[0,42]}]},{"pos":[791,803],"content":"Introduction","linkify":"Introduction","nodes":[{"content":"Introduction","pos":[0,12]}]},{"content":"This article introduces a new set of developer tools that take the form of report designs for several core business documents in the application suite.","pos":[818,969]},{"content":"These report designs have been re-imagined so that flexible branding in the header and footer is rendered for publicly facing documents when transactions are generated in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations.","pos":[970,1179]},{"content":"The following illustration shows how a legacy design for a sales invoice differs from a modern sales invoice.","pos":[1180,1289]},{"content":"Examples of a legacy design for a sales invoice and a modern sales invoice","pos":[1292,1366]},{"pos":[1410,1489],"content":"Why aren't these designs the default designs for the application suite reports?","linkify":"Why aren't these designs the default designs for the application suite reports?","nodes":[{"content":"Why aren't these designs the default designs for the application suite reports?","pos":[0,79]}]},{"content":"There are two primary reasons why we are maintaining the legacy solutions for Dynamics 365 for Operations:","pos":[1490,1596]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Modern designs don't include code behind.<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","pos":[1602,1647],"source":"**Modern designs don't include code behind.**"},{"content":"Whereas the legacy solutions use embedded Microsoft Visual Basic (VB) code to recognize configuration keys and honor regulatory requirements that vary by region, the modern designs offer much less flexibility.","pos":[1648,1857]},{"content":"The benefit of a simple design that has minimal code behind comes at the expense of reusability across regions.","pos":[1858,1969]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Modern designs aren't available for all business documents.<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","pos":[1974,2037],"source":"**Modern designs aren't available for all business documents.**"},{"content":"As for any 'preview,' there is a gap between supported business documents and the availability of a modern design.","pos":[2038,2152]},{"content":"Despite the lack of aesthetics in the legacy designs, they provide a sense of consistency, for better or worse.","pos":[2153,2264]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Important:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> These simple modern designs are <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>not<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> recommended for all types of deployments.","pos":[2266,2362],"source":"**Important:** These simple modern designs are **not** recommended for all types of deployments."},{"content":"They are intended for cases where the customer doesn't require run-time control over the layout of the document through existing application configuration settings.","pos":[2363,2527]},{"pos":[2532,2556],"content":"Apply the modern designs","linkify":"Apply the modern designs","nodes":[{"content":"Apply the modern designs","pos":[0,24]}]},{"content":"The report designs have been bundled into a model file and posted to Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS), so that you can easily access them from your existing subscription.","pos":[2557,2738]},{"content":"Use the following procedure to obtain the report design solutions and install them in your local development environment.","pos":[2739,2860]},{"content":"After you've installed them, you must apply some customizations to incorporate the new report designs for the appropriate scenarios.","pos":[2861,2993]},{"content":"Follow these steps to install the modern report designs for the application suite.","pos":[2994,3076]},{"content":"Download the ApplicationSuiteModernDesigns model file from the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Shared asset library<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page on LCS.","pos":[3082,3182],"source":"Download the ApplicationSuiteModernDesigns model file from the **Shared asset library** page on LCS."},{"content":"Sign in to <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services<ept id=\"p1\">](https://lcs.dynamics.com/)</ept> to access the deployment dashboard, and then save the model file to a location that is accessible from the development environment.","pos":[3183,3392],"source":" Sign in to [Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services](https://lcs.dynamics.com/) to access the deployment dashboard, and then save the model file to a location that is accessible from the development environment."},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>ApplicationSuiteModernDesigns model file<ph id=\"ph2\">](media/lcs-shared-asset-library-1024x489.png)</ph>","pos":[3393,3481],"source":"![ApplicationSuiteModernDesigns model file](media/lcs-shared-asset-library-1024x489.png)"},{"content":"Import the model file into your local development environment.","pos":[3486,3548]},{"content":"To install a model file in a Dynamics 365 for Operations development environment, use the ModelUtil.exe tool and the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>-import<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> directive.","pos":[3549,3688],"source":" To install a model file in a Dynamics 365 for Operations development environment, use the ModelUtil.exe tool and the **-import** directive."},{"pos":[3813,3824],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Example<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**Example**"},{"content":"Navigate to the C:<ph id=\"ph1\">\\\\</ph>AOSService<ph id=\"ph2\">\\\\</ph>PackagesLocalDirectory<ph id=\"ph3\">\\\\</ph>bin folder.","pos":[3834,3901],"source":"Navigate to the C:\\\\AOSService\\\\PackagesLocalDirectory\\\\bin folder."},{"content":"Run the following command.","pos":[3910,3936]},{"content":"For more information about how to import model files, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Distribution of models: How to export and import a model<ept id=\"p1\">](https://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/distribution-of-models-how-to-export-and-import-a-model/)</ept>.","pos":[4079,4291],"source":"For more information about how to import model files, see [Distribution of models: How to export and import a model](https://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/distribution-of-models-how-to-export-and-import-a-model/)."},{"content":"After you've imported the model file, start Microsoft Visual Studio 2015 to verify that the new collection appears under the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>AOT<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> node in Application Explorer.","pos":[4292,4454],"source":" After you've imported the model file, start Microsoft Visual Studio 2015 to verify that the new collection appears under the **AOT** node in Application Explorer."},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>New collection under the AOT node<ph id=\"ph2\">](media/imported-model-file-1024x488.png)</ph>","pos":[4455,4531],"source":"![New collection under the AOT node](media/imported-model-file-1024x488.png)"},{"content":"Follow these steps to incorporate the modern report design into an existing application suite report:","pos":[4537,4638]},{"content":"Create a project that contains the application suite report.","pos":[4647,4707]},{"pos":[4716,4804],"content":"Copy the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>DocuBrandDetailsDS<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> data set, and paste it into the collection of data sets.","source":"Copy the **DocuBrandDetailsDS** data set, and paste it into the collection of data sets."},{"pos":[4813,4901],"content":"Copy the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Modern<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> design, and paste it into the collection of existing report designs.","source":"Copy the **Modern** design, and paste it into the collection of existing report designs."},{"content":"Build and deploy the updated application suite report, which now includes the modern report design.","pos":[4910,5009]},{"content":"Incorporating the modern report design into an existing application suite report","pos":[5017,5097]},{"content":"By adding the modern report design to the existing report, you can reuse both the parameter handling and the data provider that the out-of-box solution uses.","pos":[5142,5299]},{"content":"Update the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Controller<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> object to add references to the new report design.","pos":[5304,5380],"source":"Update the **Controller** object to add references to the new report design."},{"content":"Search for code that resembles the following code.","pos":[5381,5431]},{"content":"This code is often nested in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>preModify<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> method of the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Controller<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> object.","pos":[5432,5515],"source":" This code is often nested in the **preModify** method of the **Controller** object."},{"content":"At this point, you should be able to access the modern report designs from the application.","pos":[5639,5730]},{"content":"Be sure to perform thorough test validations on these design templates before you deploy to production environments.","pos":[5731,5847]}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Install the modern report design templates | Microsoft Docs\ndescription: This articles describes how to install the modern report design templates in the application suite. You can use these samples to create graphically rich business documents that have flexible header and footer branding.\nauthor: annbe\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 2016-04-14 13:31:54\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# keywords: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: 71\nms.suite: Released- Dynamics AX 7.0.0\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 82783\nms.assetid: 6372e4af-b206-4d99-8ead-74493eb41715\n# ms.region: \n# ms.industry: \nms.author: sericks007\n\n---\n\n# Install the modern report design templates\n\nIntroduction\n------------\n\nThis article introduces a new set of developer tools that take the form of report designs for several core business documents in the application suite. These report designs have been re-imagined so that flexible branding in the header and footer is rendered for publicly facing documents when transactions are generated in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations. The following illustration shows how a legacy design for a sales invoice differs from a modern sales invoice. ![Examples of a legacy design for a sales invoice and a modern sales invoice](media/design-comparison-1024x653.png)\n\n## Why aren't these designs the default designs for the application suite reports?\nThere are two primary reasons why we are maintaining the legacy solutions for Dynamics 365 for Operations:\n\n-   **Modern designs don't include code behind.** Whereas the legacy solutions use embedded Microsoft Visual Basic (VB) code to recognize configuration keys and honor regulatory requirements that vary by region, the modern designs offer much less flexibility. The benefit of a simple design that has minimal code behind comes at the expense of reusability across regions.\n-   **Modern designs aren't available for all business documents.** As for any 'preview,' there is a gap between supported business documents and the availability of a modern design. Despite the lack of aesthetics in the legacy designs, they provide a sense of consistency, for better or worse.\n\n**Important:** These simple modern designs are **not** recommended for all types of deployments. They are intended for cases where the customer doesn't require run-time control over the layout of the document through existing application configuration settings.\n\n## Apply the modern designs\nThe report designs have been bundled into a model file and posted to Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS), so that you can easily access them from your existing subscription. Use the following procedure to obtain the report design solutions and install them in your local development environment. After you've installed them, you must apply some customizations to incorporate the new report designs for the appropriate scenarios. Follow these steps to install the modern report designs for the application suite.\n\n1.  Download the ApplicationSuiteModernDesigns model file from the **Shared asset library** page on LCS. Sign in to [Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services](https://lcs.dynamics.com/) to access the deployment dashboard, and then save the model file to a location that is accessible from the development environment. ![ApplicationSuiteModernDesigns model file](media/lcs-shared-asset-library-1024x489.png)\n2.  Import the model file into your local development environment. To install a model file in a Dynamics 365 for Operations development environment, use the ModelUtil.exe tool and the **-import** directive.\n\n        ModelUtil.exe -import -metadatastorepath=[path of the metadata store] -file=[full path of the file to import]\n\n    **Example**\n\n    1.  Navigate to the C:\\\\AOSService\\\\PackagesLocalDirectory\\\\bin folder.\n    2.  Run the following command.\n\n            ModelUtil.exe -import -metadatastorepath=C:\\AOSService\\PackagesLocalDirectory -file=\"E:\\Test\\AppSuiteModernDesigns.axmodel\"\n\n    For more information about how to import model files, see [Distribution of models: How to export and import a model](https://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/distribution-of-models-how-to-export-and-import-a-model/). After you've imported the model file, start Microsoft Visual Studio 2015 to verify that the new collection appears under the **AOT** node in Application Explorer. ![New collection under the AOT node](media/imported-model-file-1024x488.png)\n\n3.  Follow these steps to incorporate the modern report design into an existing application suite report:\n    1.  Create a project that contains the application suite report.\n    2.  Copy the **DocuBrandDetailsDS** data set, and paste it into the collection of data sets.\n    3.  Copy the **Modern** design, and paste it into the collection of existing report designs.\n    4.  Build and deploy the updated application suite report, which now includes the modern report design.\n\n    ![Incorporating the modern report design into an existing application suite report](media/Copying-modern-designs1-1024x569.png)By adding the modern report design to the existing report, you can reuse both the parameter handling and the data provider that the out-of-box solution uses.\n4.  Update the **Controller** object to add references to the new report design. Search for code that resembles the following code. This code is often nested in the **preModify** method of the **Controller** object.\n\n        // select the report design\n        this.parmReportName(ssrsReportStr(CustAccountStatementExt, DesignName));\n\n    At this point, you should be able to access the modern report designs from the application. Be sure to perform thorough test validations on these design templates before you deploy to production environments.\n\n\n\n"}