{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Financial Performance Power BI content\ndescription: This topic describes the Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations Financial Performance content pack for Microsoft Power BI. It describes the dashboard and reports that are included in the content pack, and provides information about the data model and entities that were used to build the content pack.\nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 04/04/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \n# ms.reviewer: 71\nms.search.scope: AX 7.0.0, Operations, Core\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 106233\nms.assetid: 517e6a88-e7a1-4398-9971-b22fa83306ba\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: kweekley\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Financial Performance Power BI content\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThis topic describes the Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations Financial Performance content pack for Microsoft Power BI. It describes the dashboard and reports that are included in the content pack, and provides information about the data model and entities that were used to build the content pack.\n\nAccessing the content pack\n--------------------------\n\nTwo versions of the Financial Performance content pack are available. One version is available from Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS), and the other is available from PowerBI.com.\n\n-   **Version that is available from LCS:** The Financial Performance content pack that is available from LCS supports Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations version 1611. You can find the content pack in the Shared asset library in LCS. For more information about how to download the content pack and connect it to your Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations data, see [Power BI content in LCS from Microsoft and your partners](power-bi-content-microsoft-partners.md).\n-   **Version that is available from PowerBI.com:** The Financial Performance content pack that is available from PowerBI.com supports Microsoft Dynamics AX versions 7.0 and 7.0.1. For more information about how to connect and load your Dynamics 365 for Operations data, see [Access Power BI content from PowerBI.com](power-bi-home-page.md).\n\n## Main account setup\nBecause organizations want liabilities and revenue amounts to appear as positive amounts on reports, the setup of the main accounts in Dynamics 365 for Operations is important. For these main accounts to appear as positive amounts, the main account type must be set to **Liability** or **Revenue**. When these account types are used, reporting through Microsoft Power BI will reverse the signs and show the amounts as positive.\n\n## Dashboard and reports that are included in the content pack\nAfter you’ve connected the content pack to your Dynamics 365 for Operations data, the dashboard and reports show your financial data. If you’ve never used Power BI before, you can learn more about it on the [Guided Learning page for Power BI](https://powerbi.microsoft.com/en-us/guided-learning/?WT.mc_id=PBIService_GetData). The dashboard contains summarized tiles of data that are based on underlying reports. Each tile contains summarized information for the current year across all companies in an organization. Here are some of the tiles:\n\n-   Cash\n-   Total Revenue this year\n-   Total Expenses this year\n-   Net Income this year\n-   Quick Ratio\n-   Total Expenses this year by account category\n-   Current Ratio\n-   Debt to Total Assets\n-   Actual vs Forecasted Revenue\n-   Billed Revenue this Year\n-   Operating expenses Ratio this year\n-   Profit Margin this year\n-   Actual vs Budget Expenses – All companies\n\nEach tile is backed by a supporting report. These reports contain both charts and tables that provide more information. The following table describes the reports.\n\n| Report                      | Information that the report contains                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                          |\n|-----------------------------|-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| Cash Analysis               | Cash by legal entity, cash by quarter, total cash, and cash by account **Note:** The **Cash by quarter** report doesn't include beginning balances in the total for the first quarter. It shows the total of new transactions that are posted in each quarter.                                                                                |\n| Current Ratio Analysis      | Current ratio by legal entity, current ratio by quarter, and balances for current assets and current liabilities                                                                                                                                                                                                                              |\n| Quick Ratio Analysis        | Quick ratio by legal entity, quick ratio by quarter, and balances for cash, accounts receivable, and current liabilities                                                                                                                                                                                                                      |\n| Cost of Goods Sold Analysis | Cost of goods sold (COGS) by legal entity, COGS this year and last year by quarter, COGS to sales by legal entity, total COGS, and COGS to sales percentage                                                                                                                                                                                   |\n| Working Capital Analysis    | Working capital by legal entity, working capital by quarter, current assets, current liabilities, and total working capital                                                                                                                                                                                                                   |\n| Asset and Debt Analysis     | Return on total assets and debt to total assets by legal entity, debt to total assets and return on total assets quarter to date, assets, and liabilities                                                                                                                                                                                     |\n| Profit Margin Analysis      | Actual and budget profit margin by legal entity, profit marking by quarter, profit margin percentage, and profit margin                                                                                                                                                                                                                       |\n| Net Income Analysis         | Actual and budget net income by legal entity, net income this year and last year, and expenses to net income percentage                                                                                                                                                                                                                       |\n| Earnings Analysis           | Actual and budget earnings before interest and taxes (EBIT) by legal entity, EBIT this year and last year, expenses to revenue percentage, and actual and budget expenses to revenue                                                                                                                                                          |\n| Revenue Analysis            | Total revenue, actual and budget total revenue by legal entity, total revenue this year and last year, revenue budget variance by legal entity, and total revenue this period and last period                                                                                                                                                 |\n| Expense Analysis            | Total expenses, actual to budget total expenses by legal entity, actual and budget total expense by quarter, total expenses by account category, and operating expenses ratio                                                                                                                                                                 |\n| Billed Revenue Analysis     | Total accounts receivable, total accounts receivable by legal entity, total accounts receivable by quarter, and balances for accounts receivable accounts **Note:** The reports don't include beginning balances for the accounts receivable ledger accounts. They show the total of new transactions that are posted to Accounts receivable. |\n\nThe charts and tiles on all these reports can be filtered and pinned to the dashboard. For more information about how to filter and pin in Power BI, see [Create and Configure a Dashboard](https://powerbi.microsoft.com/en-us/guided-learning/powerbi-learning-4-2-create-configure-dashboards).\n\n## Understanding the data model and entities\nThe data that populates the dashboard and reports in the Financial Performance content pack is Dynamics 365 for Operations data. The following entities were used as the basis of the content pack: **Aggregate data entities**\n\n-   **GeneralLedgerActivities** – This entity aggregates general ledger balances by account category.\n-   **BudgetActivities** – This entity aggregates budget balances by account category.\n\n**Data entities**\n\n-   FiscalCalendars\n-   MainAccounts\n-   LegalEntities\n-   Ledgers\n-   ChartofAccounts\n\nThese entities were used to create calculated measures in the data model. The calculated measures are used to calculate the key performance indicators (KPIs) and reports that are used in the content pack. By default, the content pack brings in data for the last three years and one future year. To include additional calculations on your reports and dashboard, you can modify the [Microsoft Excel workbook](https://mbs.microsoft.com/customersource/global/AX/downloads/reports/msdaxfinpercontentpowerbi). This workbook is the default data model that was used to create the content pack. After you've finished making your modifications, you can create an organizational content pack and dashboard that contain the information that you’ve added.\n\n## Additional resources\nHere are some helpful links that are related to entities and building Power BI content:\n\n-   [Data entities](..\\data-entities\\data-entities.md)\n-   [Creating organizational content packs](https://powerbi.microsoft.com/en-us/documentation/powerbi-service-organizational-content-packs-introduction/)\n-   [Data modeling using Power BI](https://powerbi.microsoft.com/en-us/guided-learning/powerbi-learning-2-1-intro-modeling-data)\n-   [Adding Power BI tiles to workspaces](configure-power-bi-integration.md)\n\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[32,70],"content":"Financial Performance Power BI content","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Financial Performance Power BI content","pos":[0,38]}]},{"pos":[84,384],"content":"This topic describes the Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations Financial Performance content pack for Microsoft Power BI. It describes the dashboard and reports that are included in the content pack, and provides information about the data model and entities that were used to build the content pack.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"This topic describes the Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations Financial Performance content pack for Microsoft Power BI. It describes the dashboard and reports that are included in the content pack, and provides information about the data model and entities that were used to build the content pack.","pos":[0,300],"nodes":[{"content":"This topic describes the Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations Financial Performance content pack for Microsoft Power BI.","pos":[0,121]},{"content":"It describes the dashboard and reports that are included in the content pack, and provides information about the data model and entities that were used to build the content pack.","pos":[122,300]}]}]},{"pos":[904,942],"content":"Financial Performance Power BI content","linkify":"Financial Performance Power BI content","nodes":[{"content":"Financial Performance Power BI content","pos":[0,38]}]},{"content":"This topic describes the Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations Financial Performance content pack for Microsoft Power BI.","pos":[988,1109]},{"content":"It describes the dashboard and reports that are included in the content pack, and provides information about the data model and entities that were used to build the content pack.","pos":[1110,1288]},{"pos":[1290,1316],"content":"Accessing the content pack","linkify":"Accessing the content pack","nodes":[{"content":"Accessing the content pack","pos":[0,26]}]},{"content":"Two versions of the Financial Performance content pack are available.","pos":[1345,1414]},{"content":"One version is available from Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS), and the other is available from PowerBI.com.","pos":[1415,1534]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Version that is available from LCS:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> The Financial Performance content pack that is available from LCS supports Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations version 1611.","pos":[1540,1706],"source":"**Version that is available from LCS:** The Financial Performance content pack that is available from LCS supports Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations version 1611."},{"content":"You can find the content pack in the Shared asset library in LCS.","pos":[1707,1772]},{"content":"For more information about how to download the content pack and connect it to your Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations data, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Power BI content in LCS from Microsoft and your partners<ept id=\"p1\">](power-bi-content-microsoft-partners.md)</ept>.","pos":[1773,2003],"source":" For more information about how to download the content pack and connect it to your Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations data, see [Power BI content in LCS from Microsoft and your partners](power-bi-content-microsoft-partners.md)."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Version that is available from PowerBI.com:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> The Financial Performance content pack that is available from PowerBI.com supports Microsoft Dynamics AX versions 7.0 and 7.0.1.","pos":[2008,2184],"source":"**Version that is available from PowerBI.com:** The Financial Performance content pack that is available from PowerBI.com supports Microsoft Dynamics AX versions 7.0 and 7.0.1."},{"content":"For more information about how to connect and load your Dynamics 365 for Operations data, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Access Power BI content from PowerBI.com<ept id=\"p1\">](power-bi-home-page.md)</ept>.","pos":[2185,2345],"source":" For more information about how to connect and load your Dynamics 365 for Operations data, see [Access Power BI content from PowerBI.com](power-bi-home-page.md)."},{"pos":[2350,2368],"content":"Main account setup","linkify":"Main account setup","nodes":[{"content":"Main account setup","pos":[0,18]}]},{"content":"Because organizations want liabilities and revenue amounts to appear as positive amounts on reports, the setup of the main accounts in Dynamics 365 for Operations is important.","pos":[2369,2545]},{"content":"For these main accounts to appear as positive amounts, the main account type must be set to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Liability<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Revenue<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[2546,2667],"source":" For these main accounts to appear as positive amounts, the main account type must be set to **Liability** or **Revenue**."},{"content":"When these account types are used, reporting through Microsoft Power BI will reverse the signs and show the amounts as positive.","pos":[2668,2796]},{"pos":[2801,2860],"content":"Dashboard and reports that are included in the content pack","linkify":"Dashboard and reports that are included in the content pack","nodes":[{"content":"Dashboard and reports that are included in the content pack","pos":[0,59]}]},{"content":"After you’ve connected the content pack to your Dynamics 365 for Operations data, the dashboard and reports show your financial data.","pos":[2861,2994]},{"content":"If you’ve never used Power BI before, you can learn more about it on the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Guided Learning page for Power BI<ept id=\"p1\">](https://powerbi.microsoft.com/en-us/guided-learning/?WT.mc_id=PBIService_GetData)</ept>.","pos":[2995,3186],"source":" If you’ve never used Power BI before, you can learn more about it on the [Guided Learning page for Power BI](https://powerbi.microsoft.com/en-us/guided-learning/?WT.mc_id=PBIService_GetData)."},{"content":"The dashboard contains summarized tiles of data that are based on underlying reports.","pos":[3187,3272]},{"content":"Each tile contains summarized information for the current year across all companies in an organization.","pos":[3273,3376]},{"content":"Here are some of the tiles:","pos":[3377,3404]},{"content":"Cash","pos":[3410,3414]},{"content":"Total Revenue this year","pos":[3419,3442]},{"content":"Total Expenses this year","pos":[3447,3471]},{"content":"Net Income this year","pos":[3476,3496]},{"content":"Quick Ratio","pos":[3501,3512]},{"content":"Total Expenses this year by account category","pos":[3517,3561]},{"content":"Current Ratio","pos":[3566,3579]},{"content":"Debt to Total Assets","pos":[3584,3604]},{"content":"Actual vs Forecasted Revenue","pos":[3609,3637]},{"content":"Billed Revenue this Year","pos":[3642,3666]},{"content":"Operating expenses Ratio this year","pos":[3671,3705]},{"content":"Profit Margin this year","pos":[3710,3733]},{"content":"Actual vs Budget Expenses – All companies","pos":[3738,3779]},{"content":"Each tile is backed by a supporting report.","pos":[3781,3824]},{"content":"These reports contain both charts and tables that provide more information.","pos":[3825,3900]},{"content":"The following table describes the reports.","pos":[3901,3943]},{"content":"Report","pos":[3947,3953]},{"content":"Information that the report contains","pos":[3977,4013]},{"content":"Cash Analysis","pos":[4683,4696]},{"content":"Cash by legal entity, cash by quarter, total cash, and cash by account <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> The <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Cash by quarter<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> report doesn't include beginning balances in the total for the first quarter.","pos":[4713,4895],"source":"Cash by legal entity, cash by quarter, total cash, and cash by account **Note:** The **Cash by quarter** report doesn't include beginning balances in the total for the first quarter."},{"content":"It shows the total of new transactions that are posted in each quarter.","pos":[4896,4967]},{"content":"Current Ratio Analysis","pos":[5051,5073]},{"content":"Current ratio by legal entity, current ratio by quarter, and balances for current assets and current liabilities","pos":[5081,5193]},{"content":"Quick Ratio Analysis","pos":[5419,5439]},{"content":"Quick ratio by legal entity, quick ratio by quarter, and balances for cash, accounts receivable, and current liabilities","pos":[5449,5569]},{"content":"Cost of Goods Sold Analysis","pos":[5787,5814]},{"content":"Cost of goods sold (COGS) by legal entity, COGS this year and last year by quarter, COGS to sales by legal entity, total COGS, and COGS to sales percentage","pos":[5817,5972]},{"content":"Working Capital Analysis","pos":[6155,6179]},{"content":"Working capital by legal entity, working capital by quarter, current assets, current liabilities, and total working capital","pos":[6185,6308]},{"content":"Asset and Debt Analysis","pos":[6523,6546]},{"content":"Return on total assets and debt to total assets by legal entity, debt to total assets and return on total assets quarter to date, assets, and liabilities","pos":[6553,6706]},{"content":"Profit Margin Analysis","pos":[6891,6913]},{"content":"Actual and budget profit margin by legal entity, profit marking by quarter, profit margin percentage, and profit margin","pos":[6921,7040]},{"content":"Net Income Analysis","pos":[7259,7278]},{"content":"Actual and budget net income by legal entity, net income this year and last year, and expenses to net income percentage","pos":[7289,7408]},{"content":"Earnings Analysis","pos":[7627,7644]},{"content":"Actual and budget earnings before interest and taxes (EBIT) by legal entity, EBIT this year and last year, expenses to revenue percentage, and actual and budget expenses to revenue","pos":[7657,7837]},{"content":"Revenue Analysis","pos":[7995,8011]},{"content":"Total revenue, actual and budget total revenue by legal entity, total revenue this year and last year, revenue budget variance by legal entity, and total revenue this period and last period","pos":[8025,8214]},{"content":"Expense Analysis","pos":[8363,8379]},{"content":"Total expenses, actual to budget total expenses by legal entity, actual and budget total expense by quarter, total expenses by account category, and operating expenses ratio","pos":[8393,8566]},{"content":"Billed Revenue Analysis","pos":[8731,8754]},{"content":"Total accounts receivable, total accounts receivable by legal entity, total accounts receivable by quarter, and balances for accounts receivable accounts <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> The reports don't include beginning balances for the accounts receivable ledger accounts.","pos":[8761,9014],"source":"Total accounts receivable, total accounts receivable by legal entity, total accounts receivable by quarter, and balances for accounts receivable accounts **Note:** The reports don't include beginning balances for the accounts receivable ledger accounts."},{"content":"They show the total of new transactions that are posted to Accounts receivable.","pos":[9015,9094]},{"content":"The charts and tiles on all these reports can be filtered and pinned to the dashboard.","pos":[9098,9184]},{"content":"For more information about how to filter and pin in Power BI, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Create and Configure a Dashboard<ept id=\"p1\">](https://powerbi.microsoft.com/en-us/guided-learning/powerbi-learning-4-2-create-configure-dashboards)</ept>.","pos":[9185,9388],"source":" For more information about how to filter and pin in Power BI, see [Create and Configure a Dashboard](https://powerbi.microsoft.com/en-us/guided-learning/powerbi-learning-4-2-create-configure-dashboards)."},{"pos":[9393,9434],"content":"Understanding the data model and entities","linkify":"Understanding the data model and entities","nodes":[{"content":"Understanding the data model and entities","pos":[0,41]}]},{"content":"The data that populates the dashboard and reports in the Financial Performance content pack is Dynamics 365 for Operations data.","pos":[9435,9563]},{"content":"The following entities were used as the basis of the content pack: <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Aggregate data entities<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","pos":[9564,9658],"source":" The following entities were used as the basis of the content pack: **Aggregate data entities**"},{"pos":[9664,9761],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>GeneralLedgerActivities<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – This entity aggregates general ledger balances by account category.","source":"**GeneralLedgerActivities** – This entity aggregates general ledger balances by account category."},{"pos":[9766,9848],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>BudgetActivities<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – This entity aggregates budget balances by account category.","source":"**BudgetActivities** – This entity aggregates budget balances by account category."},{"pos":[9850,9867],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Data entities<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**Data entities**"},{"content":"FiscalCalendars","pos":[9873,9888]},{"content":"MainAccounts","pos":[9893,9905]},{"content":"LegalEntities","pos":[9910,9923]},{"content":"Ledgers","pos":[9928,9935]},{"content":"ChartofAccounts","pos":[9940,9955]},{"content":"These entities were used to create calculated measures in the data model.","pos":[9957,10030]},{"content":"The calculated measures are used to calculate the key performance indicators (KPIs) and reports that are used in the content pack.","pos":[10031,10161]},{"content":"By default, the content pack brings in data for the last three years and one future year.","pos":[10162,10251]},{"content":"To include additional calculations on your reports and dashboard, you can modify the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Excel workbook<ept id=\"p1\">](https://mbs.microsoft.com/customersource/global/AX/downloads/reports/msdaxfinpercontentpowerbi)</ept>.","pos":[10252,10460],"source":" To include additional calculations on your reports and dashboard, you can modify the [Microsoft Excel workbook](https://mbs.microsoft.com/customersource/global/AX/downloads/reports/msdaxfinpercontentpowerbi)."},{"content":"This workbook is the default data model that was used to create the content pack.","pos":[10461,10542]},{"content":"After you've finished making your modifications, you can create an organizational content pack and dashboard that contain the information that you’ve added.","pos":[10543,10699]},{"pos":[10704,10724],"content":"Additional resources","linkify":"Additional resources","nodes":[{"content":"Additional resources","pos":[0,20]}]},{"content":"Here are some helpful links that are related to entities and building Power BI content:","pos":[10725,10812]},{"pos":[10818,10868],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Data entities<ept id=\"p1\">](..\\data-entities\\data-entities.md)</ept>","source":"[Data entities](..\\data-entities\\data-entities.md)"},{"pos":[10873,11022],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Creating organizational content packs<ept id=\"p1\">](https://powerbi.microsoft.com/en-us/documentation/powerbi-service-organizational-content-packs-introduction/)</ept>","source":"[Creating organizational content packs](https://powerbi.microsoft.com/en-us/documentation/powerbi-service-organizational-content-packs-introduction/)"},{"pos":[11027,11151],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Data modeling using Power BI<ept id=\"p1\">](https://powerbi.microsoft.com/en-us/guided-learning/powerbi-learning-2-1-intro-modeling-data)</ept>","source":"[Data modeling using Power BI](https://powerbi.microsoft.com/en-us/guided-learning/powerbi-learning-2-1-intro-modeling-data)"},{"pos":[11156,11228],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Adding Power BI tiles to workspaces<ept id=\"p1\">](configure-power-bi-integration.md)</ept>","source":"[Adding Power BI tiles to workspaces](configure-power-bi-integration.md)"}]}