{"nodes":[{"pos":[2,18],"content":"Retail home page","linkify":"Retail home page","nodes":[{"content":"Retail home page","pos":[0,16]}]},{"content":"This page points to resources that will help you use the Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations - Retail more effectively.","pos":[19,140]},{"content":"On the left-pane, select a feature area to learn more about it.","pos":[141,204]},{"content":"Dynamics 365 for Operations – Retail delivers a complete shopping experience, with a seamless and differentiating omni-channel solution that is modern, mobile, and global.","pos":[207,378]},{"content":"End-to-end capabilities, from modern point of sale (POS) software solutions, store operations, merchandising, e-commerce, call center, marketing, and customer care, to supply chain, financials, and more, can be deployed in the way that makes the most sense for your business.","pos":[379,654]},{"pos":[659,688],"content":"What's new and in development","linkify":"What's new and in development","nodes":[{"content":"What's new and in development","pos":[0,29]}]},{"pos":[689,843],"content":"Go to the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;a href=\"https://roadmap.dynamics.com/\"&gt;</bpt>Dynamics 365 Roadmap<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/a&gt;</ept> to see what new features are released and what new features are in development.","source":"Go to the <a href=\"https://roadmap.dynamics.com/\">Dynamics 365 Roadmap</a> to see what new features are released and what new features are in development."},{"content":"MARGO THIS IS NOT DONE!","pos":[846,869]}],"content":"# Retail home page\nThis page points to resources that will help you use the Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations - Retail more effectively. On the left-pane, select a feature area to learn more about it. \n\nDynamics 365 for Operations – Retail delivers a complete shopping experience, with a seamless and differentiating omni-channel solution that is modern, mobile, and global. End-to-end capabilities, from modern point of sale (POS) software solutions, store operations, merchandising, e-commerce, call center, marketing, and customer care, to supply chain, financials, and more, can be deployed in the way that makes the most sense for your business.\n\n## What's new and in development\nGo to the <a href=\"https://roadmap.dynamics.com/\">Dynamics 365 Roadmap</a> to see what new features are released and what new features are in development. \n\nMARGO THIS IS NOT DONE!\n"}