{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Enter payroll beginning balances\ndescription: The topic describes the steps for entering beginning balances for earning codes, deductions, benefits, and taxes. This information is valuable for Partners to migrate or transfer data for a new Payroll implementation from another system.\nauthor: kherr\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 07/01/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: rschloma\nms.search.scope: AX 7.0.0, Operations, Core\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 20931\nms.assetid: b48b1cb2-6e66-467e-9c0e-09b6a4aeb9fe\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: kherr\nms.search.validFrom: 2017-07-01\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Enter payroll beginning balances\n\n[!include[banner](../../includes/banner.md)]\n\nThe topic describes the steps for entering beginning balances for earning codes, deductions, benefits, and taxes. This information is valuable for partners who transfer data for a new Payroll implementation from another system. To prepare to enter beginning payroll balances, we verify the following information:\n\n> * Employee records are entered and available in the system\n> * The following data is set up and assigned to employees:\n\n> > * Pay cycles and pay periods\n> > * Earning codes\n> > * Taxes\n> > * Benefits and deductions\n\n> * The company should have chosen a date where payroll beginning balances can be set.\n\n> * Information were gathered on all earnings, benefits/deductions, benefit contributions, employee taxes, and employer taxes and their YTD amounts from the legacy system.\n\nAs you plan to enter beginning balances, consider how detailed the data needs to be. Most businesses enter a single, consolidated year-to-date amount. However if more detailed information is needed, balances can be entered in quarterly increments. Deciding the level of detail that's needed determines how many manual pay statements must be created for each worker. For a single year-to-date amount, only one manual statement is needed for each employee. To do this use year-to-date amounts from the final pay statement from the previous system as the amount entered in the new payroll system.\n\nThe following example shows how you can enter employee payroll beginning balances, including earning codes, benefits/deductions, and taxes. In a real-world example you would have a line item for each earning code, benefit deduction, benefit contribution, employee tax and employer tax with the amount entered being the year-to-date amount. Using that list of codes and amounts, follow the steps for creating a manual earning and pay statement with accounting disabled to bring over beginning balances for payroll purposes.  You disable accounting because you won't want to post this beginning balance pay statement to your general ledger. That was done in the legacy system and will come over to the new system when you set beginning balances in General ledger.\n\n> [!NOTE] \n> If you want to reproduce the same steps below, you can use the Demo data. The Demo data can be downloaded on PartnerSource\n\n### A. How to set up earnings codes to be used on payroll beginning balances\nWhen you enter payroll beginning balances, be sure the earning codes that you will be using are configured with the \"Allow editing of earning statement rates\" option enabled. This will allow you to manually key the amount from the legacy system. \n\n### B. Create earnings statement for an employee to have a beginning balance\nThis step manually creates an earnings statement for each worker for the last pay period of the legacy system, which creates the earning statement lines in the new payroll system. Enter one line per earning code and the YTD amount and hours. The sample steps are as follows:\n\n1. Open the **All earnings statements** page and click **New**.  \n\nEnter the following: \n\n| Field      | Value                 |\n|------------|-----------------------|\n| Worker     | Michael Redmond       |\n| Pay cycle  | sm                    |\n| Pay period | 6/16/2017 - 6/30/2017 |\n\n2. In the **Earnings statement line** tab, enter the following:\n\nLine 1: **Earning statement line** tab\n\n| Field            | Value       |\n|------------------|-------------|\n| Earnings code    | Regular pay |\n| Quantity         | 1.00        |\n| Rage             | 30,000      |\n| Line details tab |             |\n| Manual           | (marked)    |\n\nLine 2: **Earning statement line** tab\n\n| Field            | Value    |\n|------------------|----------|\n| Earnings code    | Bonus    |\n| Quantity         | 1.0000   |\n| Rate             | 4250.00  |\n| Line details tab |          |\n| Manual           | (marked) |\n\nLine 3: **Earning statement line** tab\n\n| Field           | Value      |\n|-----------------|------------|\n| Earnings code   | Commission |\n| Quantity        | 1.0000     |\n| Rate            | !,299.00   |\n| Rate            | 1,299.00   |\n| Line detail tab |            |\n| Manual          | (Marked)   |\n\n> [!NOTE]\n> Marking Manual checkbox setting in the **Line Details** tab for each earnings statement line is key to have payroll beginning balances entered for each worker.\n\n3. On the **Action** pane, click **Release earnings statement** USA-FED-ER-FICA.\n\n4. On the **Action** pane click **Pay statement** to open the **Generate pay statements** page and set the following:\n\n| Field              | Value     |\n|--------------------|-----------|\n| Payment date       | 6/30/2017 |\n| Payment run type   | Manual    |\n| Disable accounting | (marked)  |\n\n> [!NOTE] \n> This is only available when the payment run type is manual and wherein the user want to disable accounting on the pay run.\n\nClick **OK** and close the **Infolog**.\n\n#### Why Disable Accounting checkbox needs to be turned on when generating pay statements?\nThis prevents any lines in the pay statement from being distributed and posted to the General ledger. You do not want to post this beginning balance pay statement as its values are already in the general ledger from the legacy system. This balance loading is used for reporting and limiting purposes only.\n\n### C. Create pay statements for employees\nAfter you generate pay statements that have beginning balances, you must verify that the pay statements accurately reflect payroll data. You must also manually update the benefit and taxes information to match the values in the previous payroll system. After you verify that the amounts from the previous payroll system match the amounts on the current pay statements, you must finalize the pay statements.\n\n1. Open the **All pay statements** page.\n\n2. Highlight the last generated pay statement for Michael Redmond\n\n3. Click **Edit** to open the **Pay statement** page.\n\n4. Open the **Benefit deductions** tab and enter the following:\n\n| Field                           | Value            |\n|---------------------------------|------------------|\n| Benefit                         | Deduction amount |\n| 401K | Participate              | 3000.00          |\n| Dental | SubSp                  | 495.00           |\n| Dep care spending | Participate | 2500.00          |\n| Vision | SupSp                  | 500.00           |\n\n5. In the **Benefit deductions** tab enter the following: \n\n| Field                           | Value            |\n|---------------------------------|------------------|\n| Benefit                         | Deduction amount |\n| 401K | Participate              | 3000.00          |\n| Dental | SubSp                  | 495.00           |\n| Dep care spending | Participate | 2500.00          |\n| Vision | SupSp                  | 500.00           |\n\n6. In the **Benefit contributions** tab and enter the following:\n\n| Field              | Value               |\n|--------------------|---------------------|\n| Benefit            | Contribution amount |\n| 401K | Participate | 3000,00             |\n| Dental | SubSp     | 495.00              |\n| Vision | SubSp     | 500.00              |\n\n7. In the **Tax deductions** tab, enter the following:\n\n| Field           | Value            |\n|-----------------|------------------|\n| Tax code        | Deduction amount |\n| USA-FED-ER-FICA | 1600.00          |\n| USA-FED-ER-MEDI | 825.75           |\n\n8. In the **Tax contributions** tab enter the following:\n\n9. Click **Calculate**.\n> [!IMPORTANT] \n> Validate the totals of the pay statement that they match the YTD of the legacy system for the worker. You may want to hold off on finalizing in the next step to do some overall validating of all pay statements in aggregate. Once validated run through all the pay statements and finalize them.\n\nThe same process can be done in quarter increments if necessary for all prior quarters in each year. This is only needed if the customer needs to see the data by quarter without going back to the legacy system.\n\n## If you make a mistake Entering Beginning Balances for an Employee\nIt is possible to reverse and reenter transactions. To reverse the transaction, all you have to do is to complete the follow steps on the **All pay statements** page.\n\n1. Click **Reverse**.\n\n2. Click **Yes** when the message \"When you reverse this pay statement, a reversing pay statement will be created to offset this pay statement. Neither pay statement can be edited. Do you want to reverse this pay statement?\" displays. \n\nAfter you reverse the pay statement, you can generate a new pay statement for the worker from the earnings statement that you created previously in the “Generate earnings statements and pay statements that have beginning balances” procedure earlier in this topic. Be sure to fix any incorrect lines on the earnings statement before you generate the new pay statement, and then repeat the “Update pay statements that have beginning balances for benefits and taxes” procedure in this topic.\n","nodes":[{"content":"Enter payroll beginning balances","nodes":[{"pos":[0,32],"content":"Enter payroll beginning balances","nodes":[{"content":"Enter payroll beginning balances","pos":[0,32]}]}],"pos":[31,64],"yaml":true},{"content":"The topic describes the steps for entering beginning balances for earning codes, deductions, benefits, and taxes. This information is valuable for Partners to migrate or transfer data for a new Payroll implementation from another system.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,237],"content":"The topic describes the steps for entering beginning balances for earning codes, deductions, benefits, and taxes. This information is valuable for Partners to migrate or transfer data for a new Payroll implementation from another system.","nodes":[{"content":"The topic describes the steps for entering beginning balances for earning codes, deductions, benefits, and taxes. This information is valuable for Partners to migrate or transfer data for a new Payroll implementation from another system.","pos":[0,237],"nodes":[{"content":"The topic describes the steps for entering beginning balances for earning codes, deductions, benefits, and taxes.","pos":[0,113]},{"content":"This information is valuable for Partners to migrate or transfer data for a new Payroll implementation from another system.","pos":[114,237]}]}]}],"pos":[77,315],"yaml":true},{"pos":[827,859],"content":"Enter payroll beginning balances","linkify":"Enter payroll beginning balances","nodes":[{"content":"Enter payroll beginning balances","pos":[0,32]}]},{"content":"The topic describes the steps for entering beginning balances for earning codes, deductions, benefits, and taxes.","pos":[907,1020]},{"content":"This information is valuable for partners who transfer data for a new Payroll implementation from another system.","pos":[1021,1134]},{"content":"To prepare to enter beginning payroll balances, we verify the following information:","pos":[1135,1219]},{"content":"Employee records are entered and available in the system","pos":[1225,1281]},{"content":"The following data is set up and assigned to employees:","pos":[1286,1341]},{"content":"Pay cycles and pay periods","pos":[1349,1375]},{"content":"Earning codes","pos":[1382,1395]},{"content":"Taxes","pos":[1402,1407]},{"content":"Benefits and deductions","pos":[1414,1437]},{"content":"The company should have chosen a date where payroll beginning balances can be set.","pos":[1443,1525]},{"content":"Information were gathered on all earnings, benefits/deductions, benefit contributions, employee taxes, and employer taxes and their YTD amounts from the legacy system.","pos":[1531,1698]},{"content":"As you plan to enter beginning balances, consider how detailed the data needs to be.","pos":[1700,1784]},{"content":"Most businesses enter a single, consolidated year-to-date amount.","pos":[1785,1850]},{"content":"However if more detailed information is needed, balances can be entered in quarterly increments.","pos":[1851,1947]},{"content":"Deciding the level of detail that's needed determines how many manual pay statements must be created for each worker.","pos":[1948,2065]},{"content":"For a single year-to-date amount, only one manual statement is needed for each employee.","pos":[2066,2154]},{"content":"To do this use year-to-date amounts from the final pay statement from the previous system as the amount entered in the new payroll system.","pos":[2155,2293]},{"content":"The following example shows how you can enter employee payroll beginning balances, including earning codes, benefits/deductions, and taxes.","pos":[2295,2434]},{"content":"In a real-world example you would have a line item for each earning code, benefit deduction, benefit contribution, employee tax and employer tax with the amount entered being the year-to-date amount.","pos":[2435,2634]},{"content":"Using that list of codes and amounts, follow the steps for creating a manual earning and pay statement with accounting disabled to bring over beginning balances for payroll purposes.","pos":[2635,2817]},{"content":"You disable accounting because you won't want to post this beginning balance pay statement to your general ledger.","pos":[2819,2933]},{"content":"That was done in the legacy system and will come over to the new system when you set beginning balances in General ledger.","pos":[2934,3056]},{"pos":[3060,3193],"content":"[!NOTE] \nIf you want to reproduce the same steps below, you can use the Demo data. The Demo data can be downloaded on PartnerSource","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"If you want to reproduce the same steps below, you can use the Demo data. The Demo data can be downloaded on PartnerSource","pos":[9,131],"nodes":[{"content":"If you want to reproduce the same steps below, you can use the Demo data.","pos":[0,73]},{"content":"The Demo data can be downloaded on PartnerSource","pos":[74,122]}]}]},{"pos":[3199,3271],"content":"A. How to set up earnings codes to be used on payroll beginning balances","linkify":"A. How to set up earnings codes to be used on payroll beginning balances","nodes":[{"content":"A. How to set up earnings codes to be used on payroll beginning balances","pos":[0,72],"nodes":[{"content":"A.","pos":[0,2]},{"content":"How to set up earnings codes to be used on payroll beginning balances","pos":[3,72]}]}]},{"content":"When you enter payroll beginning balances, be sure the earning codes that you will be using are configured with the \"Allow editing of earning statement rates\" option enabled.","pos":[3272,3446]},{"content":"This will allow you to manually key the amount from the legacy system.","pos":[3447,3517]},{"pos":[3524,3596],"content":"B. Create earnings statement for an employee to have a beginning balance","linkify":"B. Create earnings statement for an employee to have a beginning balance","nodes":[{"content":"B. Create earnings statement for an employee to have a beginning balance","pos":[0,72],"nodes":[{"content":"B.","pos":[0,2]},{"content":"Create earnings statement for an employee to have a beginning balance","pos":[3,72]}]}]},{"content":"This step manually creates an earnings statement for each worker for the last pay period of the legacy system, which creates the earning statement lines in the new payroll system.","pos":[3597,3776]},{"content":"Enter one line per earning code and the YTD amount and hours.","pos":[3777,3838]},{"content":"The sample steps are as follows:","pos":[3839,3871]},{"pos":[3876,3936],"content":"Open the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>All earnings statements<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page and click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>New<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","source":"Open the **All earnings statements** page and click **New**."},{"content":"Enter the following:","pos":[3940,3960]},{"content":"Field","pos":[3965,3970]},{"content":"Value","pos":[3978,3983]},{"content":"Worker","pos":[4043,4049]},{"content":"Michael Redmond","pos":[4056,4071]},{"content":"Pay cycle","pos":[4082,4091]},{"content":"sm","pos":[4095,4097]},{"content":"Pay period","pos":[4121,4131]},{"content":"6/16/2017 - 6/30/2017","pos":[4134,4155]},{"pos":[4162,4222],"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Earnings statement line<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, enter the following:","source":"In the **Earnings statement line** tab, enter the following:"},{"pos":[4224,4262],"content":"Line 1: <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Earning statement line<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab","source":"Line 1: **Earning statement line** tab"},{"content":"Field","pos":[4266,4271]},{"content":"Value","pos":[4285,4290]},{"content":"Earnings code","pos":[4336,4349]},{"content":"Regular pay","pos":[4355,4366]},{"content":"Quantity","pos":[4371,4379]},{"content":"1.00","pos":[4390,4394]},{"content":"Rage","pos":[4406,4410]},{"content":"30,000","pos":[4425,4431]},{"content":"Line details tab","pos":[4441,4457]},{"content":"Manual","pos":[4476,4482]},{"content":"(marked)","pos":[4495,4503]},{"pos":[4510,4548],"content":"Line 2: <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Earning statement line<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab","source":"Line 2: **Earning statement line** tab"},{"content":"Field","pos":[4552,4557]},{"content":"Value","pos":[4571,4576]},{"content":"Earnings code","pos":[4616,4629]},{"content":"Bonus","pos":[4635,4640]},{"content":"Quantity","pos":[4648,4656]},{"content":"1.0000","pos":[4667,4673]},{"content":"Rate","pos":[4680,4684]},{"content":"4250.00","pos":[4699,4706]},{"content":"Line details tab","pos":[4712,4728]},{"content":"Manual","pos":[4744,4750]},{"content":"(marked)","pos":[4763,4771]},{"pos":[4775,4813],"content":"Line 3: <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Earning statement line<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab","source":"Line 3: **Earning statement line** tab"},{"content":"Field","pos":[4817,4822]},{"content":"Value","pos":[4835,4840]},{"content":"Earnings code","pos":[4883,4896]},{"content":"Commission","pos":[4901,4911]},{"content":"Quantity","pos":[4916,4924]},{"content":"1.0000","pos":[4934,4940]},{"content":"Rate","pos":[4949,4953]},{"content":"!,299.00","pos":[4967,4975]},{"content":"Rate","pos":[4982,4986]},{"content":"1,299.00","pos":[5000,5008]},{"content":"Line detail tab","pos":[5015,5030]},{"content":"Manual","pos":[5048,5054]},{"content":"(Marked)","pos":[5066,5074]},{"pos":[5082,5251],"content":"[!NOTE]\nMarking Manual checkbox setting in the **Line Details** tab for each earnings statement line is key to have payroll beginning balances entered for each worker.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"Marking Manual checkbox setting in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Line Details<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab for each earnings statement line is key to have payroll beginning balances entered for each worker.","pos":[8,167],"source":"Marking Manual checkbox setting in the **Line Details** tab for each earnings statement line is key to have payroll beginning balances entered for each worker."}]},{"pos":[5256,5333],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Action<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> pane, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Release earnings statement<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> USA-FED-ER-FICA.","source":"On the **Action** pane, click **Release earnings statement** USA-FED-ER-FICA."},{"pos":[5338,5452],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Action<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> pane click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Pay statement<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to open the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Generate pay statements<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> page and set the following:","source":"On the **Action** pane click **Pay statement** to open the **Generate pay statements** page and set the following:"},{"content":"Field","pos":[5456,5461]},{"content":"Value","pos":[5477,5482]},{"content":"Payment date","pos":[5526,5538]},{"content":"6/30/2017","pos":[5547,5556]},{"content":"Payment run type","pos":[5561,5577]},{"content":"Manual","pos":[5582,5588]},{"content":"Disable accounting","pos":[5596,5614]},{"content":"(marked)","pos":[5617,5625]},{"pos":[5632,5765],"content":"[!NOTE] \nThis is only available when the payment run type is manual and wherein the user want to disable accounting on the pay run.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"This is only available when the payment run type is manual and wherein the user want to disable accounting on the pay run.","pos":[9,131]}]},{"pos":[5767,5806],"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and close the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Infolog<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","source":"Click **OK** and close the **Infolog**."},{"pos":[5813,5898],"content":"Why Disable Accounting checkbox needs to be turned on when generating pay statements?","linkify":"Why Disable Accounting checkbox needs to be turned on when generating pay statements?","nodes":[{"content":"Why Disable Accounting checkbox needs to be turned on when generating pay statements?","pos":[0,85]}]},{"content":"This prevents any lines in the pay statement from being distributed and posted to the General ledger.","pos":[5899,6000]},{"content":"You do not want to post this beginning balance pay statement as its values are already in the general ledger from the legacy system.","pos":[6001,6133]},{"content":"This balance loading is used for reporting and limiting purposes only.","pos":[6134,6204]},{"pos":[6210,6248],"content":"C. Create pay statements for employees","linkify":"C. Create pay statements for employees","nodes":[{"content":"C. Create pay statements for employees","pos":[0,38],"nodes":[{"content":"C.","pos":[0,2]},{"content":"Create pay statements for employees","pos":[3,38]}]}]},{"content":"After you generate pay statements that have beginning balances, you must verify that the pay statements accurately reflect payroll data.","pos":[6249,6385]},{"content":"You must also manually update the benefit and taxes information to match the values in the previous payroll system.","pos":[6386,6501]},{"content":"After you verify that the amounts from the previous payroll system match the amounts on the current pay statements, you must finalize the pay statements.","pos":[6502,6655]},{"pos":[6660,6697],"content":"Open the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>All pay statements<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","source":"Open the **All pay statements** page."},{"content":"Highlight the last generated pay statement for Michael Redmond","pos":[6702,6764]},{"pos":[6769,6819],"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Edit<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to open the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Pay statement<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page.","source":"Click **Edit** to open the **Pay statement** page."},{"pos":[6824,6884],"content":"Open the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Benefit deductions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab and enter the following:","source":"Open the **Benefit deductions** tab and enter the following:"},{"content":"Field","pos":[6888,6893]},{"content":"Value","pos":[6922,6927]},{"content":"Benefit","pos":[6998,7005]},{"content":"Deduction amount","pos":[7032,7048]},{"content":"401K","pos":[7053,7057]},{"content":"Participate","pos":[7060,7071]},{"content":"3000.00","pos":[7087,7094]},{"content":"Dental","pos":[7108,7114]},{"content":"SubSp","pos":[7117,7122]},{"content":"495.00","pos":[7142,7148]},{"content":"Dep care spending","pos":[7163,7180]},{"content":"Participate","pos":[7183,7194]},{"content":"2500.00","pos":[7197,7204]},{"content":"Vision","pos":[7218,7224]},{"content":"SupSp","pos":[7227,7232]},{"content":"500.00","pos":[7252,7258]},{"pos":[7275,7329],"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Benefit deductions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab enter the following:","source":"In the **Benefit deductions** tab enter the following:"},{"content":"Field","pos":[7334,7339]},{"content":"Value","pos":[7368,7373]},{"content":"Benefit","pos":[7444,7451]},{"content":"Deduction amount","pos":[7478,7494]},{"content":"401K","pos":[7499,7503]},{"content":"Participate","pos":[7506,7517]},{"content":"3000.00","pos":[7533,7540]},{"content":"Dental","pos":[7554,7560]},{"content":"SubSp","pos":[7563,7568]},{"content":"495.00","pos":[7588,7594]},{"content":"Dep care spending","pos":[7609,7626]},{"content":"Participate","pos":[7629,7640]},{"content":"2500.00","pos":[7643,7650]},{"content":"Vision","pos":[7664,7670]},{"content":"SupSp","pos":[7673,7678]},{"content":"500.00","pos":[7698,7704]},{"pos":[7721,7782],"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Benefit contributions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab and enter the following:","source":"In the **Benefit contributions** tab and enter the following:"},{"content":"Field","pos":[7786,7791]},{"content":"Value","pos":[7807,7812]},{"content":"Benefit","pos":[7876,7883]},{"content":"Contribution amount","pos":[7897,7916]},{"content":"401K","pos":[7921,7925]},{"content":"Participate","pos":[7928,7939]},{"content":"3000,00","pos":[7942,7949]},{"content":"Dental","pos":[7966,7972]},{"content":"SubSp","pos":[7975,7980]},{"content":"495.00","pos":[7987,7993]},{"content":"Vision","pos":[8011,8017]},{"content":"SubSp","pos":[8020,8025]},{"content":"500.00","pos":[8032,8038]},{"pos":[8058,8109],"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tax deductions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, enter the following:","source":"In the **Tax deductions** tab, enter the following:"},{"content":"Field","pos":[8113,8118]},{"content":"Value","pos":[8131,8136]},{"content":"Tax code","pos":[8191,8199]},{"content":"Deduction amount","pos":[8209,8225]},{"content":"USA-FED-ER-FICA","pos":[8230,8245]},{"content":"1600.00","pos":[8248,8255]},{"content":"USA-FED-ER-MEDI","pos":[8269,8284]},{"content":"825.75","pos":[8287,8293]},{"pos":[8310,8363],"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tax contributions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab enter the following:","source":"In the **Tax contributions** tab enter the following:"},{"pos":[8368,8388],"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Calculate<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"Click **Calculate**."},{"pos":[8391,8699],"content":"[!IMPORTANT] \nValidate the totals of the pay statement that they match the YTD of the legacy system for the worker. You may want to hold off on finalizing in the next step to do some overall validating of all pay statements in aggregate. Once validated run through all the pay statements and finalize them.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"Validate the totals of the pay statement that they match the YTD of the legacy system for the worker. You may want to hold off on finalizing in the next step to do some overall validating of all pay statements in aggregate. Once validated run through all the pay statements and finalize them.","pos":[14,306],"nodes":[{"content":"Validate the totals of the pay statement that they match the YTD of the legacy system for the worker.","pos":[0,101]},{"content":"You may want to hold off on finalizing in the next step to do some overall validating of all pay statements in aggregate.","pos":[102,223]},{"content":"Once validated run through all the pay statements and finalize them.","pos":[224,292]}]}]},{"content":"The same process can be done in quarter increments if necessary for all prior quarters in each year.","pos":[8701,8801]},{"content":"This is only needed if the customer needs to see the data by quarter without going back to the legacy system.","pos":[8802,8911]},{"pos":[8916,8981],"content":"If you make a mistake Entering Beginning Balances for an Employee","linkify":"If you make a mistake Entering Beginning Balances for an Employee","nodes":[{"content":"If you make a mistake Entering Beginning Balances for an Employee","pos":[0,65]}]},{"content":"It is possible to reverse and reenter transactions.","pos":[8982,9033]},{"content":"To reverse the transaction, all you have to do is to complete the follow steps on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>All pay statements<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[9034,9148],"source":" To reverse the transaction, all you have to do is to complete the follow steps on the **All pay statements** page."},{"pos":[9153,9171],"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Reverse<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"Click **Reverse**."},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Yes<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> when the message \"When you reverse this pay statement, a reversing pay statement will be created to offset this pay statement.","pos":[9176,9316],"source":"Click **Yes** when the message \"When you reverse this pay statement, a reversing pay statement will be created to offset this pay statement."},{"content":"Neither pay statement can be edited.","pos":[9317,9353]},{"content":"Do you want to reverse this pay statement?\"","pos":[9354,9397]},{"content":"displays.","pos":[9398,9407]},{"content":"After you reverse the pay statement, you can generate a new pay statement for the worker from the earnings statement that you created previously in the “Generate earnings statements and pay statements that have beginning balances” procedure earlier in this topic.","pos":[9410,9673]},{"content":"Be sure to fix any incorrect lines on the earnings statement before you generate the new pay statement, and then repeat the “Update pay statements that have beginning balances for benefits and taxes” procedure in this topic.","pos":[9674,9898]}]}