{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Petty cash for Eastern Europe\ndescription: This topic provides information about the petty cash functionality that lets users in Estonia, Lithuania, Czech Republic, Hungary, Latvia, Poland, and Russia reflect cash operations in the system.\nauthor: ShylaThompson\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 04/04/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: RCashBalance, RCashCountStatementForm, RCashPosting, RCashRemainLimit, RCashReportJour_PL, RCashTable, RCashTableBalance, RCashTableCredLimit, RCashTableLastRevaluation, RCashTableTransactions, RCashTrans\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: shylaw\nms.search.scope: AX 7.0.0, Operations, Core\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 268504\nms.search.region: Czech Republic, Estonia, Hungary, Latvia, Lithuania, Poland, Russia\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: v-elgolu\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-05-31\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.1\n\n---\n\n# Petty cash for Eastern Europe\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThis topic provides information about the petty cash functionality that lets users in Estonia, Lithuania, Czech Republic, Hungary, Latvia, Poland, and Russia reflect cash operations in the system.\n\nYou can use the petty cash functionality to automate operations for receipts and expenditures of cash, the creation of primary documents, and the printing of related reports. The petty cash functionality lets you perform the following operations:\n\n-   Account the receipt and expenditure of available cash assets.\n-   Generate typical cash forms: Cash reimbursement slips, Cash disbursement slips, and a Journal of registration for cash slips.\n-   Control the maximum cash amount that is allowed for operations with customers, vendors, and so on.\n-   Reflect cash operations in various currencies in the system.\n-   Convert the amounts of cash operations in foreign currency to the default currency to provide accounting reporting.\n-   Generate a **Cash book** report and a cashier’s report.\n\n## Prerequisites\nBefore you can use the petty cash functionality, you must complete the following prerequisites:\n\n-   Set up cash accounts.\n-   Set up cash posting profiles.\n-   Set up number sequences for cash document numbering.\n-   Set up default values for Cash and bank management parameters.\n-   Set up cash journal names in General ledger.\n\n### Set up cash accounts\n\nTo set up a Cash, open **Cash and bank management** &gt; **Bank accounts** &gt; **Cash accounts**, and enter the following information.\n\n| Field                 | Description                                                                                                          |\n|-----------------------|----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| Cash                  | Enter a code to identify the cash account (cash).                                                                    |\n| Name                  | Enter a description of the cash account.                                                                             |\n| Currency              | Select the default currency code for cash transactions.                                                              |\n| Number sequence group | If the numbering of cash documents must differ from the numbering that is specified in the parameters, enter a code. |\n| More currencies       | Select this check box to allow currencies that differ from the accounting currency to be posted.                     |\n| Negative cash         | Select this check box to allow negative cash balances in any currency.                                               |\n\nTo set up cash balance control rules for a cash account, select the cash account, and then, on the Action Pane, on the **Cash account** tab, in the **Balance limit** group, click **Balance limit**. Enter the following information.\n\n<table>\n<colgroup>\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n</colgroup>\n<thead>\n<tr class=\"header\">\n<th>Field</th>\n<th>Description</th>\n</tr>\n</thead>\n<tbody>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Currency type</td>\n<td>Select the type of currency:\n<ul>\n<li><strong>Accounting currency</strong> – Use the basic company currency code.</li>\n<li><strong>Indicated currency</strong> – Use a currency code that differs from the basic company currency code.</li>\n</ul></td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Currency</td>\n<td>If you selected <strong>Indicated currency</strong> in the <strong>Currency type</strong> field, select a currency code. This field is unavailable if you selected <strong>Accounting currency</strong> in the <strong>Currency type</strong> field.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Balance limit type</td>\n<td>Select one of the available values:\n<ul>\n<li><strong>Maximum</strong> – The cash balance should not be allowed to exceed the <strong>Balance limit</strong> amount for the cash account (upper bound).</li>\n<li><strong>Minimum</strong> – The cash balance should not be allowed to go below the <strong>Balance limit</strong> amount for the cash account (bottom bound).</li>\n</ul></td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Check balance limit</td>\n<td>Select what occurs during the approval process for cash documents if the <strong>Balance limit</strong> amount for the cash account is exceeded:\n<ul>\n<li><strong>Accept</strong> – The limit can be exceeded.</li>\n<li><strong>Warning</strong> – The limit can be exceeded, but the user receives a warning message. The cash document is confirmed or approved.</li>\n<li><strong>Error</strong> – The limit can't be exceeded. The user receives an error message, and the cash document isn't confirmed or approved.</li>\n</ul>\nFor more information about the approval process for cash documents, see the &quot;Cash transaction approval and posting&quot; section, later in this topic.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Balance limit</td>\n<td>Enter a limit for the cash account balance. The amount should be in the currency that you specified.</td>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n</table>\n\n### Set up cash posting profiles\n\nCash posting profiles define postings to the general ledger. To set up a cash posting profile, go to **Cash** **and bank management** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Cash posting profiles**, and select or create a posting profile. Enter the following information.\n\n<table>\n<colgroup>\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n</colgroup>\n<thead>\n<tr class=\"header\">\n<th>Field</th>\n<th>Description</th>\n</tr>\n</thead>\n<tbody>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Valid for</td>\n<td>Select whether the posting profile applies to a specific cash account or all cash accounts:\n<ul>\n<li><strong>Table</strong> – If there is a posting profile line for the cash account, that line is used for cash transaction posting.</li>\n<li><strong>All</strong> – There is no posting profile line for the cash account.</li>\n</ul></td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Cash</td>\n<td>If you selected <strong>Table</strong> in the <strong>Valid for</strong> field, specify the cash account. This field remains blank if you selected <strong>All</strong> in the <strong>Valid for</strong> field.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Ledger account</td>\n<td>Enter the number of the ledger account to use as the summary account for the cash account.</td>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n</table>\n\n### Set up number sequences for cash documents\n\nTo set up number sequences for cash documents, go to **Cash and bank management** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Cash and bank management parameters**. On the **Number sequence** tab, specify number sequence codes for the **Cash reimbursement slips**, **Cash disbursement slips**, **Cash correction voucher**, and **Exchange adjustment** documents, and for **Cash report number**.\n\n### Set up default values for Cash and bank management parameters\n\nTo set up default values for Cash and bank management parameters for the petty cash functionality, go to **Cash and bank management** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Cash and bank management parameters**. On the **Cash** tab, enter the following information.\n\n<table>\n<colgroup>\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n</colgroup>\n<thead>\n<tr class=\"header\">\n<th>Field</th>\n<th>Description</th>\n</tr>\n</thead>\n<tbody>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Cash</td>\n<td>Select the default cash account in journals.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Cash posting</td>\n<td>Enter the default cash posting profile that is used if no other posting profile is specified.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Check for voucher used</td>\n<td>Select what occurs if duplicate numbers are found during the check of the cash document number:\n<ul>\n<li>Reject duplicate</li>\n<li>Reject copies within fiscal year</li>\n<li>Accept duplicates</li>\n<li>Warn in case of duplicates</li>\n</ul></td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Check operations limit</td>\n<td>Specify what occurs if the limit for operations with counteragents is exceeded:\n<ul>\n<li><strong>Accept</strong> – The limit can be exceeded.</li>\n<li><strong>Warning</strong> – The limit can be exceeded, but the user receives a warning message. The operation is posted.</li>\n<li><strong>Error</strong> – The limit can't be exceeded. The user receives an error message, and the operation isn't posted.</li>\n</ul></td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Validation method</td>\n<td>Select the validation method that is used to control exceeded limit amounts for operations:\n<ul>\n<li><strong>Operation</strong> – Validation is done per transaction</li>\n<li><strong>Agreement</strong> – Validation is done per transaction that has a specified contract with a counteragent.</li>\n</ul></td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Operations limit</td>\n<td>Enter the maximum amount that is allowed for operations with counteragents in cash.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Posting on earlier date</td>\n<td>Select this check box to enable cash transactions to be posted before the last date of the cash transaction.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Dimensions</td>\n<td>Enter dimensions in the <strong>Department code</strong>, <strong>Analytical code</strong>, and <strong>Purpose code</strong> fields. The printing form for cash documents will reflect this information.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Use confirm status</td>\n<td>Select this check box to use an additional status, <strong>Confirmed</strong>, during the approval process for cash documents. (For more information, see the &quot;Cash transaction approval and posting&quot; section.)</td>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n</table>\n\n### Set up cash journal names in General ledger\n\nTo create a journal for cash transaction posting, go to **General ledger** &gt; **Journal setup** &gt; **Journal names**, and create a new record. In the **Journal type** field, specify **Cash**. Define other default journal parameters as you require.\n\n## Daily cash operations via a Slip journal\nTo create a cash document via a Slip journal, go to **Cash and bank management** &gt; **Cash transactions** &gt; **Slip journal**, and create a new journal. On the Action Pane, click **Lines**. Add a new line, and enter the following information.\n\n<table>\n<colgroup>\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n</colgroup>\n<thead>\n<tr class=\"header\">\n<th>Field</th>\n<th>Description</th>\n</tr>\n</thead>\n<tbody>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Date</td>\n<td>Enter the date of the transaction.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Account</td>\n<td>Select the cash account. By default, a cash account is specified in the Cash and bank management parameters.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Description</td>\n<td>Enter explanatory text for the transaction.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Debit Credit</td>\n<td>Enter cash document amount in one of these fields:\n<ul>\n<li><strong>Debit</strong> – Use this field to register cash receipts and a Cash reimbursement slip.</li>\n<li><strong>Credit</strong> – Use this field to register cash expenditures and a Cash disbursement slip.</li>\n</ul></td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Offset account type Offset account</td>\n<td>Select an offset account type and offset account number.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Currency</td>\n<td>Select the code for the transaction currency.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Voucher</td>\n<td>This field is filled in automatically, based on the journal setup.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Order number</td>\n<td>If no other number sequence is set up for the cash account, this field is filled in automatically, based on the number sequence that is specified in the parameters. You can manually enter an order number in this field as you require. To prevent inconsistence in cash document numbering, the following control is applied: the number of a cash document that has an earlier date of operation can't be higher than number of a cash document that has a later date of operation. If you don't require this control, select the <strong>Posting on earlier date</strong> check box in the Cash and bank management parameters.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Approval status</td>\n<td>The first transaction status is <strong>None</strong>. For information about how to set the transaction status, See the &quot;Cash transaction approval and posting&quot; section.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Document type</td>\n<td>This field on the <strong>Cash order</strong> tab is filled in automatically, based on the amount that you entered for the cash document:\n<ul>\n<li><strong>Cash reimbursement slip</strong> – This value is used if you entered an amount in the <strong>Debit</strong> field for the cash account.</li>\n<li><strong>Cash disbursement slip</strong> – This value is used if you entered an amount in the <strong>Credit</strong> field for the cash account</li>\n<li><strong>Correction</strong> – You entered a negative amount in either the <strong>Debit</strong> field or the <strong>Credit</strong> field for the cash account.</li>\n</ul></td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Sales tax group</td>\n<td>Specify a sales tax group to calculate taxes on the operation.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Item sales tax group</td>\n<td>Specify an item sales tax group to calculate taxes on the operation.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Reason</td>\n<td>On the <strong>Cash order</strong> tab, enter text that describes the transaction subject. This text will be printed on the cash slip reporting form.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Document Date</td>\n<td>Enter the description, number, and date of the primary document that is the reason for the transaction (for example, advance reports, invoice, or order).</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Representative type</td>\n<td>This field can have the following values:\n<ul>\n<li><strong>Worker</strong> – The <strong>Representative</strong> lookup contains a list of employees if the <strong>Offset account</strong> field is set to <strong>Ledger</strong> or <strong>Bank</strong>, or a list of the counteragent's contact persons if the <strong>Offset account</strong> field is set to <strong>Customer</strong> or <strong>Vendor</strong>. To set up representatives, go to <strong>Basic</strong> &gt; <strong>Setup</strong> &gt; <strong>Contacts</strong> &gt; <strong>Contact person</strong>.</li>\n<li><strong>Other</strong> – The <strong>Representative</strong> lookup contains a list of other clients. To set up receivers who don't appear in the <strong>Customers</strong> or <strong>Vendors</strong> table, go to <strong>General ledger</strong> &gt; <strong>Receivers</strong>. This type is available only for Latvia. (The <strong>CSELatvia</strong> configuration key should be enabled.)</li>\n<li><strong>Vendor</strong> – The <strong>Representative</strong> lookup contains a list of vendors. To set up vendors, go to <strong>Accounts payable</strong> &gt; <strong>Vendors</strong>.</li>\n<li><strong>Customer</strong> – The <strong>Representative</strong> lookup contains a list of customers. To set up customers, go to <strong>Accounts receivable</strong> &gt; <strong>Customers</strong>.</li>\n</ul></td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Representative</td>\n<td>Select a representative of the type that you specified in the <strong>Representative type</strong> field.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Name of person</td>\n<td>This field is filled in automatically, based on the <strong>Offset account</strong> and <strong>Representative</strong> fields. The printing form for cash slips will reflect this information.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Identity card</td>\n<td>This field is filled in automatically, based on the identity card data for the contact person (representative). If the <strong>Offset account type</strong> field is set to <strong>Advance holder</strong>, and the <strong>Offset account</strong> field is set to an employee number, cash receipts or expenditures can be done from or to the employee. In this case the <strong>Identity card</strong> field is filled in automatically by using data for the identity card from the <strong>Employee</strong> table (<strong>Staff accounting</strong> &gt; <strong>Employee table</strong>).</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Purpose</td>\n<td>In the <strong>Purpose</strong> table, define one or more destination codes for the transaction amount. Select a destination code in the <strong>Purpose</strong> field, and enter an explanation in the <strong>Transaction text</strong> field. In the <strong>Amount</strong> field, enter an amount in the transaction currency. The <strong>Percent</strong> field shows, as a percentage, the ratio of the destination amount to the total transaction amount.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Remainder</td>\n<td>The remaining amount that is calculated. Note that the whole transaction amount must be assigned to destination codes.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Officials</td>\n<td>On the <strong>Officials</strong> tab, specify the names and titles for responsible persons: Director, Chief accountant, and Cashier. The <strong>Position</strong> values are determined by the setup of officials on the <strong>General</strong> and <strong>Ledger</strong> tabs of the <strong>Officials</strong> page (<strong>Basic</strong> &gt; <strong>Setup</strong> &gt; <strong>Contacts</strong> &gt; <strong>Officials</strong>).</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Prepayment</td>\n<td>Select this check box if the transaction is a prepayment.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Posting profile</td>\n<td>Enter the posting profile for the cash account. By default, the posting profile that is specified in the Cash and bank management parameters is used.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Offset posting profile</td>\n<td>Enter the posting profile for the selected offset account.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Total amount</td>\n<td>In the <strong>Total amount</strong> field group at the bottom of the page, the <strong>Reimb</strong> field shows the total that is calculated for all Cash reimbursement slips that are entered in the current journal, and the <strong>Disb</strong> field shows the total for all Cash disbursement slips.</td>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n</table>\n\nTo check journal entries, on the Action Pane, click **Validate**.\n\n## Daily cash operations via a General journal\nTo create a cash transaction via a General journal, go to **General ledger** &gt; **Journal entries** &gt; **General journals**, and create a new journal. On the Action Pane, click **Lines**. Add a new line, and enter the following information.\n\n<table>\n<colgroup>\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n</colgroup>\n<thead>\n<tr class=\"header\">\n<th>Field</th>\n<th>Description</th>\n</tr>\n</thead>\n<tbody>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Date</td>\n<td>Enter the date of the transaction.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Account type</td>\n<td>Select <strong>Petty cash</strong>.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Account</td>\n<td>Select the cash account number.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Transaction text</td>\n<td>Enter explanatory text for the transaction.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Debit Credit</td>\n<td>Enter cash document amount in one of these fields:\n<ul>\n<li><strong>Debit</strong> – Use this field to register cash receipts and a Cash reimbursement slip.</li>\n<li><strong>Credit</strong> – Use this field to register cash expenditures and a Cash disbursement slip.</li>\n</ul></td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Offset account type Offset account</td>\n<td>Select an offset account type and offset account number.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Currency</td>\n<td>Select the code for the transaction currency.</td>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n</table>\n\nOn the **Invoice** tab, you can specify posting profiles for the selected account and offset account. If the registered transaction is a prepayment, select the **Prepayment** check box on the **Payment** tab. In the **Representative** field group, fill in the fields as you did for the Slip journal lines to print on the **Cash** report. To check journal entries, on the Action Pane, click **Validate**.\n\n## Cash transaction approval and posting\nFor cash transactions, the following statuses can be applied: **None**, **Confirmed**, **Approved**, and **Rejected**. A **Use confirm status** parameter on the **Approval** FastTab of the **Cash** tab at **Cash and bank management** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Cash and bank management parameters** lets you activate two additional statuses: **Confirmed** and **Rejected**. Confirmation is appropriate when cash documents are issued, and cash receipts or expenditures are shared between two employees: accountant and cashier. The **Reset status** function changes the current transaction status. **Approved** becomes **Confirmed**, and **Confirmed** becomes **None**. Cash journal entries can be edited only when the status is **None**. Cash transactions can be rejected only if the transaction status is **Confirmed**. Rejected cash documents are included on the **Journal of registration of cash documents** report, but they aren't reflected on the **Cash book** report. To confirm a transaction, select the corresponding Slip journal line, and then click **Documents approval** &gt; **Confirm**. An order number is generated, based on the specified number sequence. The transaction status is changed to **Confirmed**, and you can no longer edit the journal line. The cash account balance remains unchanged. To reject a cash document, click **Documents approval** &gt; **Reject**. This option is available only for documents that have **Confirmed** status. To approve a transaction, select the corresponding Slip journal line, and then click **Documents approval** &gt; **Approve**. The **Approved** status indicates that cash funds are received or expended. The cash balance is changed. The cash transaction can be posted. To cancel an **Approved** status and reset the status to **None**, click **Documents approval** &gt; **Reset status**. Only approved cash transactions can be posted. To post a journal, click **Post** &gt; **Post**.\n\n## Print a cash order\nTo print a cash order, select a Slip journal line, and then, on the Action Pane, click **Print** &gt; **Cash order report**. The system generates a printing form for either a Cash reimbursement slip or a Cash disbursement slip, depending on whether an amount is entered in the **Debit** field the or **Credit** field for the selected line:\n\n-   If there is an amount in the **Debit** field: Cash reimbursement slip\n-   If there is an amount in the **Credit** field: Cash disbursement slip\n\nSlip journal lines that have **Confirmed**, **Approved**, or **Rejected** status can be printed. You can also print cash order documents at **Cash and bank management** &gt; **Inquires and reports** &gt; **Cash order**.\n\n## Periodic tasks\nThe following tasks can be performed at **Cash and bank management** &gt; **Periodic tasks**.\n\n<table>\n<colgroup>\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n</colgroup>\n<thead>\n<tr class=\"header\">\n<th>Periodic task</th>\n<th>Description</th>\n</tr>\n</thead>\n<tbody>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Check balance limit</td>\n<td>Check the balance for the selected cash account on the specified date, and show the result in an information message. Only approved transactions can be counted in the balance calculation. Transactions that are marked as <strong>For payroll</strong> aren't considered.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Cash balance recalculation</td>\n<td>Use this task to make sure that the ledger balances for cash accounts fit the cash balance.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Cash report creation (for Poland only)</td>\n<td>Create a <strong>Cash</strong> report. The <strong>Cash</strong> report number is generated based on the number sequence that is set up for <strong>Report number</strong>. In the dialog box for the task, in the <strong>To date</strong>, specify the last date for which cash transactions should be counted for the <strong>Cash</strong> report. Use the <strong>Filter</strong> function on the <strong>Records to include</strong> tab to specify additional criteria to limit the selection of cash transactions. These criteria can include cash account numbers and currency codes. In the <strong>Create by</strong> field, select the user who is responsible for report creation. To view the <strong>Cash</strong> report that is created, use the <strong>Cash reports</strong> button on the <strong>Cash accounts</strong> page.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Cash - Exchange adjustment FIFO and LIFO (for Poland only)</td>\n<td>Calculate the exchange adjustment per Polish standards. Use the <strong>Filter</strong> function on the <strong>Records to include</strong> tab to specify the cash account to run the task for. Select the <strong>Recalculation</strong> check box to do a full recalculation of the exchange adjustment difference for all open periods. Here is how the exchange adjustment is calculated when the first in, first out (FIFO) and last in, first out (LIFO) methods are used:\n<ul>\n<li><strong>FIFO method</strong> – The system searches for an expenditure transaction that has an earlier transaction date (smaller order number) and settles it with a receipt transaction that has an earlier transaction date (smaller order number).</li>\n<li><strong>LIFO method</strong> – The system searches for an expenditure transaction that has a later transaction date (larger order number) and settles it with a receipt transaction that has a later transaction date (larger order number).</li>\n</ul>\nThe settled amount is reflected in the <strong>Settled currency</strong> field on the <strong>Cash transaction</strong> page. If there is an exchange adjustment difference, the amount is reflected in the <strong>Exchange adjustment amount</strong> field, and a transaction of the <strong>Exchange rate difference</strong> document type is generated in the <strong>Cash transaction</strong> table. Ledger accounts for profit/loss transactions are set in the <strong>Currency</strong> table (<strong>Exchange rate financial profit</strong> and <strong>Exchange rate financial loss</strong>).</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Foreign currency revaluation - Cash</td>\n<td>Use this task to have an adequate balance in the default currency on the reporting date when the operations are entered in foreign currencies. Use the <strong>Filter</strong> function on the <strong>Records to include</strong> tab to specify the cash account to run the task for. In the dialog box for the task, use the <strong>From currency</strong> and <strong>To Currency</strong> fields to specify transaction currencies. The system compares the amount in the currency that was converted by using exchange rate on the selected date with the amount in the default currency. The difference between the two amounts (excluding the previous exchange adjustment) is the calculated exchange adjustment. This task creates an approved cash transaction of the <strong>Exchange adjustment</strong> type. The ledger transaction is formed by using the ledger account for cash and the ledger account that is specified in <strong>Unrealized profit</strong> or <strong>Unrealized loss</strong> in the <strong>Currency</strong> table.</td>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n</table>\n\n## Inquiries and reports\n| Inquiry or report                             | Description                                                                                                                                                                                                                     |\n|-----------------------------------------------|---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| Cash transactions view                        | For a Slip journal line, use the **Inquiries** button on the Action Pane to view ledger transactions, the cash balance, and other information.                                                                                  |\n| Cash transaction                              | Go to **Cash and bank management** &gt; **Inquiries and reports** &gt; **Cash transactions** to view cash transactions. Use the **Filter** function to specify additional criteria to limit the selection of cash transactions. |\n| Journal of registration (for Estonia, Russia) | The report at **Cash and bank management** &gt; **Inquiries and reports** &gt; **Journal of registration** reflects all cash reimbursement and cash disbursement slips that have been issued.                                   |\n| Cash book (for Latvia, Lithuania, Russia)     | The report at **Cash and bank management** &gt; **Inquiries and reports** &gt; **Cash book report** reflects actual cash fund movements (receipts and expenditures).                                                            |\n\n\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[32,61],"content":"Petty cash for Eastern Europe","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Petty cash for Eastern Europe","pos":[0,29]}]},{"pos":[75,271],"content":"This topic provides information about the petty cash functionality that lets users in Estonia, Lithuania, Czech Republic, Hungary, Latvia, Poland, and Russia reflect cash operations in the system.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"This topic provides information about the petty cash functionality that lets users in Estonia, Lithuania, Czech Republic, Hungary, Latvia, Poland, and Russia reflect cash operations in the system.","pos":[0,196]}]},{"pos":[1007,1036],"content":"Petty cash for Eastern Europe","linkify":"Petty cash for Eastern Europe","nodes":[{"content":"Petty cash for Eastern Europe","pos":[0,29]}]},{"content":"This topic provides information about the petty cash functionality that lets users in Estonia, Lithuania, Czech Republic, Hungary, Latvia, Poland, and Russia reflect cash operations in the system.","pos":[1082,1278]},{"content":"You can use the petty cash functionality to automate operations for receipts and expenditures of cash, the creation of primary documents, and the printing of related reports.","pos":[1280,1454]},{"content":"The petty cash functionality lets you perform the following operations:","pos":[1455,1526]},{"content":"Account the receipt and expenditure of available cash assets.","pos":[1532,1593]},{"content":"Generate typical cash forms: Cash reimbursement slips, Cash disbursement slips, and a Journal of registration for cash slips.","pos":[1598,1723]},{"content":"Control the maximum cash amount that is allowed for operations with customers, vendors, and so on.","pos":[1728,1826]},{"content":"Reflect cash operations in various currencies in the system.","pos":[1831,1891]},{"content":"Convert the amounts of cash operations in foreign currency to the default currency to provide accounting reporting.","pos":[1896,2011]},{"pos":[2016,2071],"content":"Generate a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cash book<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> report and a cashier’s report.","source":"Generate a **Cash book** report and a cashier’s report."},{"pos":[2076,2089],"content":"Prerequisites","linkify":"Prerequisites","nodes":[{"content":"Prerequisites","pos":[0,13]}]},{"content":"Before you can use the petty cash functionality, you must complete the following prerequisites:","pos":[2090,2185]},{"content":"Set up cash accounts.","pos":[2191,2212]},{"content":"Set up cash posting profiles.","pos":[2217,2246]},{"content":"Set up number sequences for cash document numbering.","pos":[2251,2303]},{"content":"Set up default values for Cash and bank management parameters.","pos":[2308,2370]},{"content":"Set up cash journal names in General ledger.","pos":[2375,2419]},{"pos":[2425,2445],"content":"Set up cash accounts","linkify":"Set up cash accounts","nodes":[{"content":"Set up cash accounts","pos":[0,20]}]},{"pos":[2447,2582],"content":"To set up a Cash, open <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cash and bank management<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Bank accounts<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Cash accounts<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>, and enter the following information.","source":"To set up a Cash, open **Cash and bank management** &gt; **Bank accounts** &gt; **Cash accounts**, and enter the following information."},{"content":"Field","pos":[2586,2591]},{"content":"Description","pos":[2610,2621]},{"content":"Cash","pos":[2876,2880]},{"content":"Enter a code to identify the cash account (cash).","pos":[2900,2949]},{"content":"Name","pos":[3021,3025]},{"content":"Enter a description of the cash account.","pos":[3045,3085]},{"content":"Currency","pos":[3166,3174]},{"content":"Select the default currency code for cash transactions.","pos":[3190,3245]},{"content":"Number sequence group","pos":[3311,3332]},{"content":"If the numbering of cash documents must differ from the numbering that is specified in the parameters, enter a code.","pos":[3335,3451]},{"content":"More currencies","pos":[3456,3471]},{"content":"Select this check box to allow currencies that differ from the accounting currency to be posted.","pos":[3480,3576]},{"content":"Negative cash","pos":[3601,3614]},{"content":"Select this check box to allow negative cash balances in any currency.","pos":[3625,3695]},{"content":"To set up cash balance control rules for a cash account, select the cash account, and then, on the Action Pane, on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cash account<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Balance limit<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> group, click <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Balance limit<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.","pos":[3745,3942],"source":"To set up cash balance control rules for a cash account, select the cash account, and then, on the Action Pane, on the **Cash account** tab, in the **Balance limit** group, click **Balance limit**."},{"content":"Enter the following information.","pos":[3943,3975]},{"content":"Field","pos":[4080,4085]},{"content":"Description","pos":[4095,4106]},{"content":"Currency type","pos":[4156,4169]},{"content":"Select the type of currency:","pos":[4179,4207],"source":"Select the type of currency:\n"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Accounting currency<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Use the basic company currency code.","pos":[4217,4292],"source":"<strong>Accounting currency</strong> – Use the basic company currency code."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Indicated currency<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Use a currency code that differs from the basic company currency code.","pos":[4302,4410],"source":"<strong>Indicated currency</strong> – Use a currency code that differs from the basic company currency code."},{"content":"Currency","pos":[4455,4463]},{"content":"If you selected <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Indicated currency<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> in the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Currency type<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field, select a currency code.","pos":[4473,4593],"source":"If you selected <strong>Indicated currency</strong> in the <strong>Currency type</strong> field, select a currency code."},{"content":"This field is unavailable if you selected <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Accounting currency<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> in the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Currency type<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field.","pos":[4594,4717],"source":" This field is unavailable if you selected <strong>Accounting currency</strong> in the <strong>Currency type</strong> field."},{"content":"Balance limit type","pos":[4750,4768]},{"content":"Select one of the available values:","pos":[4778,4813],"source":"Select one of the available values:\n"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Maximum<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – The cash balance should not be allowed to exceed the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Balance limit<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> amount for the cash account (upper bound).","pos":[4823,4976],"source":"<strong>Maximum</strong> – The cash balance should not be allowed to exceed the <strong>Balance limit</strong> amount for the cash account (upper bound)."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Minimum<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – The cash balance should not be allowed to go below the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Balance limit<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> amount for the cash account (bottom bound).","pos":[4986,5142],"source":"<strong>Minimum</strong> – The cash balance should not be allowed to go below the <strong>Balance limit</strong> amount for the cash account (bottom bound)."},{"content":"Check balance limit","pos":[5187,5206]},{"content":"Select what occurs during the approval process for cash documents if the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Balance limit<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> amount for the cash account is exceeded:","pos":[5216,5360],"source":"Select what occurs during the approval process for cash documents if the <strong>Balance limit</strong> amount for the cash account is exceeded:\n"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Accept<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – The limit can be exceeded.","pos":[5370,5422],"source":"<strong>Accept</strong> – The limit can be exceeded."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Warning<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – The limit can be exceeded, but the user receives a warning message.","pos":[5432,5526],"source":"<strong>Warning</strong> – The limit can be exceeded, but the user receives a warning message."},{"content":"The cash document is confirmed or approved.","pos":[5527,5570]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Error<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – The limit can't be exceeded.","pos":[5580,5633],"source":"<strong>Error</strong> – The limit can't be exceeded."},{"content":"The user receives an error message, and the cash document isn't confirmed or approved.","pos":[5634,5720]},{"content":"For more information about the approval process for cash documents, see the <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;quot;</ph>Cash transaction approval and posting<ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;quot;</ph> section, later in this topic.","pos":[5732,5887],"source":"\nFor more information about the approval process for cash documents, see the &quot;Cash transaction approval and posting&quot; section, later in this topic."},{"content":"Balance limit","pos":[5920,5933]},{"content":"Enter a limit for the cash account balance.","pos":[5943,5986]},{"content":"The amount should be in the currency that you specified.","pos":[5987,6043]},{"pos":[6078,6106],"content":"Set up cash posting profiles","linkify":"Set up cash posting profiles","nodes":[{"content":"Set up cash posting profiles","pos":[0,28]}]},{"content":"Cash posting profiles define postings to the general ledger.","pos":[6108,6168]},{"content":"To set up a cash posting profile, go to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cash<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>and bank management<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Setup<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Cash posting profiles<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>, and select or create a posting profile.","pos":[6169,6328],"source":" To set up a cash posting profile, go to **Cash** **and bank management** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Cash posting profiles**, and select or create a posting profile."},{"content":"Enter the following information.","pos":[6329,6361]},{"content":"Field","pos":[6466,6471]},{"content":"Description","pos":[6481,6492]},{"content":"Valid for","pos":[6542,6551]},{"content":"Select whether the posting profile applies to a specific cash account or all cash accounts:","pos":[6561,6652],"source":"Select whether the posting profile applies to a specific cash account or all cash accounts:\n"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Table<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – If there is a posting profile line for the cash account, that line is used for cash transaction posting.","pos":[6662,6791],"source":"<strong>Table</strong> – If there is a posting profile line for the cash account, that line is used for cash transaction posting."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>All<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – There is no posting profile line for the cash account.","pos":[6801,6878],"source":"<strong>All</strong> – There is no posting profile line for the cash account."},{"content":"Cash","pos":[6923,6927]},{"content":"If you selected <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Table<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> in the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Valid for<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field, specify the cash account.","pos":[6937,7042],"source":"If you selected <strong>Table</strong> in the <strong>Valid for</strong> field, specify the cash account."},{"content":"This field remains blank if you selected <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>All<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> in the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Valid for<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field.","pos":[7043,7145],"source":" This field remains blank if you selected <strong>All</strong> in the <strong>Valid for</strong> field."},{"content":"Ledger account","pos":[7178,7192]},{"content":"Enter the number of the ledger account to use as the summary account for the cash account.","pos":[7202,7292]},{"pos":[7327,7369],"content":"Set up number sequences for cash documents","linkify":"Set up number sequences for cash documents","nodes":[{"content":"Set up number sequences for cash documents","pos":[0,42]}]},{"content":"To set up number sequences for cash documents, go to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cash and bank management<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Setup<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Cash and bank management parameters<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.","pos":[7371,7513],"source":"To set up number sequences for cash documents, go to **Cash and bank management** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Cash and bank management parameters**."},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Number sequence<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, specify number sequence codes for the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Cash reimbursement slips<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Cash disbursement slips<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Cash correction voucher<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>, and <bpt id=\"p5\">**</bpt>Exchange adjustment<ept id=\"p5\">**</ept> documents, and for <bpt id=\"p6\">**</bpt>Cash report number<ept id=\"p6\">**</ept>.","pos":[7514,7742],"source":" On the **Number sequence** tab, specify number sequence codes for the **Cash reimbursement slips**, **Cash disbursement slips**, **Cash correction voucher**, and **Exchange adjustment** documents, and for **Cash report number**."},{"pos":[7748,7809],"content":"Set up default values for Cash and bank management parameters","linkify":"Set up default values for Cash and bank management parameters","nodes":[{"content":"Set up default values for Cash and bank management parameters","pos":[0,61]}]},{"content":"To set up default values for Cash and bank management parameters for the petty cash functionality, go to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cash and bank management<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Setup<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Cash and bank management parameters<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.","pos":[7811,8005],"source":"To set up default values for Cash and bank management parameters for the petty cash functionality, go to **Cash and bank management** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Cash and bank management parameters**."},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cash<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, enter the following information.","pos":[8006,8059],"source":" On the **Cash** tab, enter the following information."},{"content":"Field","pos":[8164,8169]},{"content":"Description","pos":[8179,8190]},{"content":"Cash","pos":[8240,8244]},{"content":"Select the default cash account in journals.","pos":[8254,8298]},{"content":"Cash posting","pos":[8332,8344]},{"content":"Enter the default cash posting profile that is used if no other posting profile is specified.","pos":[8354,8447]},{"content":"Check for voucher used","pos":[8480,8502]},{"content":"Select what occurs if duplicate numbers are found during the check of the cash document number:","pos":[8512,8607],"source":"Select what occurs if duplicate numbers are found during the check of the cash document number:\n"},{"content":"Reject duplicate","pos":[8617,8633]},{"content":"Reject copies within fiscal year","pos":[8643,8675]},{"content":"Accept duplicates","pos":[8685,8702]},{"content":"Warn in case of duplicates","pos":[8712,8738]},{"content":"Check operations limit","pos":[8783,8805]},{"content":"Specify what occurs if the limit for operations with counteragents is exceeded:","pos":[8815,8894],"source":"Specify what occurs if the limit for operations with counteragents is exceeded:\n"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Accept<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – The limit can be exceeded.","pos":[8904,8956],"source":"<strong>Accept</strong> – The limit can be exceeded."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Warning<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – The limit can be exceeded, but the user receives a warning message.","pos":[8966,9060],"source":"<strong>Warning</strong> – The limit can be exceeded, but the user receives a warning message."},{"content":"The operation is posted.","pos":[9061,9085]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Error<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – The limit can't be exceeded.","pos":[9095,9148],"source":"<strong>Error</strong> – The limit can't be exceeded."},{"content":"The user receives an error message, and the operation isn't posted.","pos":[9149,9216]},{"content":"Validation method","pos":[9260,9277]},{"content":"Select the validation method that is used to control exceeded limit amounts for operations:","pos":[9287,9378],"source":"Select the validation method that is used to control exceeded limit amounts for operations:\n"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Operation<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Validation is done per transaction","pos":[9388,9451],"source":"<strong>Operation</strong> – Validation is done per transaction"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Agreement<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Validation is done per transaction that has a specified contract with a counteragent.","pos":[9461,9575],"source":"<strong>Agreement</strong> – Validation is done per transaction that has a specified contract with a counteragent."},{"content":"Operations limit","pos":[9620,9636]},{"content":"Enter the maximum amount that is allowed for operations with counteragents in cash.","pos":[9646,9729]},{"content":"Posting on earlier date","pos":[9762,9785]},{"content":"Select this check box to enable cash transactions to be posted before the last date of the cash transaction.","pos":[9795,9903]},{"content":"Dimensions","pos":[9937,9947]},{"content":"Enter dimensions in the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Department code<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Analytical code<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, and <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Purpose code<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> fields.","pos":[9957,10090],"source":"Enter dimensions in the <strong>Department code</strong>, <strong>Analytical code</strong>, and <strong>Purpose code</strong> fields."},{"content":"The printing form for cash documents will reflect this information.","pos":[10091,10158]},{"content":"Use confirm status","pos":[10191,10209]},{"content":"Select this check box to use an additional status, <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Confirmed<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, during the approval process for cash documents.","pos":[10219,10345],"source":"Select this check box to use an additional status, <strong>Confirmed</strong>, during the approval process for cash documents."},{"content":"(For more information, see the <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;quot;</ph>Cash transaction approval and posting<ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;quot;</ph> section.)","pos":[10346,10436],"source":" (For more information, see the &quot;Cash transaction approval and posting&quot; section.)"},{"pos":[10471,10514],"content":"Set up cash journal names in General ledger","linkify":"Set up cash journal names in General ledger","nodes":[{"content":"Set up cash journal names in General ledger","pos":[0,43]}]},{"content":"To create a journal for cash transaction posting, go to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>General ledger<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Journal setup<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Journal names<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>, and create a new record.","pos":[10516,10662],"source":"To create a journal for cash transaction posting, go to **General ledger** &gt; **Journal setup** &gt; **Journal names**, and create a new record."},{"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Journal type<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field, specify <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Cash<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[10663,10711],"source":" In the **Journal type** field, specify **Cash**."},{"content":"Define other default journal parameters as you require.","pos":[10712,10767]},{"pos":[10772,10812],"content":"Daily cash operations via a Slip journal","linkify":"Daily cash operations via a Slip journal","nodes":[{"content":"Daily cash operations via a Slip journal","pos":[0,40]}]},{"content":"To create a cash document via a Slip journal, go to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cash and bank management<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Cash transactions<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Slip journal<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>, and create a new journal.","pos":[10813,10969],"source":"To create a cash document via a Slip journal, go to **Cash and bank management** &gt; **Cash transactions** &gt; **Slip journal**, and create a new journal."},{"content":"On the Action Pane, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Lines<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[10970,11006],"source":" On the Action Pane, click **Lines**."},{"content":"Add a new line, and enter the following information.","pos":[11007,11059]},{"content":"Field","pos":[11164,11169]},{"content":"Description","pos":[11179,11190]},{"content":"Date","pos":[11240,11244]},{"content":"Enter the date of the transaction.","pos":[11254,11288]},{"content":"Account","pos":[11322,11329]},{"content":"Select the cash account.","pos":[11339,11363]},{"content":"By default, a cash account is specified in the Cash and bank management parameters.","pos":[11364,11447]},{"content":"Description","pos":[11480,11491]},{"content":"Enter explanatory text for the transaction.","pos":[11501,11544]},{"content":"Debit Credit","pos":[11578,11590]},{"content":"Enter cash document amount in one of these fields:","pos":[11600,11650],"source":"Enter cash document amount in one of these fields:\n"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Debit<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Use this field to register cash receipts and a Cash reimbursement slip.","pos":[11660,11756],"source":"<strong>Debit</strong> – Use this field to register cash receipts and a Cash reimbursement slip."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Credit<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Use this field to register cash expenditures and a Cash disbursement slip.","pos":[11766,11866],"source":"<strong>Credit</strong> – Use this field to register cash expenditures and a Cash disbursement slip."},{"content":"Offset account type Offset account","pos":[11910,11944]},{"content":"Select an offset account type and offset account number.","pos":[11954,12010]},{"content":"Currency","pos":[12044,12052]},{"content":"Select the code for the transaction currency.","pos":[12062,12107]},{"content":"Voucher","pos":[12140,12147]},{"content":"This field is filled in automatically, based on the journal setup.","pos":[12157,12223]},{"content":"Order number","pos":[12257,12269]},{"content":"If no other number sequence is set up for the cash account, this field is filled in automatically, based on the number sequence that is specified in the parameters.","pos":[12279,12443]},{"content":"You can manually enter an order number in this field as you require.","pos":[12444,12512]},{"content":"To prevent inconsistence in cash document numbering, the following control is applied: the number of a cash document that has an earlier date of operation can't be higher than number of a cash document that has a later date of operation.","pos":[12513,12750]},{"content":"If you don't require this control, select the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Posting on earlier date<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> check box in the Cash and bank management parameters.","pos":[12751,12891],"source":" If you don't require this control, select the <strong>Posting on earlier date</strong> check box in the Cash and bank management parameters."},{"content":"Approval status","pos":[12924,12939]},{"content":"The first transaction status is <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>None<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.","pos":[12949,13003],"source":"The first transaction status is <strong>None</strong>."},{"content":"For information about how to set the transaction status, See the <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;quot;</ph>Cash transaction approval and posting<ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;quot;</ph> section.","pos":[13004,13127],"source":" For information about how to set the transaction status, See the &quot;Cash transaction approval and posting&quot; section."},{"content":"Document type","pos":[13161,13174]},{"content":"This field on the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Cash order<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> tab is filled in automatically, based on the amount that you entered for the cash document:","pos":[13184,13321],"source":"This field on the <strong>Cash order</strong> tab is filled in automatically, based on the amount that you entered for the cash document:\n"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Cash reimbursement slip<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – This value is used if you entered an amount in the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Debit<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field for the cash account.","pos":[13331,13475],"source":"<strong>Cash reimbursement slip</strong> – This value is used if you entered an amount in the <strong>Debit</strong> field for the cash account."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Cash disbursement slip<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – This value is used if you entered an amount in the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Credit<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field for the cash account","pos":[13485,13628],"source":"<strong>Cash disbursement slip</strong> – This value is used if you entered an amount in the <strong>Credit</strong> field for the cash account"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Correction<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – You entered a negative amount in either the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Debit<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field or the <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Credit<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field for the cash account.","pos":[13638,13799],"source":"<strong>Correction</strong> – You entered a negative amount in either the <strong>Debit</strong> field or the <strong>Credit</strong> field for the cash account."},{"content":"Sales tax group","pos":[13843,13858]},{"content":"Specify a sales tax group to calculate taxes on the operation.","pos":[13868,13930]},{"content":"Item sales tax group","pos":[13964,13984]},{"content":"Specify an item sales tax group to calculate taxes on the operation.","pos":[13994,14062]},{"content":"Reason","pos":[14095,14101]},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Cash order<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> tab, enter text that describes the transaction subject.","pos":[14111,14201],"source":"On the <strong>Cash order</strong> tab, enter text that describes the transaction subject."},{"content":"This text will be printed on the cash slip reporting form.","pos":[14202,14260]},{"content":"Document Date","pos":[14294,14307]},{"content":"Enter the description, number, and date of the primary document that is the reason for the transaction (for example, advance reports, invoice, or order).","pos":[14317,14470]},{"content":"Representative type","pos":[14503,14522]},{"content":"This field can have the following values:","pos":[14532,14573],"source":"This field can have the following values:\n"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Worker<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – The <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Representative<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> lookup contains a list of employees if the <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Offset account<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field is set to <bpt id=\"p4\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Ledger<ept id=\"p4\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> or <bpt id=\"p5\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Bank<ept id=\"p5\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, or a list of the counteragent's contact persons if the <bpt id=\"p6\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Offset account<ept id=\"p6\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field is set to <bpt id=\"p7\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Customer<ept id=\"p7\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> or <bpt id=\"p8\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Vendor<ept id=\"p8\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.","pos":[14583,14942],"source":"<strong>Worker</strong> – The <strong>Representative</strong> lookup contains a list of employees if the <strong>Offset account</strong> field is set to <strong>Ledger</strong> or <strong>Bank</strong>, or a list of the counteragent's contact persons if the <strong>Offset account</strong> field is set to <strong>Customer</strong> or <strong>Vendor</strong>."},{"content":"To set up representatives, go to <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Basic<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Setup<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Contacts<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> <ph id=\"ph3\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p4\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Contact person<ept id=\"p4\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.","pos":[14943,15095],"source":" To set up representatives, go to <strong>Basic</strong> &gt; <strong>Setup</strong> &gt; <strong>Contacts</strong> &gt; <strong>Contact person</strong>."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Other<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – The <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Representative<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> lookup contains a list of other clients.","pos":[15105,15206],"source":"<strong>Other</strong> – The <strong>Representative</strong> lookup contains a list of other clients."},{"content":"To set up receivers who don't appear in the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Customers<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Vendors<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> table, go to <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>General ledger<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p4\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Receivers<ept id=\"p4\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.","pos":[15207,15383],"source":" To set up receivers who don't appear in the <strong>Customers</strong> or <strong>Vendors</strong> table, go to <strong>General ledger</strong> &gt; <strong>Receivers</strong>."},{"content":"This type is available only for Latvia.","pos":[15384,15423]},{"content":"(The <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>CSELatvia<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> configuration key should be enabled.)","pos":[15424,15493],"source":" (The <strong>CSELatvia</strong> configuration key should be enabled.)"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Vendor<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – The <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Representative<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> lookup contains a list of vendors.","pos":[15503,15599],"source":"<strong>Vendor</strong> – The <strong>Representative</strong> lookup contains a list of vendors."},{"content":"To set up vendors, go to <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Accounts payable<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Vendors<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.","pos":[15600,15689],"source":" To set up vendors, go to <strong>Accounts payable</strong> &gt; <strong>Vendors</strong>."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Customer<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – The <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Representative<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> lookup contains a list of customers.","pos":[15699,15799],"source":"<strong>Customer</strong> – The <strong>Representative</strong> lookup contains a list of customers."},{"content":"To set up customers, go to <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Accounts receivable<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Customers<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.","pos":[15800,15896],"source":" To set up customers, go to <strong>Accounts receivable</strong> &gt; <strong>Customers</strong>."},{"content":"Representative","pos":[15941,15955]},{"content":"Select a representative of the type that you specified in the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Representative type<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field.","pos":[15965,16070],"source":"Select a representative of the type that you specified in the <strong>Representative type</strong> field."},{"content":"Name of person","pos":[16103,16117]},{"content":"This field is filled in automatically, based on the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Offset account<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Representative<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> fields.","pos":[16127,16254],"source":"This field is filled in automatically, based on the <strong>Offset account</strong> and <strong>Representative</strong> fields."},{"content":"The printing form for cash slips will reflect this information.","pos":[16255,16318]},{"content":"Identity card","pos":[16352,16365]},{"content":"This field is filled in automatically, based on the identity card data for the contact person (representative).","pos":[16375,16486]},{"content":"If the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Offset account type<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field is set to <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Advance holder<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, and the <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Offset account<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field is set to an employee number, cash receipts or expenditures can be done from or to the employee.","pos":[16487,16722],"source":" If the <strong>Offset account type</strong> field is set to <strong>Advance holder</strong>, and the <strong>Offset account</strong> field is set to an employee number, cash receipts or expenditures can be done from or to the employee."},{"content":"In this case the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Identity card<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field is filled in automatically by using data for the identity card from the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Employee<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> table (<bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Staff accounting<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p4\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Employee table<ept id=\"p4\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>).","pos":[16723,16954],"source":" In this case the <strong>Identity card</strong> field is filled in automatically by using data for the identity card from the <strong>Employee</strong> table (<strong>Staff accounting</strong> &gt; <strong>Employee table</strong>)."},{"content":"Purpose","pos":[16987,16994]},{"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Purpose<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> table, define one or more destination codes for the transaction amount.","pos":[17004,17107],"source":"In the <strong>Purpose</strong> table, define one or more destination codes for the transaction amount."},{"content":"Select a destination code in the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Purpose<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field, and enter an explanation in the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Transaction text<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field.","pos":[17108,17245],"source":" Select a destination code in the <strong>Purpose</strong> field, and enter an explanation in the <strong>Transaction text</strong> field."},{"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Amount<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field, enter an amount in the transaction currency.","pos":[17246,17328],"source":" In the <strong>Amount</strong> field, enter an amount in the transaction currency."},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Percent<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field shows, as a percentage, the ratio of the destination amount to the total transaction amount.","pos":[17329,17456],"source":" The <strong>Percent</strong> field shows, as a percentage, the ratio of the destination amount to the total transaction amount."},{"content":"Remainder","pos":[17490,17499]},{"content":"The remaining amount that is calculated.","pos":[17509,17549]},{"content":"Note that the whole transaction amount must be assigned to destination codes.","pos":[17550,17627]},{"content":"Officials","pos":[17660,17669]},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Officials<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> tab, specify the names and titles for responsible persons: Director, Chief accountant, and Cashier.","pos":[17679,17812],"source":"On the <strong>Officials</strong> tab, specify the names and titles for responsible persons: Director, Chief accountant, and Cashier."},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Position<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> values are determined by the setup of officials on the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>General<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> and <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Ledger<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> tabs of the <bpt id=\"p4\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Officials<ept id=\"p4\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> page (<bpt id=\"p5\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Basic<ept id=\"p5\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p6\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Setup<ept id=\"p6\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p7\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Contacts<ept id=\"p7\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> <ph id=\"ph3\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p8\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Officials<ept id=\"p8\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>).","pos":[17813,18111],"source":" The <strong>Position</strong> values are determined by the setup of officials on the <strong>General</strong> and <strong>Ledger</strong> tabs of the <strong>Officials</strong> page (<strong>Basic</strong> &gt; <strong>Setup</strong> &gt; <strong>Contacts</strong> &gt; <strong>Officials</strong>)."},{"content":"Prepayment","pos":[18145,18155]},{"content":"Select this check box if the transaction is a prepayment.","pos":[18165,18222]},{"content":"Posting profile","pos":[18255,18270]},{"content":"Enter the posting profile for the cash account.","pos":[18280,18327]},{"content":"By default, the posting profile that is specified in the Cash and bank management parameters is used.","pos":[18328,18429]},{"content":"Offset posting profile","pos":[18463,18485]},{"content":"Enter the posting profile for the selected offset account.","pos":[18495,18553]},{"content":"Total amount","pos":[18586,18598]},{"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Total amount<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field group at the bottom of the page, the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Reimb<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field shows the total that is calculated for all Cash reimbursement slips that are entered in the current journal, and the <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Disb<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field shows the total for all Cash disbursement slips.","pos":[18608,18910],"source":"In the <strong>Total amount</strong> field group at the bottom of the page, the <strong>Reimb</strong> field shows the total that is calculated for all Cash reimbursement slips that are entered in the current journal, and the <strong>Disb</strong> field shows the total for all Cash disbursement slips."},{"pos":[18941,19006],"content":"To check journal entries, on the Action Pane, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Validate<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"To check journal entries, on the Action Pane, click **Validate**."},{"pos":[19011,19054],"content":"Daily cash operations via a General journal","linkify":"Daily cash operations via a General journal","nodes":[{"content":"Daily cash operations via a General journal","pos":[0,43]}]},{"content":"To create a cash transaction via a General journal, go to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>General ledger<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Journal entries<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>General journals<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>, and create a new journal.","pos":[19055,19209],"source":"To create a cash transaction via a General journal, go to **General ledger** &gt; **Journal entries** &gt; **General journals**, and create a new journal."},{"content":"On the Action Pane, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Lines<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[19210,19246],"source":" On the Action Pane, click **Lines**."},{"content":"Add a new line, and enter the following information.","pos":[19247,19299]},{"content":"Field","pos":[19404,19409]},{"content":"Description","pos":[19419,19430]},{"content":"Date","pos":[19480,19484]},{"content":"Enter the date of the transaction.","pos":[19494,19528]},{"content":"Account type","pos":[19562,19574]},{"content":"Select <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Petty cash<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.","pos":[19584,19619],"source":"Select <strong>Petty cash</strong>."},{"content":"Account","pos":[19652,19659]},{"content":"Select the cash account number.","pos":[19669,19700]},{"content":"Transaction text","pos":[19734,19750]},{"content":"Enter explanatory text for the transaction.","pos":[19760,19803]},{"content":"Debit Credit","pos":[19836,19848]},{"content":"Enter cash document amount in one of these fields:","pos":[19858,19908],"source":"Enter cash document amount in one of these fields:\n"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Debit<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Use this field to register cash receipts and a Cash reimbursement slip.","pos":[19918,20014],"source":"<strong>Debit</strong> – Use this field to register cash receipts and a Cash reimbursement slip."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Credit<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Use this field to register cash expenditures and a Cash disbursement slip.","pos":[20024,20124],"source":"<strong>Credit</strong> – Use this field to register cash expenditures and a Cash disbursement slip."},{"content":"Offset account type Offset account","pos":[20169,20203]},{"content":"Select an offset account type and offset account number.","pos":[20213,20269]},{"content":"Currency","pos":[20302,20310]},{"content":"Select the code for the transaction currency.","pos":[20320,20365]},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Invoice<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, you can specify posting profiles for the selected account and offset account.","pos":[20396,20497],"source":"On the **Invoice** tab, you can specify posting profiles for the selected account and offset account."},{"content":"If the registered transaction is a prepayment, select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Prepayment<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> check box on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Payment<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> tab.","pos":[20498,20604],"source":" If the registered transaction is a prepayment, select the **Prepayment** check box on the **Payment** tab."},{"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Representative<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field group, fill in the fields as you did for the Slip journal lines to print on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Cash<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> report.","pos":[20605,20733],"source":" In the **Representative** field group, fill in the fields as you did for the Slip journal lines to print on the **Cash** report."},{"content":"To check journal entries, on the Action Pane, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Validate<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[20734,20799],"source":" To check journal entries, on the Action Pane, click **Validate**."},{"pos":[20804,20841],"content":"Cash transaction approval and posting","linkify":"Cash transaction approval and posting","nodes":[{"content":"Cash transaction approval and posting","pos":[0,37]}]},{"content":"For cash transactions, the following statuses can be applied: <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>None<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Confirmed<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Approved<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>, and <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Rejected<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>.","pos":[20842,20960],"source":"For cash transactions, the following statuses can be applied: **None**, **Confirmed**, **Approved**, and **Rejected**."},{"content":"A <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Use confirm status<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> parameter on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Approval<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> FastTab of the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Cash<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> tab at <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Cash and bank management<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p5\">**</bpt>Setup<ept id=\"p5\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p6\">**</bpt>Cash and bank management parameters<ept id=\"p6\">**</ept> lets you activate two additional statuses: <bpt id=\"p7\">**</bpt>Confirmed<ept id=\"p7\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p8\">**</bpt>Rejected<ept id=\"p8\">**</ept>.","pos":[20961,21210],"source":" A **Use confirm status** parameter on the **Approval** FastTab of the **Cash** tab at **Cash and bank management** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Cash and bank management parameters** lets you activate two additional statuses: **Confirmed** and **Rejected**."},{"content":"Confirmation is appropriate when cash documents are issued, and cash receipts or expenditures are shared between two employees: accountant and cashier.","pos":[21211,21362]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Reset status<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> function changes the current transaction status.","pos":[21363,21432],"source":" The **Reset status** function changes the current transaction status."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Approved<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> becomes <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Confirmed<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, and <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Confirmed<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> becomes <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>None<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>.","pos":[21433,21504],"source":"**Approved** becomes **Confirmed**, and **Confirmed** becomes **None**."},{"content":"Cash journal entries can be edited only when the status is <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>None<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[21505,21573],"source":" Cash journal entries can be edited only when the status is **None**."},{"content":"Cash transactions can be rejected only if the transaction status is <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Confirmed<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[21574,21656],"source":" Cash transactions can be rejected only if the transaction status is **Confirmed**."},{"content":"Rejected cash documents are included on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Journal of registration of cash documents<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> report, but they aren't reflected on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Cash book<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> report.","pos":[21657,21809],"source":" Rejected cash documents are included on the **Journal of registration of cash documents** report, but they aren't reflected on the **Cash book** report."},{"content":"To confirm a transaction, select the corresponding Slip journal line, and then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Documents approval<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Confirm<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[21810,21935],"source":" To confirm a transaction, select the corresponding Slip journal line, and then click **Documents approval** &gt; **Confirm**."},{"content":"An order number is generated, based on the specified number sequence.","pos":[21936,22005]},{"content":"The transaction status is changed to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Confirmed<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, and you can no longer edit the journal line.","pos":[22006,22102],"source":" The transaction status is changed to **Confirmed**, and you can no longer edit the journal line."},{"content":"The cash account balance remains unchanged.","pos":[22103,22146]},{"content":"To reject a cash document, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Documents approval<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Reject<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[22147,22219],"source":" To reject a cash document, click **Documents approval** &gt; **Reject**."},{"content":"This option is available only for documents that have <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Confirmed<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> status.","pos":[22220,22295],"source":" This option is available only for documents that have **Confirmed** status."},{"content":"To approve a transaction, select the corresponding Slip journal line, and then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Documents approval<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Approve<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[22296,22421],"source":" To approve a transaction, select the corresponding Slip journal line, and then click **Documents approval** &gt; **Approve**."},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Approved<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> status indicates that cash funds are received or expended.","pos":[22422,22497],"source":" The **Approved** status indicates that cash funds are received or expended."},{"content":"The cash balance is changed.","pos":[22498,22526]},{"content":"The cash transaction can be posted.","pos":[22527,22562]},{"content":"To cancel an <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Approved<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> status and reset the status to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>None<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, click <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Documents approval<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Reset status<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>.","pos":[22563,22681],"source":" To cancel an **Approved** status and reset the status to **None**, click **Documents approval** &gt; **Reset status**."},{"content":"Only approved cash transactions can be posted.","pos":[22682,22728]},{"content":"To post a journal, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Post<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Post<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[22729,22777],"source":" To post a journal, click **Post** &gt; **Post**."},{"pos":[22782,22800],"content":"Print a cash order","linkify":"Print a cash order","nodes":[{"content":"Print a cash order","pos":[0,18]}]},{"content":"To print a cash order, select a Slip journal line, and then, on the Action Pane, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Print<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Cash order report<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[22801,22925],"source":"To print a cash order, select a Slip journal line, and then, on the Action Pane, click **Print** &gt; **Cash order report**."},{"content":"The system generates a printing form for either a Cash reimbursement slip or a Cash disbursement slip, depending on whether an amount is entered in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Debit<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field the or <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Credit<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> field for the selected line:","pos":[22926,23140],"source":" The system generates a printing form for either a Cash reimbursement slip or a Cash disbursement slip, depending on whether an amount is entered in the **Debit** field the or **Credit** field for the selected line:"},{"pos":[23146,23215],"content":"If there is an amount in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Debit<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field: Cash reimbursement slip","source":"If there is an amount in the **Debit** field: Cash reimbursement slip"},{"pos":[23220,23289],"content":"If there is an amount in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Credit<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field: Cash disbursement slip","source":"If there is an amount in the **Credit** field: Cash disbursement slip"},{"content":"Slip journal lines that have <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Confirmed<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Approved<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, or <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Rejected<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> status can be printed.","pos":[23291,23387],"source":"Slip journal lines that have **Confirmed**, **Approved**, or **Rejected** status can be printed."},{"content":"You can also print cash order documents at <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cash and bank management<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Inquires and reports<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Cash order<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.","pos":[23388,23510],"source":" You can also print cash order documents at **Cash and bank management** &gt; **Inquires and reports** &gt; **Cash order**."},{"pos":[23515,23529],"content":"Periodic tasks","linkify":"Periodic tasks","nodes":[{"content":"Periodic tasks","pos":[0,14]}]},{"pos":[23530,23623],"content":"The following tasks can be performed at <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cash and bank management<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Periodic tasks<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","source":"The following tasks can be performed at **Cash and bank management** &gt; **Periodic tasks**."},{"content":"Periodic task","pos":[23728,23741]},{"content":"Description","pos":[23751,23762]},{"content":"Check balance limit","pos":[23812,23831]},{"content":"Check the balance for the selected cash account on the specified date, and show the result in an information message.","pos":[23841,23958]},{"content":"Only approved transactions can be counted in the balance calculation.","pos":[23959,24028]},{"content":"Transactions that are marked as <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>For payroll<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> aren't considered.","pos":[24029,24108],"source":" Transactions that are marked as <strong>For payroll</strong> aren't considered."},{"content":"Cash balance recalculation","pos":[24142,24168]},{"content":"Use this task to make sure that the ledger balances for cash accounts fit the cash balance.","pos":[24178,24269]},{"content":"Cash report creation (for Poland only)","pos":[24302,24340]},{"content":"Create a <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Cash<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> report.","pos":[24350,24388],"source":"Create a <strong>Cash</strong> report."},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Cash<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> report number is generated based on the number sequence that is set up for <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Report number<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.","pos":[24389,24521],"source":" The <strong>Cash</strong> report number is generated based on the number sequence that is set up for <strong>Report number</strong>."},{"content":"In the dialog box for the task, in the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>To date<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, specify the last date for which cash transactions should be counted for the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Cash<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> report.","pos":[24522,24692],"source":" In the dialog box for the task, in the <strong>To date</strong>, specify the last date for which cash transactions should be counted for the <strong>Cash</strong> report."},{"content":"Use the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Filter<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> function on the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Records to include<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> tab to specify additional criteria to limit the selection of cash transactions.","pos":[24693,24856],"source":" Use the <strong>Filter</strong> function on the <strong>Records to include</strong> tab to specify additional criteria to limit the selection of cash transactions."},{"content":"These criteria can include cash account numbers and currency codes.","pos":[24857,24924]},{"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Create by<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field, select the user who is responsible for report creation.","pos":[24925,25021],"source":" In the <strong>Create by</strong> field, select the user who is responsible for report creation."},{"content":"To view the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Cash<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> report that is created, use the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Cash reports<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> button on the <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Cash accounts<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> page.","pos":[25022,25168],"source":" To view the <strong>Cash</strong> report that is created, use the <strong>Cash reports</strong> button on the <strong>Cash accounts</strong> page."},{"content":"Cash - Exchange adjustment FIFO and LIFO (for Poland only)","pos":[25202,25260]},{"content":"Calculate the exchange adjustment per Polish standards.","pos":[25270,25325]},{"content":"Use the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Filter<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> function on the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Records to include<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> tab to specify the cash account to run the task for.","pos":[25326,25462],"source":" Use the <strong>Filter</strong> function on the <strong>Records to include</strong> tab to specify the cash account to run the task for."},{"content":"Select the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Recalculation<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> check box to do a full recalculation of the exchange adjustment difference for all open periods.","pos":[25463,25601],"source":" Select the <strong>Recalculation</strong> check box to do a full recalculation of the exchange adjustment difference for all open periods."},{"content":"Here is how the exchange adjustment is calculated when the first in, first out (FIFO) and last in, first out (LIFO) methods are used:","pos":[25602,25735],"source":" Here is how the exchange adjustment is calculated when the first in, first out (FIFO) and last in, first out (LIFO) methods are used:\n"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>FIFO method<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – The system searches for an expenditure transaction that has an earlier transaction date (smaller order number) and settles it with a receipt transaction that has an earlier transaction date (smaller order number).","pos":[25745,25989],"source":"<strong>FIFO method</strong> – The system searches for an expenditure transaction that has an earlier transaction date (smaller order number) and settles it with a receipt transaction that has an earlier transaction date (smaller order number)."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>LIFO method<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – The system searches for an expenditure transaction that has a later transaction date (larger order number) and settles it with a receipt transaction that has a later transaction date (larger order number).","pos":[25999,26235],"source":"<strong>LIFO method</strong> – The system searches for an expenditure transaction that has a later transaction date (larger order number) and settles it with a receipt transaction that has a later transaction date (larger order number)."},{"content":"The settled amount is reflected in the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Settled currency<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field on the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Cash transaction<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> page.","pos":[26247,26372],"source":"\nThe settled amount is reflected in the <strong>Settled currency</strong> field on the <strong>Cash transaction</strong> page."},{"content":"If there is an exchange adjustment difference, the amount is reflected in the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Exchange adjustment amount<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field, and a transaction of the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Exchange rate difference<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> document type is generated in the <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Cash transaction<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> table.","pos":[26373,26643],"source":" If there is an exchange adjustment difference, the amount is reflected in the <strong>Exchange adjustment amount</strong> field, and a transaction of the <strong>Exchange rate difference</strong> document type is generated in the <strong>Cash transaction</strong> table."},{"content":"Ledger accounts for profit/loss transactions are set in the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Currency<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> table (<bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Exchange rate financial profit<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> and <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Exchange rate financial loss<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>).","pos":[26644,26836],"source":" Ledger accounts for profit/loss transactions are set in the <strong>Currency</strong> table (<strong>Exchange rate financial profit</strong> and <strong>Exchange rate financial loss</strong>)."},{"content":"Foreign currency revaluation - Cash","pos":[26869,26904]},{"content":"Use this task to have an adequate balance in the default currency on the reporting date when the operations are entered in foreign currencies.","pos":[26914,27056]},{"content":"Use the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Filter<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> function on the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Records to include<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> tab to specify the cash account to run the task for.","pos":[27057,27193],"source":" Use the <strong>Filter</strong> function on the <strong>Records to include</strong> tab to specify the cash account to run the task for."},{"content":"In the dialog box for the task, use the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>From currency<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>To Currency<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> fields to specify transaction currencies.","pos":[27194,27339],"source":" In the dialog box for the task, use the <strong>From currency</strong> and <strong>To Currency</strong> fields to specify transaction currencies."},{"content":"The system compares the amount in the currency that was converted by using exchange rate on the selected date with the amount in the default currency.","pos":[27340,27490]},{"content":"The difference between the two amounts (excluding the previous exchange adjustment) is the calculated exchange adjustment.","pos":[27491,27613]},{"content":"This task creates an approved cash transaction of the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Exchange adjustment<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> type.","pos":[27614,27710],"source":" This task creates an approved cash transaction of the <strong>Exchange adjustment</strong> type."},{"content":"The ledger transaction is formed by using the ledger account for cash and the ledger account that is specified in <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Unrealized profit<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Unrealized loss<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> in the <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Currency<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> table.","pos":[27711,27935],"source":" The ledger transaction is formed by using the ledger account for cash and the ledger account that is specified in <strong>Unrealized profit</strong> or <strong>Unrealized loss</strong> in the <strong>Currency</strong> table."},{"pos":[27969,27990],"content":"Inquiries and reports","linkify":"Inquiries and reports","nodes":[{"content":"Inquiries and reports","pos":[0,21]}]},{"content":"Inquiry or report","pos":[27993,28010]},{"content":"Description","pos":[28041,28052]},{"content":"Cash transactions view","pos":[28545,28567]},{"pos":[28593,28735],"content":"For a Slip journal line, use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Inquiries<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button on the Action Pane to view ledger transactions, the cash balance, and other information.","source":"For a Slip journal line, use the **Inquiries** button on the Action Pane to view ledger transactions, the cash balance, and other information."},{"content":"Cash transaction","pos":[28821,28837]},{"content":"Go to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cash and bank management<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Inquiries and reports<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Cash transactions<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> to view cash transactions.","pos":[28869,28988],"source":"Go to **Cash and bank management** &gt; **Inquiries and reports** &gt; **Cash transactions** to view cash transactions."},{"content":"Use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Filter<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> function to specify additional criteria to limit the selection of cash transactions.","pos":[28989,29092],"source":" Use the **Filter** function to specify additional criteria to limit the selection of cash transactions."},{"content":"Journal of registration (for Estonia, Russia)","pos":[29097,29142]},{"pos":[29145,29334],"content":"The report at <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cash and bank management<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Inquiries and reports<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Journal of registration<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> reflects all cash reimbursement and cash disbursement slips that have been issued.","source":"The report at **Cash and bank management** &gt; **Inquiries and reports** &gt; **Journal of registration** reflects all cash reimbursement and cash disbursement slips that have been issued."},{"content":"Cash book (for Latvia, Lithuania, Russia)","pos":[29373,29414]},{"pos":[29421,29585],"content":"The report at <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cash and bank management<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Inquiries and reports<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Cash book report<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> reflects actual cash fund movements (receipts and expenditures).","source":"The report at **Cash and bank management** &gt; **Inquiries and reports** &gt; **Cash book report** reflects actual cash fund movements (receipts and expenditures)."}]}