{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,92],"content":"License codes and configuration keys report | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"License codes and configuration keys report | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,60]}]},{"pos":[106,217],"content":"This topic points you to a report that lists the license codes and configuration keys available in Dynamics AX.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"This topic points you to a report that lists the license codes and configuration keys available in Dynamics AX.","pos":[0,111]}]},{"pos":[649,692],"content":"License codes and configuration keys report","linkify":"License codes and configuration keys report","nodes":[{"content":"License codes and configuration keys report","pos":[0,43]}]},{"content":"When you purchase Microsoft Dynamics AX, all functionality is included.","pos":[694,765]},{"content":"By default, some features and functionality that you do not use may be enabled.","pos":[766,845]},{"content":"The administrator should disable the features that are not needed by disabling license codes and configuration keys.","pos":[846,962]},{"content":"When a license code or configuration key is disabled, the associated module or feature is removed from the user interface.","pos":[964,1086]},{"content":"Large sets of functionality, such as modules, are controlled by license codes.","pos":[1087,1165]},{"content":"Many license codes, in turn, enable configuration keys that allow you to enable and disable functionality at a more detailed level.","pos":[1166,1297]},{"pos":[1302,1320],"content":"To view the report","linkify":"To view the report","nodes":[{"content":"To view the report","pos":[0,18]}]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>License codes and configuration keys report<ept id=\"p1\">](https://mbs.microsoft.com/customersource/northamerica/AX/downloads/reports/axtechrefrep)</ept>lists each configuration key that is available.","pos":[1321,1506],"source":"The [License codes and configuration keys report](https://mbs.microsoft.com/customersource/northamerica/AX/downloads/reports/axtechrefrep)lists each configuration key that is available."},{"content":"The report also indicates the license code and menu items associated with each configuration key.","pos":[1507,1604]},{"pos":[1609,1634],"content":"How the report is grouped","linkify":"How the report is grouped","nodes":[{"content":"How the report is grouped","pos":[0,25]}]},{"content":"The report is a Microsoft Excel file.","pos":[1635,1672]},{"content":"For large reports, the rows are grouped alphabetically on tab 1.","pos":[1673,1737]},{"content":"All rows are displayed when you click tab 2.","pos":[1738,1782]},{"content":"![GeneratedReports]","pos":[1783,1802]}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: License codes and configuration keys report | Microsoft Docs\ndescription: This topic points you to a report that lists the license codes and configuration keys available in Dynamics AX.\nauthor: annbe\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 2016-10-11 15:40:51\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# keywords: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: 71\nms.suite: Released- Dynamics AX platform update 1\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 203464\nms.assetid: 78ff7156-baaa-479b-8c02-704ad9ebe1af\n# ms.region: \n# ms.industry: \nms.author: annbe\n\n---\n\n# License codes and configuration keys report\n\nWhen you purchase Microsoft Dynamics AX, all functionality is included. By default, some features and functionality that you do not use may be enabled. The administrator should disable the features that are not needed by disabling license codes and configuration keys.\n\nWhen a license code or configuration key is disabled, the associated module or feature is removed from the user interface. Large sets of functionality, such as modules, are controlled by license codes. Many license codes, in turn, enable configuration keys that allow you to enable and disable functionality at a more detailed level.\n\n## To view the report\nThe [License codes and configuration keys report](https://mbs.microsoft.com/customersource/northamerica/AX/downloads/reports/axtechrefrep)lists each configuration key that is available. The report also indicates the license code and menu items associated with each configuration key.\n\n## How the report is grouped\nThe report is a Microsoft Excel file. For large reports, the rows are grouped alphabetically on tab 1. All rows are displayed when you click tab 2. ![GeneratedReports]\n\n"}