{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,73],"content":"Case management examples | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Case management examples | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,41]}]},{"pos":[256,266],"content":"CaseDetail","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"CaseDetail","pos":[0,10]}]},{"pos":[503,527],"content":"Case management examples","linkify":"Case management examples","nodes":[{"content":"Case management examples","pos":[0,24]}]},{"content":"By planning, tracking, and analyzing cases, you can develop efficient resolutions that can be used for similar issues.","pos":[529,647]},{"content":"For example, when customer service representatives or Human Resources generalists create cases, they can find information in knowledge articles to help them work with or resolve a case more efficiently.","pos":[648,850]},{"content":"The following examples show how cases can be used for different situations in an organization.","pos":[851,945]},{"pos":[950,1018],"content":"Example: How Fabrikam uses cases for customers in the private sector","linkify":"Example: How Fabrikam uses cases for customers in the private sector","nodes":[{"content":"Example: How Fabrikam uses cases for customers in the private sector","pos":[0,68]}]},{"content":"Lisa, a customer service representative at Fabrikam, receives a telephone call from Lionel, a Fabrikam customer.","pos":[1019,1131]},{"content":"Lionel is having trouble setting the correct volume level on the new sound system that Fabrikam just installed in his music store.","pos":[1132,1262]},{"content":"Lisa creates a case for Lionel and assigns the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Volume<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> category to the case.","pos":[1263,1342],"source":" Lisa creates a case for Lionel and assigns the **Volume** category to the case."},{"content":"Because Lisa knows that it's important for Lionel to have music in his store, she elevates the priority and assigns a one-day service level agreement (SLA) to the case.","pos":[1343,1511]},{"content":"She also enters the case details in the case log.","pos":[1512,1561]},{"content":"Lisa notices that several knowledge articles are associated with the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Volume<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> category, and that three of them are marked as helpful for resolving cases.","pos":[1562,1717],"source":" Lisa notices that several knowledge articles are associated with the **Volume** category, and that three of them are marked as helpful for resolving cases."},{"content":"Lisa opens each article and discusses the resolution steps with Lionel, but none of the solutions solve the issue that Lionel is having with his new sound system.","pos":[1718,1880]},{"content":"Lisa tells Lionel that an audio technician will call him within 24 hours and work with him to try to solve the issue.","pos":[1881,1998]},{"content":"Lisa activates the case, and a set of activities is created.","pos":[1999,2059]},{"content":"She assigns the activities to Terrence, a member of the audio engineering team.","pos":[2060,2139]},{"content":"Terrence sees that new activities are assigned to him.","pos":[2140,2194]},{"content":"He opens the case and reads the case log to learn more about the case.","pos":[2195,2265]},{"content":"Terrence encountered the same issue the day before, and he developed a solution.","pos":[2266,2346]},{"content":"Terrence contacts Lionel and offers this solution for the issue.","pos":[2347,2411]},{"content":"Terrence also enters it in the case details.","pos":[2412,2456]},{"content":"Because his solution is successful, Terrence decides to document it, so that other people can use it if they encounter the same issue.","pos":[2457,2591]},{"content":"Terrence adds the document to the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Knowledge article<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, assigns the document to the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Volume<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> category, and manually elevates the ranking, so that other Fabrikam employees will know that it's a successful solution.","pos":[2592,2813],"source":" Terrence adds the document to the **Knowledge article** page, assigns the document to the **Volume** category, and manually elevates the ranking, so that other Fabrikam employees will know that it's a successful solution."},{"content":"Terrence then elevates the case to the next level.","pos":[2814,2864]},{"content":"By elevating the case, he creates a new activity for Marie, who is a quality assurance representative in the customer service department.","pos":[2865,3002]},{"content":"Marie sees that a new activity is assigned to her, and she opens the case that is associated with the activity.","pos":[3003,3114]},{"content":"Marie reviews the case and the case details to make sure that the correct process was followed for the case.","pos":[3115,3223]},{"content":"She verifies that the actual case time did not exceed the time frame that was estimated in the SLA.","pos":[3224,3323]},{"content":"She notes that Terrence contacted the customer, and that the issue was resolved.","pos":[3324,3404]},{"content":"Marie is satisfied with the treatment that the customer received and the results of the case.","pos":[3405,3498]},{"content":"She resolves the case as closed.","pos":[3499,3531]},{"content":"When Marie closes the case, the open activity that is assigned to her is also closed.","pos":[3532,3617]},{"pos":[3622,3699],"content":"Example: How City Power & Light uses cases for customers in the public sector","linkify":"Example: How City Power & Light uses cases for customers in the public sector","nodes":[{"content":"Example: How City Power &amp; Light uses cases for customers in the public sector","pos":[0,77],"source":"Example: How City Power & Light uses cases for customers in the public sector"}]},{"content":"Annie, a customer service representative with City Power &amp; Light, receives a telephone call from a resident of the city that City Power &amp; Light serves.","pos":[3700,3851],"source":"Annie, a customer service representative with City Power & Light, receives a telephone call from a resident of the city that City Power & Light serves."},{"content":"Annie records the call as an activity and takes notes of the conversation.","pos":[3852,3926]},{"content":"The resident tells Annie that his house has no power.","pos":[3927,3980]},{"content":"Annie informs the resident that City Power &amp; Light will investigate, find, and resolve the issue as quickly as possible.","pos":[3981,4101],"source":" Annie informs the resident that City Power & Light will investigate, find, and resolve the issue as quickly as possible."},{"content":"She then creates a case, associates the telephone call with the case, and creates a service order.","pos":[4102,4200]},{"content":"Annie knows that other residents are likely to call to report a power outage.","pos":[4201,4278]},{"content":"Therefore, to avoid overwhelming the customer service center, and to save time, Annie sends a group instant message (IM) to inform the other representatives about the issue, and to tell them that a case and service order have been created.","pos":[4279,4518]},{"content":"She includes the case number and service order number in her IM.","pos":[4519,4583]},{"content":"Then, if City Power &amp; Light receives more telephone calls about the power outage, the customer service representatives can create an activity for each telephone call and assign it to the existing case.","pos":[4584,4785],"source":" Then, if City Power & Light receives more telephone calls about the power outage, the customer service representatives can create an activity for each telephone call and assign it to the existing case."},{"pos":[4790,4836],"content":"Example: How Fabrikam uses cases for employees","linkify":"Example: How Fabrikam uses cases for employees","nodes":[{"content":"Example: How Fabrikam uses cases for employees","pos":[0,46]}]},{"content":"The following scenarios show how Fabrikam Human Resources generalists in different locations can use case management when they address issues for employees.","pos":[4837,4993]},{"pos":[4999,5015],"content":"In Great Britain","linkify":"In Great Britain","nodes":[{"content":"In Great Britain","pos":[0,16]}]},{"content":"Cristine, the Human Resources generalist for the Great Britain division of Fabrikam, receives a telephone call from Claus, a Fabrikam employee.","pos":[5017,5160]},{"content":"Claus informs Cristine that nine weeks ago, immediately after the birth of his son, he changed the number of dependents on his tax withholdings.","pos":[5161,5305]},{"content":"Claus wants to know why the changes haven't become effective.","pos":[5306,5367]},{"content":"Cristine creates a case for Claus.","pos":[5368,5402]},{"content":"She reviews Claus’s tax information and learns that, although Claus entered new dependent information, he didn't select a start date for the new tax withholdings.","pos":[5403,5565]},{"content":"Cristine sends an email message to inform Claus that he must select a start date and resubmit his changes.","pos":[5566,5672]},{"content":"Claus replies to Cristine’s message to tell her that he has now selected a start date and resubmitted his changes.","pos":[5673,5787]},{"content":"Cristine attaches the email message from Claus to the case record, verifies that the correct changes were made and submitted, and closes the case.","pos":[5788,5934]},{"pos":[5940,5960],"content":"In the United States","linkify":"In the United States","nodes":[{"content":"In the United States","pos":[0,20]}]},{"content":"Luke, the Human Resources generalist for the United States division of Fabrikam, receives an email message from Shannon, a Fabrikam employee.","pos":[5962,6103]},{"content":"Shannon is a machine operator who was injured on the job six months ago.","pos":[6104,6176]},{"content":"Since then, she has been working with Humongous Insurance to have her medical expenses paid.","pos":[6177,6269]},{"content":"Because Shannon contacted Luke about this issue four weeks ago, a case has already been created.","pos":[6270,6366]},{"content":"Shannon’s new email message explains that Humongous Insurance is still not returning her telephone calls.","pos":[6367,6472]},{"content":"Luke opens the existing case, adds Shannon’s email message as a document, and reviews the case log.","pos":[6473,6572]},{"content":"When Luke created this case, he assigned the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Insurance<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> category to it.","pos":[6573,6647],"source":" When Luke created this case, he assigned the **Insurance** category to it."},{"content":"He now sees that there is a new knowledge article that is associated with the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Insurance<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> category.","pos":[6648,6749],"source":" He now sees that there is a new knowledge article that is associated with the **Insurance** category."},{"content":"Luke reads the knowledge article and learns that all phones at Humongous Insurance are down while the company’s telephone system is being updated.","pos":[6750,6896]},{"content":"The article states that the insurance company sent an email message to all its customers, but that several customers did not receive the message because of a problem with the company’s email system.","pos":[6897,7095]},{"content":"All customers who have active insurance claims are asked to send their inquiries to Humongous Insurance by email or paper mail.","pos":[7096,7223]},{"content":"Luke sends Shannon an email message that explains what she must do to have her insurance claim settled.","pos":[7224,7327]},{"content":"He also ranks the knowledge article that he read as a helpful source of information.","pos":[7328,7412]},{"content":"Luke creates another activity for himself, so that he can follow up with both Shannon and Humongous Insurance in four weeks to make sure that the claim has been resolved.","pos":[7413,7583]},{"content":"After four weeks, Luke contacts Shannon.","pos":[7584,7624]},{"content":"He learns that Humongous Insurance has paid her claims, and that she is happy with the resolution.","pos":[7625,7723]},{"content":"Luke changes the status of the case to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Closed<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[7724,7774],"source":" Luke changes the status of the case to **Closed**."}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Case management examples | Microsoft Docs\ndescription: \nauthor: annbe\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 2015-12-11 23:25:17\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nkeywords: CaseDetail\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: 51\nms.suite: Released- Dynamics AX 7.0.0\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 23541\nms.assetid: 706dfb47-9f67-46bb-8a0c-a2082a99e808\n# ms.region: \n# ms.industry: \nms.author: annbe\n\n---\n\n# Case management examples\n\nBy planning, tracking, and analyzing cases, you can develop efficient resolutions that can be used for similar issues. For example, when customer service representatives or Human Resources generalists create cases, they can find information in knowledge articles to help them work with or resolve a case more efficiently. The following examples show how cases can be used for different situations in an organization.\n\n## Example: How Fabrikam uses cases for customers in the private sector\nLisa, a customer service representative at Fabrikam, receives a telephone call from Lionel, a Fabrikam customer. Lionel is having trouble setting the correct volume level on the new sound system that Fabrikam just installed in his music store. Lisa creates a case for Lionel and assigns the **Volume** category to the case. Because Lisa knows that it's important for Lionel to have music in his store, she elevates the priority and assigns a one-day service level agreement (SLA) to the case. She also enters the case details in the case log. Lisa notices that several knowledge articles are associated with the **Volume** category, and that three of them are marked as helpful for resolving cases. Lisa opens each article and discusses the resolution steps with Lionel, but none of the solutions solve the issue that Lionel is having with his new sound system. Lisa tells Lionel that an audio technician will call him within 24 hours and work with him to try to solve the issue. Lisa activates the case, and a set of activities is created. She assigns the activities to Terrence, a member of the audio engineering team. Terrence sees that new activities are assigned to him. He opens the case and reads the case log to learn more about the case. Terrence encountered the same issue the day before, and he developed a solution. Terrence contacts Lionel and offers this solution for the issue. Terrence also enters it in the case details. Because his solution is successful, Terrence decides to document it, so that other people can use it if they encounter the same issue. Terrence adds the document to the **Knowledge article** page, assigns the document to the **Volume** category, and manually elevates the ranking, so that other Fabrikam employees will know that it's a successful solution. Terrence then elevates the case to the next level. By elevating the case, he creates a new activity for Marie, who is a quality assurance representative in the customer service department. Marie sees that a new activity is assigned to her, and she opens the case that is associated with the activity. Marie reviews the case and the case details to make sure that the correct process was followed for the case. She verifies that the actual case time did not exceed the time frame that was estimated in the SLA. She notes that Terrence contacted the customer, and that the issue was resolved. Marie is satisfied with the treatment that the customer received and the results of the case. She resolves the case as closed. When Marie closes the case, the open activity that is assigned to her is also closed.\n\n## Example: How City Power & Light uses cases for customers in the public sector\nAnnie, a customer service representative with City Power & Light, receives a telephone call from a resident of the city that City Power & Light serves. Annie records the call as an activity and takes notes of the conversation. The resident tells Annie that his house has no power. Annie informs the resident that City Power & Light will investigate, find, and resolve the issue as quickly as possible. She then creates a case, associates the telephone call with the case, and creates a service order. Annie knows that other residents are likely to call to report a power outage. Therefore, to avoid overwhelming the customer service center, and to save time, Annie sends a group instant message (IM) to inform the other representatives about the issue, and to tell them that a case and service order have been created. She includes the case number and service order number in her IM. Then, if City Power & Light receives more telephone calls about the power outage, the customer service representatives can create an activity for each telephone call and assign it to the existing case.\n\n## Example: How Fabrikam uses cases for employees\nThe following scenarios show how Fabrikam Human Resources generalists in different locations can use case management when they address issues for employees.\n\n### In Great Britain\n\nCristine, the Human Resources generalist for the Great Britain division of Fabrikam, receives a telephone call from Claus, a Fabrikam employee. Claus informs Cristine that nine weeks ago, immediately after the birth of his son, he changed the number of dependents on his tax withholdings. Claus wants to know why the changes haven't become effective. Cristine creates a case for Claus. She reviews Claus’s tax information and learns that, although Claus entered new dependent information, he didn't select a start date for the new tax withholdings. Cristine sends an email message to inform Claus that he must select a start date and resubmit his changes. Claus replies to Cristine’s message to tell her that he has now selected a start date and resubmitted his changes. Cristine attaches the email message from Claus to the case record, verifies that the correct changes were made and submitted, and closes the case.\n\n### In the United States\n\nLuke, the Human Resources generalist for the United States division of Fabrikam, receives an email message from Shannon, a Fabrikam employee. Shannon is a machine operator who was injured on the job six months ago. Since then, she has been working with Humongous Insurance to have her medical expenses paid. Because Shannon contacted Luke about this issue four weeks ago, a case has already been created. Shannon’s new email message explains that Humongous Insurance is still not returning her telephone calls. Luke opens the existing case, adds Shannon’s email message as a document, and reviews the case log. When Luke created this case, he assigned the **Insurance** category to it. He now sees that there is a new knowledge article that is associated with the **Insurance** category. Luke reads the knowledge article and learns that all phones at Humongous Insurance are down while the company’s telephone system is being updated. The article states that the insurance company sent an email message to all its customers, but that several customers did not receive the message because of a problem with the company’s email system. All customers who have active insurance claims are asked to send their inquiries to Humongous Insurance by email or paper mail. Luke sends Shannon an email message that explains what she must do to have her insurance claim settled. He also ranks the knowledge article that he read as a helpful source of information. Luke creates another activity for himself, so that he can follow up with both Shannon and Humongous Insurance in four weeks to make sure that the claim has been resolved. After four weeks, Luke contacts Shannon. He learns that Humongous Insurance has paid her claims, and that she is happy with the resolution. Luke changes the status of the case to **Closed**.\n\n"}