{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,98],"content":"System diagnostics (Lifecycle Services) (AX 2012) | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"System diagnostics (Lifecycle Services) (AX 2012) | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,66]}]},{"pos":[508,557],"content":"System diagnostics (Lifecycle Services) (AX 2012)","linkify":"System diagnostics (Lifecycle Services) (AX 2012)","nodes":[{"content":"System diagnostics (Lifecycle Services) (AX 2012)","pos":[0,49]}]},{"content":"In Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services, you can use System diagnostics to monitor your Microsoft Dynamics AX environments.","pos":[559,683]},{"content":"This topic describes the data that you can see after you install the local service component of System diagnostics and discovered one or more Microsoft Dynamics AX environments.","pos":[684,861]},{"content":"For more information about installing the local service component, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Install and run System diagnostics (Lifecycle Services)<ept id=\"p1\">](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/install-and-run-system-diagnostics-lifecycle-services/)</ept>.","pos":[862,1083],"source":" For more information about installing the local service component, see [Install and run System diagnostics (Lifecycle Services)](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/install-and-run-system-diagnostics-lifecycle-services/)."},{"pos":[1088,1111],"content":"Open System diagnostics","linkify":"Open System diagnostics","nodes":[{"content":"Open System diagnostics","pos":[0,23]}]},{"pos":[1116,1169],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Go to Lifecycle Services<ept id=\"p1\">](https://lcs.dynamics.com)</ept>.","source":"[Go to Lifecycle Services](https://lcs.dynamics.com)."},{"content":"Open a project for which you have installed local service component of System diagnostics and discovered one or more Microsoft Dynamics AX environments.","pos":[1174,1326]},{"content":"Click the System diagnostics tile.All data displayed on the dashboard is based on the last run of the local service component.","pos":[1331,1457]},{"pos":[1462,1471],"content":"Dashboard","linkify":"Dashboard","nodes":[{"content":"Dashboard","pos":[0,9]}]},{"content":"The dashboard provides a visual indication of the number of hosts (servers running AOS instances or database servers) in the selected environment that encountered errors when running rules, and displays the last 5 messages.","pos":[1472,1695]},{"content":"It also indicates whether any collector jobs encountered errors while running.","pos":[1696,1774]},{"pos":[1779,1787],"content":"Messages","linkify":"Messages","nodes":[{"content":"Messages","pos":[0,8]}]},{"content":"The Messages page displays the errors and warnings about rules conditions that were detected by System diagnostics after the last set of data collector jobs were run.","pos":[1788,1954]},{"content":"When you select a rule, you can see details about the rule and the condition that triggered it at the bottom of the page.","pos":[1955,2076]},{"content":"Using filters, you can choose to display failed rules, passed rules, ignored rules, or all rules.","pos":[2077,2174]},{"content":"You can choose rules to ignore by clicking Ignore rule.","pos":[2175,2230]},{"content":"To show an ignored rule again, in the Show filter, select Rule ignored, select the rule, and click Show rule.","pos":[2231,2340]},{"pos":[2345,2357],"content":"Environments","linkify":"Environments","nodes":[{"content":"Environments","pos":[0,12]}]},{"content":"The Environments page displays a list of the environments that were discovered by System diagnostics.","pos":[2358,2459]},{"content":"Each environment tile indicates the time that the last data collector job was run, and whether any rule violations were encountered.","pos":[2460,2592]},{"pos":[2597,2601],"content":"Jobs","linkify":"Jobs","nodes":[{"content":"Jobs","pos":[0,4]}]},{"content":"The Jobs page lists the status of the collections jobs, and the servers that they ran on.","pos":[2602,2691]},{"pos":[2696,2706],"content":"Collectors","linkify":"Collectors","nodes":[{"content":"Collectors","pos":[0,10]}]},{"content":"The Collectors page enables you to view the diagnostic data most recently collected from your Microsoft Dynamics AX environment.","pos":[2707,2835]},{"content":"You can browse or search to find a specific collector.","pos":[2836,2890]},{"pos":[2895,2901],"content":"Report","linkify":"Report","nodes":[{"content":"Report","pos":[0,6]}]},{"content":"The Report page provides detailed information about the environment, as well as any issues that were detected.","pos":[2902,3012]},{"content":"You can right-click the Report page to export the report to an HTML file.","pos":[3013,3086]},{"pos":[3091,3096],"content":"Admin","linkify":"Admin","nodes":[{"content":"Admin","pos":[0,5]}]},{"content":"The Admin page is used to manage certificates and to download the on-premises installer.","pos":[3097,3185]}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: System diagnostics (Lifecycle Services) (AX 2012) | Microsoft Docs\ndescription: \nauthor: annbe\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 2015-12-05 23:26:56\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Lifecycle Services\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# keywords: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \n# ms.reviewer: \nms.suite: AX 2012\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 19041\nms.assetid: 4f88a0aa-e774-4cfe-8828-3662a4e9e25f\n# ms.region: \n# ms.industry: \nms.author: kfend\n\n---\n\n# System diagnostics (Lifecycle Services) (AX 2012)\n\nIn Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services, you can use System diagnostics to monitor your Microsoft Dynamics AX environments. This topic describes the data that you can see after you install the local service component of System diagnostics and discovered one or more Microsoft Dynamics AX environments. For more information about installing the local service component, see [Install and run System diagnostics (Lifecycle Services)](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/install-and-run-system-diagnostics-lifecycle-services/).\n\n## Open System diagnostics\n1.  [Go to Lifecycle Services](https://lcs.dynamics.com).\n2.  Open a project for which you have installed local service component of System diagnostics and discovered one or more Microsoft Dynamics AX environments.\n3.  Click the System diagnostics tile.All data displayed on the dashboard is based on the last run of the local service component.\n\n## Dashboard\nThe dashboard provides a visual indication of the number of hosts (servers running AOS instances or database servers) in the selected environment that encountered errors when running rules, and displays the last 5 messages. It also indicates whether any collector jobs encountered errors while running.\n\n## Messages\nThe Messages page displays the errors and warnings about rules conditions that were detected by System diagnostics after the last set of data collector jobs were run. When you select a rule, you can see details about the rule and the condition that triggered it at the bottom of the page. Using filters, you can choose to display failed rules, passed rules, ignored rules, or all rules. You can choose rules to ignore by clicking Ignore rule. To show an ignored rule again, in the Show filter, select Rule ignored, select the rule, and click Show rule.\n\n## Environments\nThe Environments page displays a list of the environments that were discovered by System diagnostics. Each environment tile indicates the time that the last data collector job was run, and whether any rule violations were encountered.\n\n## Jobs\nThe Jobs page lists the status of the collections jobs, and the servers that they ran on.\n\n## Collectors\nThe Collectors page enables you to view the diagnostic data most recently collected from your Microsoft Dynamics AX environment. You can browse or search to find a specific collector.\n\n## Report\nThe Report page provides detailed information about the environment, as well as any issues that were detected. You can right-click the Report page to export the report to an HTML file.\n\n## Admin\nThe Admin page is used to manage certificates and to download the on-premises installer.\n\n\n\n"}