{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Finance and Operations glossary\ndescription: The Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations glossary defines key terms and concepts in the Finance and Operations product. \nauthor: tonyafehr\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 04/04/2017\nms.topic: business-process\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: annbe\nms.search.scope: AX 7.0.0, Operations, Core\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 44101\nms.assetid: d4e01957-69a0-4c92-91c5-4646c8b0cad8\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: tfehr\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Finance and Operations glossary\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThe Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations glossary defines key terms and concepts in the Finance and Operations product. \n\n### **A**\n\n###### **accounting journal**\n\nA journal that is used to record the financial consequences of accounting events in an accounting system.\n\n###### **accounting rule**\n\nA rule in an accounting system that controls the principles, methods, and procedures for classifying, recording, and reporting the financial consequences of accounting events.\n\n###### **ACH (Automated Clearing House)**\n\nAn electronic funds transfer system available in the United States that facilitates the transfer of funds between receiving party and originating party bank accounts.\n\n###### **actual quantity**\n\nThe measured quantity that is input into or output from an activity.\n\n###### **address verification service**\n\nThe service that is provided by a credit card processor that validates that the billing address provided by a card holder matches the information on file with the issuing bank.\n\n###### **adjusted unit price**\n\nThe calculated unit price based on the attribute-based pricing and the actual potency received.\n\n###### **advanced pricing**\n\nLogic used to calculate the purchase price of a potency item.\n\n###### **aging**\n\nThe process of classifying time periods by age.\n\n###### **aging period**\n\nThe number of days in a time period used to report an overdue customer payment balance.\n\n### **B**\n\n###### **balance sheet**\n\nA statement of the financial position of an organization that reports the state of assets, liabilities, and equity on a specified date.\n\n###### **balance sheet account**\n\nAn account that describes the changes in value reported on a balance sheet.\n\n###### **bank reconciliation**\n\nA practice of reconciling a ledger account that represents a bank account by matching ledger account entries to bank statement entries.\n\n###### **batch attribute**\n\nA product attribute of a process batch or a transfer batch.\n\n###### **best before date**\n\nA recommended date for obtaining the optimum quality or characteristic of a product.\n\n###### **best before period**\n\nThe time period in which to obtain the optimum quality or characteristic of a product.\n\n###### **bill of exchange**\n\nA source document that documents an unconditional request for a third-party to pay a second party on demand.\n\n###### **bill of materials**\n\nA list of products and their quantities that are required to produce one product.\n\n###### **blocking**\n\nThe action of placing a document or product on hold.\n\n###### **budget control**\n\nA practice of authorizing expenditure only when budget funds can be reserved to meet future payment commitments.\n\n###### **budget control dimension**\n\nA combination of active financial dimensions values used to allocate budget funds to pay for planned activities.\n\n###### **budget control rule**\n\nThe encoding of a business decision to check committed and actual expenditure against available budget funds allocated for detailed or aggregate activities defined by valid budget control dimension value combinations.\n\n###### **budget cycle time span**\n\nA time period specified as a number of fiscal calendar periods. The budget period can be different from the accounting period.\n\n###### **budget group**\n\nA set of financial dimension values in a budget dimension hierarchy that is used to calculate aggregate budget funds allocated to superordinate financial dimension values by summing budget funds allocated to subordinate financial dimension values.\n\n###### **budget model**\n\nA planning structure used to schedule budget fund allocations and expenditures.\n\n###### **bulk item**\n\nA formula item input into a product delivery activity.\n\n###### **bundle**\n\nThe combination of a number of products for sale as one unit.\n\n###### **business unit**\n\nA semi-autonomous operating unit that is created to meet strategic business objectives.\n\n### **C**\n\n###### **capacity load**\n\nThe maximum amount of scheduled work that a work center can perform at a required capacity level.\n\n###### **capacity planning**\n\nA procedure for determining the resource capacity requirements that meet the demand of future output during specific time periods.\n\n###### **carry-forward budget**\n\nThe budget that is transferred from one fiscal year to the next and that is reserved for open purchase orders in the new fiscal year.\n\n###### **cash-generating unit**\n\nThe smallest group of classifiable assets that generates cash independently of other assets within an organization. These groups of assets are used to measure impairment losses that will be incurred.\n\n###### **catch weight**\n\nThe actual or nominal weight of a sales item or inventory item.\n\n###### **chart of accounts**\n\nA list of main accounts.\n\n###### **COGS (cost of goods sold)**\n\nAn accounting category used to sum the financial consequences of manufacturing products and carrying inventory.\n\n###### **commodity pricing**\n\nA pricing strategy for updating the price of sales items produced from commodities subject to frequent price changes.\n\n###### **consolidated order**\n\nA source document that documents more than one referenced order.\n\n###### **contractor**\n\nA role assumed by a person who participates in a contractor-employer relationship with a legal entity.\n\n###### **co-product**\n\nAn item produced jointly with another item.\n\n###### **cost center**\n\nAn operating unit whose managers are accountable for budgeted and actual expenditures.\n\n###### **cost of goods sold**\n\nAn accounting category used to sum the financial consequences of manufacturing products and carrying inventory.\n\n###### **cost variance**\n\nThe difference between an expected cost and an actual cost.\n\n###### **costing**\n\nThe process of calculating, assigning, and allocating the cost of economic resources acquired, produced, or delivered by an organization.\n\n###### **CTP (capable-to-promise)**\n\nThe portion of product output from available operations resources and available input product required to fulfill a specific customer requirement.\n\n###### **currency code**\n\nAn alphanumeric identifier that represents a currency unit.\n\n###### **cycle time**\n\nThe time taken to complete an activity.\n\n### **D**\n\n###### **dashboard**\n\nThe typical start page in Finance and Operations. On the dashboard, users see a section for each workspace that they have access to. Each section displays the tiles from the summary sections in the related workspace. The dashboard consists of a name and sections with tiles.\n\n###### **data entity**\n\nAn information structure that represents the data characteristic of an entity.\n\n###### **delegate**\n\nA delegate is a type that represents references to methods with a particular parameter list and return type.\n\n###### **delivery note**\n\nA business document that documents the delivery of products between two parties.\n\n###### **demand forecast**\n\nA prediction of future product demand.\n\n###### **demand forecasting**\n\nA business process that estimates future demand and creates demand forecasts based on historical transaction data.\n\n###### **deployable package**\n\nThe vehicle used for deployment on User Acceptance Test (UAT) and production environments.\n\n###### **designer**\n\nA Visual Studio tool that you used to create, update, and inspect your model elements.\n\n###### **dimension-based product configuration**\n\nA configuration technology used to create product variants by selecting values for product dimensions.\n\n###### **distinct product**\n\nA uniquely identifiable product.\n\n###### **document blocking**\n\nA method of placing an operations process on hold while ordered items are in a quality assurance process.\n\n###### **document management system**\n\nAn application service for storing and handling an organization's documents.\n\n###### **duty**\n\nIn the security model, a set of application access privileges that are required for a user to carry out their responsibilities.\n\n### **E**\n\n###### **EFT (electronic funds transfer)**\n\nA networked system for transferring funds from one bank account to another.\n\n###### **event**\n\nAn event lets a class or object to notify other classes or objects when something of interest occurs.\n\n###### **EPE (Every Product Every)**\n\nA lean concept that is used to establish a regular repeating production cycle.\n\n###### **extension**\n\nCustomizing an application by adding functionality to existing code.\n\n### **F**\n\n###### **financial dimension**\n\nA financial data classifier created from the parties, locations, products, and activities in an organization and used for management reporting.\n\n###### **financial dimension value**\n\nA data element in the domain of a financial dimension.\n\n###### **financial statement**\n\nA report that documents the financial information and financial position of an organization.\n\n###### **fixed cost**\n\nA cost that does not vary with changes in product delivery throughput or output.\n\n###### **fixed currency**\n\nA currency that has a fixed exchange rate in relation to another currency.\n\n###### **fixed quantity kanban**\n\nA type of kanban that is used when the number of kanbans that are assigned to a kanban rule is constant.\n\n###### **flexible authentication**\n\nAn authentication process where users in a variety of identity management systems can be authenticated.\n\n###### **formula**\n\nA numeric relationship among production process inputs and production process outputs.\n\n###### **formula item**\n\nAn output of a batch process controlled by a formula.\n\n### **G**\n\n###### **general budget reservation**\n\nA document that is often used by public sector entities to set aside or earmark budgeted funds so that those funds are not available for other purposes.\n\n###### **grace period**\n\nThe time period beyond a specified date during which an obligation can be fulfilled without penalty.\n\n###### **GST (goods and services tax)**\n\nA value-added tax levied in some countries/regions.\n\n### **I**\n\n###### **intercompany**\n\nOccurring between or relating two or more legal entities that are part the same organization that consolidates the accounts of all legal entities.\n\n###### **invoice matching**\n\nA practice of matching vendor invoice prices and product quantities to purchase orders and product receipts.\n\n###### **item allocation key**\n\nA product family grouping that is used for forecast and demand scheduling.\n\n###### **item relation**\n\nA reference to the item allocation group or the item and its product dimensions in a kanban rule.\n\n### **K**\n\n###### **kanban**\n\nA signal that communicates a requirement for a quantity of product.\n\n###### **kanban flow**\n\nDefines the sequence of activities that are performed for kanbans that are created for a kanban rule.\n\n###### **kanban job**\n\nA process or transfer activity in a production flow that is triggered by a Kanban.\n\n###### **kanban job consumption**\n\nThe withdrawal of product components from inventory in order to complete the kanban production jobs.\n\n###### **kanban product quantity**\n\nThe number of item requirements that are carried on a kanban based on a kanban rule.\n\n###### **kanban rule**\n\nA rule in a lean manufacturing system that realizes material planning and replenishment policies by controlling how process and transfer activities are coordinated in production flows.\n\n### **L**\n\n###### **lean manufacturing**\n\nA philosophy in which manufacturing operations promote lean production flows and business activities.\n\n###### **lean schedule group**\n\nA way in which to aggregate items for production, for example, based on a setup group, shipping group, or transport group.\n\n###### **ledger account**\n\nA classifier created from the combination of main account value and other financial dimension values listed in a chart of accounts and used to classify the financial consequences of economic activity.\n\n###### **license code**\n\nAn alphanumeric key that grants a party the right to use software or software components as prescribed in the terms of the license agreement, and that activates and inactivates software modules, software capabilities, and software functions.\n\n###### **liquidity**\n\nThe ability of a party to use current assets to settle current liabilities.\n\n### **M**\n\n###### **manufacturing overhead based on material**\n\nManufacturing overhead is expressed as indirect cost-calculation formulas for a surcharge percentage. A cost group that is assigned to material components acts as the basis for a calculation formula. Calculation formulas can be defined for individual products or for item groups that are assigned to products, to provide more flexibility in calculating manufacturing overhead that is based on material.\n\n###### **master scheduling**\n\nThe process for generating a timetable for matching supply with demand.\n\n###### **model**\n\nA model contains code elements and reference metadata. It is created and inspected in Visual Studio.\n\n###### **model element**\n\nA model is a group of elements (source files and metadata) that constitutes a distributable software solution. The model is a design-time concept.\n\n### **N**\n\n###### **NBV (net book value)**\n\nThe value of a fixed asset calculated as the difference between the original cost of the fixed asset minus its accumulated depreciations.\n\n### **O**\n\n###### **object permission**\n\nA permitted create, read, update, delete, or execute operation on a securable object.\n\n###### **operating unit**\n\nAn organization that divides the control of economic resources and operational processes among people who have a duty to maximize the use of scarce resources, to improve processes, and to account for their performance.\n\n###### **output product**\n\nThe physical products that result from an activity.\n\n###### **overlayering**\n\nA method of customizing source code by providing new source code that overrides the default source code.\n\n### **P**\n\n###### **package**\n\nA package is a compilable and deployable unit of one or more models.\n\n###### **party**\n\nAn entity that assumes a legally binding role when participating in contractual relationships.\n\n###### **party**\n\nA person or organization that participates in economic activities.\n\n###### **pegging**\n\nThe process of tracing the quantity of a required item to its source.\n\n###### **pegging event**\n\nA resource flow event that signals the demand for a product.\n\n###### **phantom item**\n\nAn item that is produced but not stocked.\n\n###### **planned intercompany demand**\n\nPredicted demand for a product by a legal entity that assumes the role of a vendor. The planned demand is generated from planned demand for the product from a downstream legal entity.\n\n###### **post**\n\nTo record the monetary value of an economic event in a specific account, or to summarize and reclassify general and subsidiary journal account entries into general and subsidiary ledger account entries.\n\n###### **preparer**\n\nThe person who creates a source document to initiate a request for economic resources.\n\n###### **privilege**\n\nOne or more permissions a user requires to perform a task.\n\n###### **procurement catalog**\n\nA listing of product offerings that are grouped by procurement category. A procurement catalog is used to request products for internal use by an organization.\n\n###### **product component**\n\nA part of a product.\n\n###### **product dimension**\n\nThe size, color, or configuration product attributes that are used for dimension-based product configuration.\n\n###### **product family**\n\nA unique grouping of items, services, or rights that either participates in the same production or delivery activities or that are offered to the same market segments. In Finance and Operations, the grouping is represented by using a forecast allocation key.\n\n###### **product master**\n\nA standard or functional product representation that is the basis for configuring product variants.\n\n###### **product receipt**\n\nA source document that documents the receipt of products ordered, the receipt of products returned, or the receipt of products received on consignment.\n\n###### **product variant**\n\nA configuration of a product master.\n\n###### **production flow**\n\nA production process designed using Lean principles.\n\n###### **production flow model**\n\nA representation of the production capacity provided by a group of work cells in a production flow process.\n\n###### **production order**\n\nA source document that documents the requirements for producing items to meet a demand.\n\n###### **production schedule**\n\nA schedule to produce a specific item and item quantity at a specific time and by specific human and operational resources.\n\n###### **prospect**\n\nA participant that has the existing and potential ability to provide a service or probable future economic benefit to a legal entity.\n\n###### **purchase agreement policy**\n\nA policy that authorizes parties to modify purchase agreement terms.\n\n###### **purchase order policy**\n\nA policy that authorizes parties to modify purchase order terms and to control order processing.\n\n###### **purchase quotation**\n\nA source document that documents an offer to purchase a quantity of product for a specified price and by a specified date in response to a request for quotation in a procurement process.\n\n###### **purchase requisition**\n\nA source document that documents product requests so that they can be submitted for review and be used to authorize purchasing by a purchasing organization.\n\n### **Q**\n\n###### **quantity variance**\n\nThe difference between an ordered product quantity and a received product quantity when no more receipts are expected.\n\n### **R**\n\n###### **receipt advice**\n\nA business document that documents a summary of the products a buyer receives from a vendor.\n\n###### **reconciliation**\n\nA practice of adjusting two or more accounts or statements so that the figures agree.\n\n###### **reduction key**\n\nA method that is used to increase or decrease forecast requirements in master planning, based on user defined percentages that are applied during specific periods.\n\n###### **register**\n\nA record that is used to record the operational, legal, and financial consequences of resource flow events in an accounting system.\n\n###### **regulated product**\n\nA product that is regulated by a government authority that requires compliance and audit reporting.\n\n###### **RFQ (request for quotation**\n\nA source document that documents an invitation to bid on supplying a quantity of product for a specified price and by a specified date.\n\n###### **requester**\n\nThe person who requests the economic resources.\n\n###### **restricted product**\n\nA product whose distribution is limited or constrained by a government authority.\n\n### **S**\n\n###### **sales agreement**\n\nA source document that documents an agreement between two or more parties based on an understanding that a selling party will commit to selling a specific quantity or value of product over a period of time in exchange for favorable prices and discounts.\n\n###### **sales agreement policy**\n\nA policy that authorizes parties to modify sales agreement terms.\n\n###### **sales order policy**\n\nA policy that authorizes parties to modify sales order terms and to control order processing and payment processes.\n\n###### **sales quotation**\n\nA source document that documents an offer to supply a quantity of product for a specified price and by a specified date in response to a request for quotation in a sales process.\n\n###### **security role**\n\nA defined set of application access privileges. The security role assigned to a user determines which tasks the user can perform and which parts of the user interface the user can view. All users must be assigned at least one security role in order to access the system.\n\n###### **segregation of duties**\n\nA design principle used to reduce the risk of fraud, irregularities, and errors that separates the recording, verification, authorization, custody of assets, and periodic review duties of people who participate in, document, or record the financial consequences of economic transactions.\n\n###### **sequencing**\n\nThe order in which jobs are processed or operations are performed at a manufacturing facility to achieve objectives.\n\n###### **shared asset**\n\nAn asset that is used by more than one cash-generating unit (CGU). An example is a distribution center that is used to store items before they are transported to different markets that share that same distribution center.\n\n###### **single use kanban**\n\nA type of kanban that is used with a fixed quantity kanban rule to meet exceptionally high demand. A single use kanban does not trigger a new kanban when it is discarded.\n\n###### **smart rounding**\n\nA marketing practice to use odd numbers that are marginally less than their nearest round number to set prices.\n\n###### **source requirement**\n\nThe product quantity documented on a source document line that creates a pegging requirement.\n\n###### **statistical baseline forecast**\n\nAn estimate of future demand that is created by applying a forecasting algorithm to historical transaction data.\n\n###### **supermarket**\n\nA just-in-time inventory location that has finite capacity and is used to batch material near a point of consumption.\n\n###### **system-defined financial dimension type**\n\nA financial dimension mapped to a table or view in the database that represents an entity type and whose values are in the domain of one attribute of that entity type.\n\n### **T**\n\n###### **takt time**\n\nThe time that it takes to produce one unit of a product.\n\n###### **Task guide**\n\nA controlled, guided experience through the steps in a Task recording. A Task guide leads the user through the experience that was recorded. All security, data, and application behaviors are the same when completing a Task guide as they are without the Task guide. The Task guide uses the same instrumentation as Task recorder to know when a user has completed the intended step, so that it can prompt the user to take the next step in the recording.\n\n###### **Task recorder**\n\nA tool that is pre-installed in Finance and Operations. When recording, it records all events that the user enters in the Finance and Operations user interface that get executed against the server—including values added, settings changed, data removed, etc.\n\n###### **Task recording**\n\nA file that contains the actions and annotations that are captured when Task recorder is run in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations.\n\n###### **three-way matching policy**\n\nA matching policy that requires one or more vendor invoice prices to match with one or more purchase order prices and that requires one or more vendor invoice quantities to match with one or more product receipt quantities.\n\n###### **transfer batch**\n\nThe quantity of one or more items that is transferred or that can be transferred.\n\n###### **two-way matching policy**\n\nA matching policy that requires one or more vendor invoice prices to match with one or more purchase order prices.\n\n### **U**\n\n###### **user-defined financial dimension type**\n\nA financial dimension mapped to a user-defined list of values.\n\n### **V**\n\n###### **value stream**\n\nAn operating unit that controls one or more production flows.\n\n###### **variant configuration technology**\n\nA method of modeling product masters and searching for product variant configurations.\n\n###### **VAT (value-added tax)**\n\nA tax on products at each stage of their production based on the value added during that stage.\n\n###### **vendor catalog**\n\nA listing of product offerings that are available for purchase from a vendor.\n\n###### **vendor invoice**\n\nA source document that documents a vendor payment request. A vendor invoice can refer to one or more purchase orders. When the vendor invoice is authorized, a payment can be made to the vendor.\n\n### **W**\n\n###### **work cell**\n\nA resource group that participates in a production flow activity.\n\n###### **worker**\n\nA person who assumes the role of an employee or a contractor and is paid in exchange for services.\n\n###### **workspace**\n\nA page that provides an overview of one of the activities that the user performs. The page uses tiles, lists, and charts to display pending work and related data from multiple sources, and the page surfaces frequent tasks related to this data. Tiles shown in the summary section of the workspace are also displayed in the related section in the dashboard.\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"content":"Finance and Operations glossary","nodes":[{"pos":[0,31],"content":"Finance and Operations glossary","nodes":[{"content":"Finance and Operations glossary","pos":[0,31]}]}],"pos":[31,63],"yaml":true},{"content":"The Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations glossary defines key terms and concepts in the Finance and Operations product.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,132],"content":"The Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations glossary defines key terms and concepts in the Finance and Operations product.","nodes":[{"content":"The Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations glossary defines key terms and concepts in the Finance and Operations product.","pos":[0,132]}]}],"pos":[76,209],"yaml":true},{"pos":[732,763],"content":"Finance and Operations glossary","linkify":"Finance and Operations glossary","nodes":[{"content":"Finance and Operations glossary","pos":[0,31]}]},{"content":"The Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations glossary defines key terms and concepts in the Finance and Operations product.","pos":[809,941]},{"pos":[948,953],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>A<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**A**","source":"**A**"},{"pos":[962,984],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>accounting journal<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**accounting journal**","source":"**accounting journal**"},{"content":"A journal that is used to record the financial consequences of accounting events in an accounting system.","pos":[986,1091]},{"pos":[1100,1119],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>accounting rule<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**accounting rule**","source":"**accounting rule**"},{"content":"A rule in an accounting system that controls the principles, methods, and procedures for classifying, recording, and reporting the financial consequences of accounting events.","pos":[1121,1296]},{"pos":[1305,1339],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ACH (Automated Clearing House)<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**ACH (Automated Clearing House)**","source":"**ACH (Automated Clearing House)**"},{"content":"An electronic funds transfer system available in the United States that facilitates the transfer of funds between receiving party and originating party bank accounts.","pos":[1341,1507]},{"pos":[1516,1535],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>actual quantity<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**actual quantity**","source":"**actual quantity**"},{"content":"The measured quantity that is input into or output from an activity.","pos":[1537,1605]},{"pos":[1614,1646],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>address verification service<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**address verification service**","source":"**address verification service**"},{"content":"The service that is provided by a credit card processor that validates that the billing address provided by a card holder matches the information on file with the issuing bank.","pos":[1648,1824]},{"pos":[1833,1856],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>adjusted unit price<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**adjusted unit price**","source":"**adjusted unit price**"},{"content":"The calculated unit price based on the attribute-based pricing and the actual potency received.","pos":[1858,1953]},{"pos":[1962,1982],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>advanced pricing<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**advanced pricing**","source":"**advanced pricing**"},{"content":"Logic used to calculate the purchase price of a potency item.","pos":[1984,2045]},{"pos":[2054,2063],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>aging<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**aging**","source":"**aging**"},{"content":"The process of classifying time periods by age.","pos":[2065,2112]},{"pos":[2121,2137],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>aging period<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**aging period**","source":"**aging period**"},{"content":"The number of days in a time period used to report an overdue customer payment balance.","pos":[2139,2226]},{"pos":[2232,2237],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>B<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**B**","source":"**B**"},{"pos":[2246,2263],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>balance sheet<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**balance sheet**","source":"**balance sheet**"},{"content":"A statement of the financial position of an organization that reports the state of assets, liabilities, and equity on a specified date.","pos":[2265,2400]},{"pos":[2409,2434],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>balance sheet account<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**balance sheet account**","source":"**balance sheet account**"},{"content":"An account that describes the changes in value reported on a balance sheet.","pos":[2436,2511]},{"pos":[2520,2543],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>bank reconciliation<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**bank reconciliation**","source":"**bank reconciliation**"},{"content":"A practice of reconciling a ledger account that represents a bank account by matching ledger account entries to bank statement entries.","pos":[2545,2680]},{"pos":[2689,2708],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>batch attribute<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**batch attribute**","source":"**batch attribute**"},{"content":"A product attribute of a process batch or a transfer batch.","pos":[2710,2769]},{"pos":[2778,2798],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>best before date<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**best before date**","source":"**best before date**"},{"content":"A recommended date for obtaining the optimum quality or characteristic of a product.","pos":[2800,2884]},{"pos":[2893,2915],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>best before period<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**best before period**","source":"**best before period**"},{"content":"The time period in which to obtain the optimum quality or characteristic of a product.","pos":[2917,3003]},{"pos":[3012,3032],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>bill of exchange<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**bill of exchange**","source":"**bill of exchange**"},{"content":"A source document that documents an unconditional request for a third-party to pay a second party on demand.","pos":[3034,3142]},{"pos":[3151,3172],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>bill of materials<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**bill of materials**","source":"**bill of materials**"},{"content":"A list of products and their quantities that are required to produce one product.","pos":[3174,3255]},{"pos":[3264,3276],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>blocking<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**blocking**","source":"**blocking**"},{"content":"The action of placing a document or product on hold.","pos":[3278,3330]},{"pos":[3339,3357],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>budget control<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**budget control**","source":"**budget control**"},{"content":"A practice of authorizing expenditure only when budget funds can be reserved to meet future payment commitments.","pos":[3359,3471]},{"pos":[3480,3508],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>budget control dimension<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**budget control dimension**","source":"**budget control dimension**"},{"content":"A combination of active financial dimensions values used to allocate budget funds to pay for planned activities.","pos":[3510,3622]},{"pos":[3631,3654],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>budget control rule<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**budget control rule**","source":"**budget control rule**"},{"content":"The encoding of a business decision to check committed and actual expenditure against available budget funds allocated for detailed or aggregate activities defined by valid budget control dimension value combinations.","pos":[3656,3873]},{"pos":[3882,3908],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>budget cycle time span<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**budget cycle time span**","source":"**budget cycle time span**"},{"content":"A time period specified as a number of fiscal calendar periods.","pos":[3910,3973]},{"content":"The budget period can be different from the accounting period.","pos":[3974,4036]},{"pos":[4045,4061],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>budget group<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**budget group**","source":"**budget group**"},{"content":"A set of financial dimension values in a budget dimension hierarchy that is used to calculate aggregate budget funds allocated to superordinate financial dimension values by summing budget funds allocated to subordinate financial dimension values.","pos":[4063,4310]},{"pos":[4319,4335],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>budget model<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**budget model**","source":"**budget model**"},{"content":"A planning structure used to schedule budget fund allocations and expenditures.","pos":[4337,4416]},{"pos":[4425,4438],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>bulk item<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**bulk item**","source":"**bulk item**"},{"content":"A formula item input into a product delivery activity.","pos":[4440,4494]},{"pos":[4503,4513],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>bundle<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**bundle**","source":"**bundle**"},{"content":"The combination of a number of products for sale as one unit.","pos":[4515,4576]},{"pos":[4585,4602],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>business unit<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**business unit**","source":"**business unit**"},{"content":"A semi-autonomous operating unit that is created to meet strategic business objectives.","pos":[4604,4691]},{"pos":[4697,4702],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>C<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**C**","source":"**C**"},{"pos":[4711,4728],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>capacity load<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**capacity load**","source":"**capacity load**"},{"content":"The maximum amount of scheduled work that a work center can perform at a required capacity level.","pos":[4730,4827]},{"pos":[4836,4857],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>capacity planning<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**capacity planning**","source":"**capacity planning**"},{"content":"A procedure for determining the resource capacity requirements that meet the demand of future output during specific time periods.","pos":[4859,4989]},{"pos":[4998,5022],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>carry-forward budget<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**carry-forward budget**","source":"**carry-forward budget**"},{"content":"The budget that is transferred from one fiscal year to the next and that is reserved for open purchase orders in the new fiscal year.","pos":[5024,5157]},{"pos":[5166,5190],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>cash-generating unit<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**cash-generating unit**","source":"**cash-generating unit**"},{"content":"The smallest group of classifiable assets that generates cash independently of other assets within an organization.","pos":[5192,5307]},{"content":"These groups of assets are used to measure impairment losses that will be incurred.","pos":[5308,5391]},{"pos":[5400,5416],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>catch weight<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**catch weight**","source":"**catch weight**"},{"content":"The actual or nominal weight of a sales item or inventory item.","pos":[5418,5481]},{"pos":[5490,5511],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>chart of accounts<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**chart of accounts**","source":"**chart of accounts**"},{"content":"A list of main accounts.","pos":[5513,5537]},{"pos":[5546,5575],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>COGS (cost of goods sold)<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**COGS (cost of goods sold)**","source":"**COGS (cost of goods sold)**"},{"content":"An accounting category used to sum the financial consequences of manufacturing products and carrying inventory.","pos":[5577,5688]},{"pos":[5697,5718],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>commodity pricing<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**commodity pricing**","source":"**commodity pricing**"},{"content":"A pricing strategy for updating the price of sales items produced from commodities subject to frequent price changes.","pos":[5720,5837]},{"pos":[5846,5868],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>consolidated order<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**consolidated order**","source":"**consolidated order**"},{"content":"A source document that documents more than one referenced order.","pos":[5870,5934]},{"pos":[5943,5957],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>contractor<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**contractor**","source":"**contractor**"},{"content":"A role assumed by a person who participates in a contractor-employer relationship with a legal entity.","pos":[5959,6061]},{"pos":[6070,6084],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>co-product<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**co-product**","source":"**co-product**"},{"content":"An item produced jointly with another item.","pos":[6086,6129]},{"pos":[6138,6153],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>cost center<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**cost center**","source":"**cost center**"},{"content":"An operating unit whose managers are accountable for budgeted and actual expenditures.","pos":[6155,6241]},{"pos":[6250,6272],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>cost of goods sold<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**cost of goods sold**","source":"**cost of goods sold**"},{"content":"An accounting category used to sum the financial consequences of manufacturing products and carrying inventory.","pos":[6274,6385]},{"pos":[6394,6411],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>cost variance<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**cost variance**","source":"**cost variance**"},{"content":"The difference between an expected cost and an actual cost.","pos":[6413,6472]},{"pos":[6481,6492],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>costing<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**costing**","source":"**costing**"},{"content":"The process of calculating, assigning, and allocating the cost of economic resources acquired, produced, or delivered by an organization.","pos":[6494,6631]},{"pos":[6640,6668],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>CTP (capable-to-promise)<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**CTP (capable-to-promise)**","source":"**CTP (capable-to-promise)**"},{"content":"The portion of product output from available operations resources and available input product required to fulfill a specific customer requirement.","pos":[6670,6816]},{"pos":[6825,6842],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>currency code<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**currency code**","source":"**currency code**"},{"content":"An alphanumeric identifier that represents a currency unit.","pos":[6844,6903]},{"pos":[6912,6926],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>cycle time<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**cycle time**","source":"**cycle time**"},{"content":"The time taken to complete an activity.","pos":[6928,6967]},{"pos":[6973,6978],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>D<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**D**","source":"**D**"},{"pos":[6987,7000],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>dashboard<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**dashboard**","source":"**dashboard**"},{"content":"The typical start page in Finance and Operations.","pos":[7002,7051]},{"content":"On the dashboard, users see a section for each workspace that they have access to.","pos":[7052,7134]},{"content":"Each section displays the tiles from the summary sections in the related workspace.","pos":[7135,7218]},{"content":"The dashboard consists of a name and sections with tiles.","pos":[7219,7276]},{"pos":[7285,7300],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>data entity<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**data entity**","source":"**data entity**"},{"content":"An information structure that represents the data characteristic of an entity.","pos":[7302,7380]},{"pos":[7389,7401],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>delegate<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**delegate**","source":"**delegate**"},{"content":"A delegate is a type that represents references to methods with a particular parameter list and return type.","pos":[7403,7511]},{"pos":[7520,7537],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>delivery note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**delivery note**","source":"**delivery note**"},{"content":"A business document that documents the delivery of products between two parties.","pos":[7539,7619]},{"pos":[7628,7647],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>demand forecast<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**demand forecast**","source":"**demand forecast**"},{"content":"A prediction of future product demand.","pos":[7649,7687]},{"pos":[7696,7718],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>demand forecasting<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**demand forecasting**","source":"**demand forecasting**"},{"content":"A business process that estimates future demand and creates demand forecasts based on historical transaction data.","pos":[7720,7834]},{"pos":[7843,7865],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>deployable package<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**deployable package**","source":"**deployable package**"},{"content":"The vehicle used for deployment on User Acceptance Test (UAT) and production environments.","pos":[7867,7957]},{"pos":[7966,7978],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>designer<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**designer**","source":"**designer**"},{"content":"A Visual Studio tool that you used to create, update, and inspect your model elements.","pos":[7980,8066]},{"pos":[8075,8116],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>dimension-based product configuration<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**dimension-based product configuration**","source":"**dimension-based product configuration**"},{"content":"A configuration technology used to create product variants by selecting values for product dimensions.","pos":[8118,8220]},{"pos":[8229,8249],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>distinct product<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**distinct product**","source":"**distinct product**"},{"content":"A uniquely identifiable product.","pos":[8251,8283]},{"pos":[8292,8313],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>document blocking<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**document blocking**","source":"**document blocking**"},{"content":"A method of placing an operations process on hold while ordered items are in a quality assurance process.","pos":[8315,8420]},{"pos":[8429,8459],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>document management system<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**document management system**","source":"**document management system**"},{"content":"An application service for storing and handling an organization's documents.","pos":[8461,8537]},{"pos":[8546,8554],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>duty<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**duty**","source":"**duty**"},{"content":"In the security model, a set of application access privileges that are required for a user to carry out their responsibilities.","pos":[8556,8683]},{"pos":[8689,8694],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>E<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**E**","source":"**E**"},{"pos":[8703,8738],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>EFT (electronic funds transfer)<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**EFT (electronic funds transfer)**","source":"**EFT (electronic funds transfer)**"},{"content":"A networked system for transferring funds from one bank account to another.","pos":[8740,8815]},{"pos":[8824,8833],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>event<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**event**","source":"**event**"},{"content":"An event lets a class or object to notify other classes or objects when something of interest occurs.","pos":[8835,8936]},{"pos":[8945,8974],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>EPE (Every Product Every)<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**EPE (Every Product Every)**","source":"**EPE (Every Product Every)**"},{"content":"A lean concept that is used to establish a regular repeating production cycle.","pos":[8976,9054]},{"pos":[9063,9076],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>extension<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**extension**","source":"**extension**"},{"content":"Customizing an application by adding functionality to existing code.","pos":[9078,9146]},{"pos":[9152,9157],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>F<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**F**","source":"**F**"},{"pos":[9166,9189],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>financial dimension<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**financial dimension**","source":"**financial dimension**"},{"content":"A financial data classifier created from the parties, locations, products, and activities in an organization and used for management reporting.","pos":[9191,9334]},{"pos":[9343,9372],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>financial dimension value<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**financial dimension value**","source":"**financial dimension value**"},{"content":"A data element in the domain of a financial dimension.","pos":[9374,9428]},{"pos":[9437,9460],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>financial statement<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**financial statement**","source":"**financial statement**"},{"content":"A report that documents the financial information and financial position of an organization.","pos":[9462,9554]},{"pos":[9563,9577],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>fixed cost<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**fixed cost**","source":"**fixed cost**"},{"content":"A cost that does not vary with changes in product delivery throughput or output.","pos":[9579,9659]},{"pos":[9668,9686],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>fixed currency<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**fixed currency**","source":"**fixed currency**"},{"content":"A currency that has a fixed exchange rate in relation to another currency.","pos":[9688,9762]},{"pos":[9771,9796],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>fixed quantity kanban<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**fixed quantity kanban**","source":"**fixed quantity kanban**"},{"content":"A type of kanban that is used when the number of kanbans that are assigned to a kanban rule is constant.","pos":[9798,9902]},{"pos":[9911,9938],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>flexible authentication<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**flexible authentication**","source":"**flexible authentication**"},{"content":"An authentication process where users in a variety of identity management systems can be authenticated.","pos":[9940,10043]},{"pos":[10052,10063],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>formula<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**formula**","source":"**formula**"},{"content":"A numeric relationship among production process inputs and production process outputs.","pos":[10065,10151]},{"pos":[10160,10176],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>formula item<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**formula item**","source":"**formula item**"},{"content":"An output of a batch process controlled by a formula.","pos":[10178,10231]},{"pos":[10237,10242],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>G<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**G**","source":"**G**"},{"pos":[10251,10281],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>general budget reservation<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**general budget reservation**","source":"**general budget reservation**"},{"content":"A document that is often used by public sector entities to set aside or earmark budgeted funds so that those funds are not available for other purposes.","pos":[10283,10435]},{"pos":[10444,10460],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>grace period<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**grace period**","source":"**grace period**"},{"content":"The time period beyond a specified date during which an obligation can be fulfilled without penalty.","pos":[10462,10562]},{"pos":[10571,10603],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>GST (goods and services tax)<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**GST (goods and services tax)**","source":"**GST (goods and services tax)**"},{"content":"A value-added tax levied in some countries/regions.","pos":[10605,10656]},{"pos":[10662,10667],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>I<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**I**","source":"**I**"},{"pos":[10676,10692],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>intercompany<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**intercompany**","source":"**intercompany**"},{"content":"Occurring between or relating two or more legal entities that are part the same organization that consolidates the accounts of all legal entities.","pos":[10694,10840]},{"pos":[10849,10869],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>invoice matching<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**invoice matching**","source":"**invoice matching**"},{"content":"A practice of matching vendor invoice prices and product quantities to purchase orders and product receipts.","pos":[10871,10979]},{"pos":[10988,11011],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>item allocation key<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**item allocation key**","source":"**item allocation key**"},{"content":"A product family grouping that is used for forecast and demand scheduling.","pos":[11013,11087]},{"pos":[11096,11113],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>item relation<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**item relation**","source":"**item relation**"},{"content":"A reference to the item allocation group or the item and its product dimensions in a kanban rule.","pos":[11115,11212]},{"pos":[11218,11223],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>K<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**K**","source":"**K**"},{"pos":[11232,11242],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>kanban<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**kanban**","source":"**kanban**"},{"content":"A signal that communicates a requirement for a quantity of product.","pos":[11244,11311]},{"pos":[11320,11335],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>kanban flow<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**kanban flow**","source":"**kanban flow**"},{"content":"Defines the sequence of activities that are performed for kanbans that are created for a kanban rule.","pos":[11337,11438]},{"pos":[11447,11461],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>kanban job<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**kanban job**","source":"**kanban job**"},{"content":"A process or transfer activity in a production flow that is triggered by a Kanban.","pos":[11463,11545]},{"pos":[11554,11580],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>kanban job consumption<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**kanban job consumption**","source":"**kanban job consumption**"},{"content":"The withdrawal of product components from inventory in order to complete the kanban production jobs.","pos":[11582,11682]},{"pos":[11691,11718],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>kanban product quantity<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**kanban product quantity**","source":"**kanban product quantity**"},{"content":"The number of item requirements that are carried on a kanban based on a kanban rule.","pos":[11720,11804]},{"pos":[11813,11828],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>kanban rule<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**kanban rule**","source":"**kanban rule**"},{"content":"A rule in a lean manufacturing system that realizes material planning and replenishment policies by controlling how process and transfer activities are coordinated in production flows.","pos":[11830,12014]},{"pos":[12020,12025],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>L<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**L**","source":"**L**"},{"pos":[12034,12056],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>lean manufacturing<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**lean manufacturing**","source":"**lean manufacturing**"},{"content":"A philosophy in which manufacturing operations promote lean production flows and business activities.","pos":[12058,12159]},{"pos":[12168,12191],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>lean schedule group<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**lean schedule group**","source":"**lean schedule group**"},{"content":"A way in which to aggregate items for production, for example, based on a setup group, shipping group, or transport group.","pos":[12193,12315]},{"pos":[12324,12342],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ledger account<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**ledger account**","source":"**ledger account**"},{"content":"A classifier created from the combination of main account value and other financial dimension values listed in a chart of accounts and used to classify the financial consequences of economic activity.","pos":[12344,12544]},{"pos":[12553,12569],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>license code<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**license code**","source":"**license code**"},{"content":"An alphanumeric key that grants a party the right to use software or software components as prescribed in the terms of the license agreement, and that activates and inactivates software modules, software capabilities, and software functions.","pos":[12571,12812]},{"pos":[12821,12834],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>liquidity<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**liquidity**","source":"**liquidity**"},{"content":"The ability of a party to use current assets to settle current liabilities.","pos":[12836,12911]},{"pos":[12917,12922],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>M<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**M**","source":"**M**"},{"pos":[12931,12975],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>manufacturing overhead based on material<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**manufacturing overhead based on material**","source":"**manufacturing overhead based on material**"},{"content":"Manufacturing overhead is expressed as indirect cost-calculation formulas for a surcharge percentage.","pos":[12977,13078]},{"content":"A cost group that is assigned to material components acts as the basis for a calculation formula.","pos":[13079,13176]},{"content":"Calculation formulas can be defined for individual products or for item groups that are assigned to products, to provide more flexibility in calculating manufacturing overhead that is based on material.","pos":[13177,13379]},{"pos":[13388,13409],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>master scheduling<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**master scheduling**","source":"**master scheduling**"},{"content":"The process for generating a timetable for matching supply with demand.","pos":[13411,13482]},{"pos":[13491,13500],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>model<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**model**","source":"**model**"},{"content":"A model contains code elements and reference metadata.","pos":[13502,13556]},{"content":"It is created and inspected in Visual Studio.","pos":[13557,13602]},{"pos":[13611,13628],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>model element<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**model element**","source":"**model element**"},{"content":"A model is a group of elements (source files and metadata) that constitutes a distributable software solution.","pos":[13630,13740]},{"content":"The model is a design-time concept.","pos":[13741,13776]},{"pos":[13782,13787],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>N<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**N**","source":"**N**"},{"pos":[13796,13820],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>NBV (net book value)<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**NBV (net book value)**","source":"**NBV (net book value)**"},{"content":"The value of a fixed asset calculated as the difference between the original cost of the fixed asset minus its accumulated depreciations.","pos":[13822,13959]},{"pos":[13965,13970],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>O<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**O**","source":"**O**"},{"pos":[13979,14000],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>object permission<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**object permission**","source":"**object permission**"},{"content":"A permitted create, read, update, delete, or execute operation on a securable object.","pos":[14002,14087]},{"pos":[14096,14114],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>operating unit<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**operating unit**","source":"**operating unit**"},{"content":"An organization that divides the control of economic resources and operational processes among people who have a duty to maximize the use of scarce resources, to improve processes, and to account for their performance.","pos":[14116,14334]},{"pos":[14343,14361],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>output product<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**output product**","source":"**output product**"},{"content":"The physical products that result from an activity.","pos":[14363,14414]},{"pos":[14423,14439],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>overlayering<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**overlayering**","source":"**overlayering**"},{"content":"A method of customizing source code by providing new source code that overrides the default source code.","pos":[14441,14545]},{"pos":[14551,14556],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>P<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**P**","source":"**P**"},{"pos":[14565,14576],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>package<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**package**","source":"**package**"},{"content":"A package is a compilable and deployable unit of one or more models.","pos":[14578,14646]},{"pos":[14655,14664],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>party<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**party**","source":"**party**"},{"content":"An entity that assumes a legally binding role when participating in contractual relationships.","pos":[14666,14760]},{"pos":[14769,14778],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>party<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**party**","source":"**party**"},{"content":"A person or organization that participates in economic activities.","pos":[14780,14846]},{"pos":[14855,14866],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>pegging<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**pegging**","source":"**pegging**"},{"content":"The process of tracing the quantity of a required item to its source.","pos":[14868,14937]},{"pos":[14946,14963],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>pegging event<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**pegging event**","source":"**pegging event**"},{"content":"A resource flow event that signals the demand for a product.","pos":[14965,15025]},{"pos":[15034,15050],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>phantom item<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**phantom item**","source":"**phantom item**"},{"content":"An item that is produced but not stocked.","pos":[15052,15093]},{"pos":[15102,15133],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>planned intercompany demand<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**planned intercompany demand**","source":"**planned intercompany demand**"},{"content":"Predicted demand for a product by a legal entity that assumes the role of a vendor.","pos":[15135,15218]},{"content":"The planned demand is generated from planned demand for the product from a downstream legal entity.","pos":[15219,15318]},{"pos":[15327,15335],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>post<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**post**","source":"**post**"},{"content":"To record the monetary value of an economic event in a specific account, or to summarize and reclassify general and subsidiary journal account entries into general and subsidiary ledger account entries.","pos":[15337,15539]},{"pos":[15548,15560],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>preparer<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**preparer**","source":"**preparer**"},{"content":"The person who creates a source document to initiate a request for economic resources.","pos":[15562,15648]},{"pos":[15657,15670],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>privilege<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**privilege**","source":"**privilege**"},{"content":"One or more permissions a user requires to perform a task.","pos":[15672,15730]},{"pos":[15739,15762],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>procurement catalog<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**procurement catalog**","source":"**procurement catalog**"},{"content":"A listing of product offerings that are grouped by procurement category.","pos":[15764,15836]},{"content":"A procurement catalog is used to request products for internal use by an organization.","pos":[15837,15923]},{"pos":[15932,15953],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>product component<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**product component**","source":"**product component**"},{"content":"A part of a product.","pos":[15955,15975]},{"pos":[15984,16005],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>product dimension<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**product dimension**","source":"**product dimension**"},{"content":"The size, color, or configuration product attributes that are used for dimension-based product configuration.","pos":[16007,16116]},{"pos":[16125,16143],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>product family<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**product family**","source":"**product family**"},{"content":"A unique grouping of items, services, or rights that either participates in the same production or delivery activities or that are offered to the same market segments.","pos":[16145,16312]},{"content":"In Finance and Operations, the grouping is represented by using a forecast allocation key.","pos":[16313,16403]},{"pos":[16412,16430],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>product master<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**product master**","source":"**product master**"},{"content":"A standard or functional product representation that is the basis for configuring product variants.","pos":[16432,16531]},{"pos":[16540,16559],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>product receipt<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**product receipt**","source":"**product receipt**"},{"content":"A source document that documents the receipt of products ordered, the receipt of products returned, or the receipt of products received on consignment.","pos":[16561,16712]},{"pos":[16721,16740],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>product variant<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**product variant**","source":"**product variant**"},{"content":"A configuration of a product master.","pos":[16742,16778]},{"pos":[16787,16806],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>production flow<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**production flow**","source":"**production flow**"},{"content":"A production process designed using Lean principles.","pos":[16808,16860]},{"pos":[16869,16894],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>production flow model<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**production flow model**","source":"**production flow model**"},{"content":"A representation of the production capacity provided by a group of work cells in a production flow process.","pos":[16896,17003]},{"pos":[17012,17032],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>production order<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**production order**","source":"**production order**"},{"content":"A source document that documents the requirements for producing items to meet a demand.","pos":[17034,17121]},{"pos":[17130,17153],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>production schedule<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**production schedule**","source":"**production schedule**"},{"content":"A schedule to produce a specific item and item quantity at a specific time and by specific human and operational resources.","pos":[17155,17278]},{"pos":[17287,17299],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>prospect<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**prospect**","source":"**prospect**"},{"content":"A participant that has the existing and potential ability to provide a service or probable future economic benefit to a legal entity.","pos":[17301,17434]},{"pos":[17443,17472],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>purchase agreement policy<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**purchase agreement policy**","source":"**purchase agreement policy**"},{"content":"A policy that authorizes parties to modify purchase agreement terms.","pos":[17474,17542]},{"pos":[17551,17576],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>purchase order policy<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**purchase order policy**","source":"**purchase order policy**"},{"content":"A policy that authorizes parties to modify purchase order terms and to control order processing.","pos":[17578,17674]},{"pos":[17683,17705],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>purchase quotation<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**purchase quotation**","source":"**purchase quotation**"},{"content":"A source document that documents an offer to purchase a quantity of product for a specified price and by a specified date in response to a request for quotation in a procurement process.","pos":[17707,17893]},{"pos":[17902,17926],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>purchase requisition<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**purchase requisition**","source":"**purchase requisition**"},{"content":"A source document that documents product requests so that they can be submitted for review and be used to authorize purchasing by a purchasing organization.","pos":[17928,18084]},{"pos":[18090,18095],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**Q**","source":"**Q**"},{"pos":[18104,18125],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>quantity variance<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**quantity variance**","source":"**quantity variance**"},{"content":"The difference between an ordered product quantity and a received product quantity when no more receipts are expected.","pos":[18127,18245]},{"pos":[18251,18256],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>R<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**R**","source":"**R**"},{"pos":[18265,18283],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>receipt advice<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**receipt advice**","source":"**receipt advice**"},{"content":"A business document that documents a summary of the products a buyer receives from a vendor.","pos":[18285,18377]},{"pos":[18386,18404],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>reconciliation<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**reconciliation**","source":"**reconciliation**"},{"content":"A practice of adjusting two or more accounts or statements so that the figures agree.","pos":[18406,18491]},{"pos":[18500,18517],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>reduction key<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**reduction key**","source":"**reduction key**"},{"content":"A method that is used to increase or decrease forecast requirements in master planning, based on user defined percentages that are applied during specific periods.","pos":[18519,18682]},{"pos":[18691,18703],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>register<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**register**","source":"**register**"},{"content":"A record that is used to record the operational, legal, and financial consequences of resource flow events in an accounting system.","pos":[18705,18836]},{"pos":[18845,18866],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>regulated product<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**regulated product**","source":"**regulated product**"},{"content":"A product that is regulated by a government authority that requires compliance and audit reporting.","pos":[18868,18967]},{"pos":[18976,19006],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>RFQ (request for quotation<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**RFQ (request for quotation**","source":"**RFQ (request for quotation**"},{"content":"A source document that documents an invitation to bid on supplying a quantity of product for a specified price and by a specified date.","pos":[19008,19143]},{"pos":[19152,19165],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>requester<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**requester**","source":"**requester**"},{"content":"The person who requests the economic resources.","pos":[19167,19214]},{"pos":[19223,19245],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>restricted product<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**restricted product**","source":"**restricted product**"},{"content":"A product whose distribution is limited or constrained by a government authority.","pos":[19247,19328]},{"pos":[19334,19339],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>S<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**S**","source":"**S**"},{"pos":[19348,19367],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>sales agreement<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**sales agreement**","source":"**sales agreement**"},{"content":"A source document that documents an agreement between two or more parties based on an understanding that a selling party will commit to selling a specific quantity or value of product over a period of time in exchange for favorable prices and discounts.","pos":[19369,19622]},{"pos":[19631,19657],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>sales agreement policy<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**sales agreement policy**","source":"**sales agreement policy**"},{"content":"A policy that authorizes parties to modify sales agreement terms.","pos":[19659,19724]},{"pos":[19733,19755],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>sales order policy<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**sales order policy**","source":"**sales order policy**"},{"content":"A policy that authorizes parties to modify sales order terms and to control order processing and payment processes.","pos":[19757,19872]},{"pos":[19881,19900],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>sales quotation<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**sales quotation**","source":"**sales quotation**"},{"content":"A source document that documents an offer to supply a quantity of product for a specified price and by a specified date in response to a request for quotation in a sales process.","pos":[19902,20080]},{"pos":[20089,20106],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>security role<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**security role**","source":"**security role**"},{"content":"A defined set of application access privileges.","pos":[20108,20155]},{"content":"The security role assigned to a user determines which tasks the user can perform and which parts of the user interface the user can view.","pos":[20156,20293]},{"content":"All users must be assigned at least one security role in order to access the system.","pos":[20294,20378]},{"pos":[20387,20412],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>segregation of duties<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**segregation of duties**","source":"**segregation of duties**"},{"content":"A design principle used to reduce the risk of fraud, irregularities, and errors that separates the recording, verification, authorization, custody of assets, and periodic review duties of people who participate in, document, or record the financial consequences of economic transactions.","pos":[20414,20701]},{"pos":[20710,20724],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>sequencing<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**sequencing**","source":"**sequencing**"},{"content":"The order in which jobs are processed or operations are performed at a manufacturing facility to achieve objectives.","pos":[20726,20842]},{"pos":[20851,20867],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>shared asset<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**shared asset**","source":"**shared asset**"},{"content":"An asset that is used by more than one cash-generating unit (CGU).","pos":[20869,20935]},{"content":"An example is a distribution center that is used to store items before they are transported to different markets that share that same distribution center.","pos":[20936,21090]},{"pos":[21099,21120],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>single use kanban<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**single use kanban**","source":"**single use kanban**"},{"content":"A type of kanban that is used with a fixed quantity kanban rule to meet exceptionally high demand.","pos":[21122,21220]},{"content":"A single use kanban does not trigger a new kanban when it is discarded.","pos":[21221,21292]},{"pos":[21301,21319],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>smart rounding<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**smart rounding**","source":"**smart rounding**"},{"content":"A marketing practice to use odd numbers that are marginally less than their nearest round number to set prices.","pos":[21321,21432]},{"pos":[21441,21463],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>source requirement<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**source requirement**","source":"**source requirement**"},{"content":"The product quantity documented on a source document line that creates a pegging requirement.","pos":[21465,21558]},{"pos":[21567,21600],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>statistical baseline forecast<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**statistical baseline forecast**","source":"**statistical baseline forecast**"},{"content":"An estimate of future demand that is created by applying a forecasting algorithm to historical transaction data.","pos":[21602,21714]},{"pos":[21723,21738],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>supermarket<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**supermarket**","source":"**supermarket**"},{"content":"A just-in-time inventory location that has finite capacity and is used to batch material near a point of consumption.","pos":[21740,21857]},{"pos":[21866,21909],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>system-defined financial dimension type<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**system-defined financial dimension type**","source":"**system-defined financial dimension type**"},{"content":"A financial dimension mapped to a table or view in the database that represents an entity type and whose values are in the domain of one attribute of that entity type.","pos":[21911,22078]},{"pos":[22084,22089],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>T<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**T**","source":"**T**"},{"pos":[22098,22111],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>takt time<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**takt time**","source":"**takt time**"},{"content":"The time that it takes to produce one unit of a product.","pos":[22113,22169]},{"pos":[22178,22192],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Task guide<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**Task guide**","source":"**Task guide**"},{"content":"A controlled, guided experience through the steps in a Task recording.","pos":[22194,22264]},{"content":"A Task guide leads the user through the experience that was recorded.","pos":[22265,22334]},{"content":"All security, data, and application behaviors are the same when completing a Task guide as they are without the Task guide.","pos":[22335,22458]},{"content":"The Task guide uses the same instrumentation as Task recorder to know when a user has completed the intended step, so that it can prompt the user to take the next step in the recording.","pos":[22459,22644]},{"pos":[22653,22670],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Task recorder<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**Task recorder**","source":"**Task recorder**"},{"content":"A tool that is pre-installed in Finance and Operations.","pos":[22672,22727]},{"content":"When recording, it records all events that the user enters in the Finance and Operations user interface that get executed against the server—including values added, settings changed, data removed, etc.","pos":[22728,22929]},{"pos":[22938,22956],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Task recording<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**Task recording**","source":"**Task recording**"},{"content":"A file that contains the actions and annotations that are captured when Task recorder is run in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations.","pos":[22958,23104]},{"pos":[23113,23142],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>three-way matching policy<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**three-way matching policy**","source":"**three-way matching policy**"},{"content":"A matching policy that requires one or more vendor invoice prices to match with one or more purchase order prices and that requires one or more vendor invoice quantities to match with one or more product receipt quantities.","pos":[23144,23367]},{"pos":[23376,23394],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>transfer batch<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**transfer batch**","source":"**transfer batch**"},{"content":"The quantity of one or more items that is transferred or that can be transferred.","pos":[23396,23477]},{"pos":[23486,23513],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>two-way matching policy<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**two-way matching policy**","source":"**two-way matching policy**"},{"content":"A matching policy that requires one or more vendor invoice prices to match with one or more purchase order prices.","pos":[23515,23629]},{"pos":[23635,23640],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>U<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**U**","source":"**U**"},{"pos":[23649,23690],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>user-defined financial dimension type<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**user-defined financial dimension type**","source":"**user-defined financial dimension type**"},{"content":"A financial dimension mapped to a user-defined list of values.","pos":[23692,23754]},{"pos":[23760,23765],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>V<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**V**","source":"**V**"},{"pos":[23774,23790],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>value stream<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**value stream**","source":"**value stream**"},{"content":"An operating unit that controls one or more production flows.","pos":[23792,23853]},{"pos":[23862,23898],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>variant configuration technology<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**variant configuration technology**","source":"**variant configuration technology**"},{"content":"A method of modeling product masters and searching for product variant configurations.","pos":[23900,23986]},{"pos":[23995,24020],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>VAT (value-added tax)<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**VAT (value-added tax)**","source":"**VAT (value-added tax)**"},{"content":"A tax on products at each stage of their production based on the value added during that stage.","pos":[24022,24117]},{"pos":[24126,24144],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>vendor catalog<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**vendor catalog**","source":"**vendor catalog**"},{"content":"A listing of product offerings that are available for purchase from a vendor.","pos":[24146,24223]},{"pos":[24232,24250],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>vendor invoice<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**vendor invoice**","source":"**vendor invoice**"},{"content":"A source document that documents a vendor payment request.","pos":[24252,24310]},{"content":"A vendor invoice can refer to one or more purchase orders.","pos":[24311,24369]},{"content":"When the vendor invoice is authorized, a payment can be made to the vendor.","pos":[24370,24445]},{"pos":[24451,24456],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>W<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**W**","source":"**W**"},{"pos":[24465,24478],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>work cell<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**work cell**","source":"**work cell**"},{"content":"A resource group that participates in a production flow activity.","pos":[24480,24545]},{"pos":[24554,24564],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>worker<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**worker**","source":"**worker**"},{"content":"A person who assumes the role of an employee or a contractor and is paid in exchange for services.","pos":[24566,24664]},{"pos":[24673,24686],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>workspace<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**workspace**","source":"**workspace**"},{"content":"A page that provides an overview of one of the activities that the user performs.","pos":[24688,24769]},{"content":"The page uses tiles, lists, and charts to display pending work and related data from multiple sources, and the page surfaces frequent tasks related to this data.","pos":[24770,24931]},{"content":"Tiles shown in the summary section of the workspace are also displayed in the related section in the dashboard.","pos":[24932,25043]}]}