{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,69],"content":"One-time vendors in the public sector","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"One-time vendors in the public sector","pos":[0,37]}]},{"pos":[83,236],"content":"This article provides information about how to create a one-time vendor and invoice, and how to import and create multiple one-time vendors and invoices.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"This article provides information about how to create a one-time vendor and invoice, and how to import and create multiple one-time vendors and invoices.","pos":[0,153]}]},{"pos":[839,876],"content":"One-time vendors in the public sector","linkify":"One-time vendors in the public sector","nodes":[{"content":"One-time vendors in the public sector","pos":[0,37]}]},{"content":"This article provides information about how to create a one-time vendor and invoice, and how to import and create multiple one-time vendors and invoices.","pos":[878,1031]},{"content":"Occasionally, you might have to create an invoice for a new vendor that you have no regular relationship with.","pos":[1034,1144]},{"content":"In Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations, if approval or a contract in the form of a purchase order isn't required, you can quickly create an invoice at the same time that you create a record for the vendor.","pos":[1145,1352]},{"content":"For example, you have to pay referees or refunds, but a master vendor record doesn't exist.","pos":[1353,1444]},{"content":"Alternatively, you might have to create multiple invoices for new vendors that you have no regular relationship with.","pos":[1445,1562]},{"content":"If neither approval nor a purchase order is required, you can quickly create invoices at the same time that you create records for the vendors.","pos":[1563,1706]},{"content":"For example, you want to support vendor payments for jury duty, registration payments, and customer refunds or other payments, but master vendor records don't exist.","pos":[1707,1872]},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Planning for one-time vendors in the public-sector<ept id=\"p1\">](plan-one-time-vendors-public-sector.md)</ept>.","pos":[1873,1992],"source":" For more information, see [Planning for one-time vendors in the public-sector](plan-one-time-vendors-public-sector.md)."},{"pos":[1997,2042],"content":"How do I create a onetime vendor and invoice?","linkify":"How do I create a onetime vendor and invoice?","nodes":[{"content":"How do I create a onetime vendor and invoice?","pos":[0,45]}]},{"content":"The vendor record uses values from the default one-time vendor account, unless new values are entered.","pos":[2043,2145]},{"content":"That account is specified in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>General<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section of the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Accounts payable parameters<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page.","pos":[2146,2243],"source":" That account is specified in the **General** section of the **Accounts payable parameters** page."},{"content":"To view the account details, on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>All vendors<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, click the vendor account number of the default one-time vendor.","pos":[2244,2365],"source":" To view the account details, on the **All vendors** page, click the vendor account number of the default one-time vendor."},{"pos":[2370,2435],"content":"How do I import and create multiple onetime vendors and invoices?","linkify":"How do I import and create multiple onetime vendors and invoices?","nodes":[{"content":"How do I import and create multiple onetime vendors and invoices?","pos":[0,65]}]},{"content":"To create multiple one-time vendors and invoices, you first create a file that contains the vendor and invoice information, and then import the file into a staging table in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations.","pos":[2436,2647]},{"content":"You then process the imported file and generate the invoices.","pos":[2648,2709]},{"content":"For information about how to create the file, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Planning for one-time vendors in the public sector<ept id=\"p1\">](plan-one-time-vendors-public-sector.md)</ept>.","pos":[2710,2853],"source":" For information about how to create the file, see [Planning for one-time vendors in the public sector](plan-one-time-vendors-public-sector.md)."},{"pos":[2857,2865],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[2876,2992],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Accounts payable in the public sector<ept id=\"p1\">](https://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/Accounts-payable-in-the-public-sector/)</ept>","source":"[Accounts payable in the public sector](https://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/Accounts-payable-in-the-public-sector/)"}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: One-time vendors in the public sector\ndescription: This article provides information about how to create a one-time vendor and invoice, and how to import and create multiple one-time vendors and invoices. \nauthor: rschloma\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 2015-12-07 17 - 52 - 53\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: LedgerTransVoucher, SysConfiguration, Tax1099Summary, VendTableListPage\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: rschloma\nms.search.scope: AX 7.0.0, Operations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 19801\nms.assetid: 403857a3-bebb-4ff7-b1b5-c88f41fc18ae\nms.search.region: Global\nms.search.industry: Public sector\nms.author: brpotter\nms.dyn365.ops.intro: 01-02-2016\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# One-time vendors in the public sector\n\nThis article provides information about how to create a one-time vendor and invoice, and how to import and create multiple one-time vendors and invoices. \n\nOccasionally, you might have to create an invoice for a new vendor that you have no regular relationship with. In Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations, if approval or a contract in the form of a purchase order isn't required, you can quickly create an invoice at the same time that you create a record for the vendor. For example, you have to pay referees or refunds, but a master vendor record doesn't exist. Alternatively, you might have to create multiple invoices for new vendors that you have no regular relationship with. If neither approval nor a purchase order is required, you can quickly create invoices at the same time that you create records for the vendors. For example, you want to support vendor payments for jury duty, registration payments, and customer refunds or other payments, but master vendor records don't exist. For more information, see [Planning for one-time vendors in the public-sector](plan-one-time-vendors-public-sector.md).\n\n## How do I create a onetime vendor and invoice?\nThe vendor record uses values from the default one-time vendor account, unless new values are entered. That account is specified in the **General** section of the **Accounts payable parameters** page. To view the account details, on the **All vendors** page, click the vendor account number of the default one-time vendor.\n\n## How do I import and create multiple onetime vendors and invoices?\nTo create multiple one-time vendors and invoices, you first create a file that contains the vendor and invoice information, and then import the file into a staging table in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations. You then process the imported file and generate the invoices. For information about how to create the file, see [Planning for one-time vendors in the public sector](plan-one-time-vendors-public-sector.md).  \n\nSee also\n--------\n\n[Accounts payable in the public sector](https://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/Accounts-payable-in-the-public-sector/)\n\n"}