{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Fixed asset transaction options\ndescription: This article describes the different methods available to create fixed asset transactions.\nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 04/04/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: AssetTable, PurchCreateOrder\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: twheeloc\nms.search.scope: AX 7.0.0, Operations, Core\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 23061\nms.assetid: 338c495b-a4d8-461e-b85b-a83faf673730\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: saraschi\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Fixed asset transaction options\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThis article describes the different methods available to create fixed asset transactions.\n\nYou can set up Fixed assets for integration with Accounts payable, Accounts receivable, Procurement and sourcing, and General ledger. You can also transfer items in Inventory management to Fixed assets if you want to use those items internally.\n\n## Accounts payable\nYou can enter Fixed assets transactions in the Journal voucher page. This page can be opened from the Invoice journal page. You can also open the Journal voucher page from the Invoice approval journal page. In the Offset account type field, select Fixed assets. Then, in the Offset account field, select a fixed asset number. On the Fixed assets tab, enter values in the Transaction type and Book fields.\n\n## Accounts receivable\nYou can enter Fixed assets transactions in the Free text invoice page.  In the Free text invoice page, in the Invoice lines grid, select a line item. Click the Line details FastTab. Enter the fixed asset number and book for the disposal transaction. For free text invoices, the fixed asset transaction type is always Disposal - sale.\n\n## Procurement and sourcing\nYou can enter Fixed assets transactions in the Purchase order page. Enter the required information to create a purchase order, and then click OK. In the Purchase order page, click the Line details FastTab. Then, on the Fixed assets tab, enter information about the fixed asset. \n\nTo post an acquisition transaction for an existing fixed asset, specify the fixed asset number, book, and transaction type. The fixed asset cannot be posted if any of this information is missing. To post an acquisition transaction for a new fixed asset, select the New fixed asset? option, and then select the fixed asset group to assign the new asset to. However, no fixed asset fields are available for a line if the item is in an inventory model group that uses a standard cost inventory model. Additionally, the options that are defined in the Fixed assets parameters page determine whether you can post acquisition transactions from the purchasing modules. \n\nWhen a purchase order or the Inventory to fixed assets journal is used to acquire fixed assets, the inventory value is affected.\n\n## General ledger\nAny fixed asset transaction type can be posted in the General journal page. You can also use journals in Fixed assets to post fixed asset transactions.\n\n## Options for entering fixed asset transaction types\n\n\n| Transaction type                    | Module                   | Options                                   |\n|-------------------------------------|--------------------------|-------------------------------------------|\n| Acquisition, Acquisition adjustment | Fixed assets             | Fixed assets, Inventory to fixed assets   |\n|                                     | General ledger           | General journal                           |\n|                                     | Accounts payable         | Invoice journal, Invoice approval journal |\n|                                     | Procurement and sourcing | Purchase order                            |\n| Depreciation                        | Fixed assets             | Fixed assets                              |\n|                                     | General ledger           | General journal                           |\n| Disposal                            | Fixed assets             | Fixed assets                              |\n| ** **                               | General ledger           | General journal                           |\n| ** **                               | Accounts receivable      | Free text invoice                         |\n\n\n\nFor more information, see [Fixed assets integration](fixed-asset-integration.md).\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,700],"content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Fixed asset transaction options\ndescription: This article describes the different methods available to create fixed asset transactions.\nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 04/04/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: AssetTable, PurchCreateOrder\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: twheeloc\nms.search.scope: AX 7.0.0, Operations, Core\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 23061\nms.assetid: 338c495b-a4d8-461e-b85b-a83faf673730\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: saraschi\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n","nodes":[{"content":"Fixed asset transaction options","nodes":[{"pos":[0,31],"content":"Fixed asset transaction options","nodes":[{"content":"Fixed asset transaction options","pos":[0,31]}]}],"path":["title"]},{"content":"This article describes the different methods available to create fixed asset transactions.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,90],"content":"This article describes the different methods available to create fixed asset transactions.","nodes":[{"content":"This article describes the different methods available to create fixed asset transactions.","pos":[0,90]}]}],"path":["description"]}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[708,739],"content":"Fixed asset transaction options","linkify":"Fixed asset transaction options","nodes":[{"content":"Fixed asset transaction options","pos":[0,31]}]},{"content":"This article describes the different methods available to create fixed asset transactions.","pos":[785,875]},{"content":"You can set up Fixed assets for integration with Accounts payable, Accounts receivable, Procurement and sourcing, and General ledger.","pos":[877,1010]},{"content":"You can also transfer items in Inventory management to Fixed assets if you want to use those items internally.","pos":[1011,1121]},{"pos":[1126,1142],"content":"Accounts payable","linkify":"Accounts payable","nodes":[{"content":"Accounts payable","pos":[0,16]}]},{"content":"You can enter Fixed assets transactions in the Journal voucher page.","pos":[1143,1211]},{"content":"This page can be opened from the Invoice journal page.","pos":[1212,1266]},{"content":"You can also open the Journal voucher page from the Invoice approval journal page.","pos":[1267,1349]},{"content":"In the Offset account type field, select Fixed assets.","pos":[1350,1404]},{"content":"Then, in the Offset account field, select a fixed asset number.","pos":[1405,1468]},{"content":"On the Fixed assets tab, enter values in the Transaction type and Book fields.","pos":[1469,1547]},{"pos":[1552,1571],"content":"Accounts receivable","linkify":"Accounts receivable","nodes":[{"content":"Accounts receivable","pos":[0,19]}]},{"content":"You can enter Fixed assets transactions in the Free text invoice page.","pos":[1572,1642]},{"content":"In the Free text invoice page, in the Invoice lines grid, select a line item.","pos":[1644,1721]},{"content":"Click the Line details FastTab.","pos":[1722,1753]},{"content":"Enter the fixed asset number and book for the disposal transaction.","pos":[1754,1821]},{"content":"For free text invoices, the fixed asset transaction type is always Disposal - sale.","pos":[1822,1905]},{"pos":[1910,1934],"content":"Procurement and sourcing","linkify":"Procurement and sourcing","nodes":[{"content":"Procurement and sourcing","pos":[0,24]}]},{"content":"You can enter Fixed assets transactions in the Purchase order page.","pos":[1935,2002]},{"content":"Enter the required information to create a purchase order, and then click OK.","pos":[2003,2080]},{"content":"In the Purchase order page, click the Line details FastTab.","pos":[2081,2140]},{"content":"Then, on the Fixed assets tab, enter information about the fixed asset.","pos":[2141,2212]},{"content":"To post an acquisition transaction for an existing fixed asset, specify the fixed asset number, book, and transaction type.","pos":[2215,2338]},{"content":"The fixed asset cannot be posted if any of this information is missing.","pos":[2339,2410]},{"content":"To post an acquisition transaction for a new fixed asset, select the New fixed asset? option, and then select the fixed asset group to assign the new asset to.","pos":[2411,2570]},{"content":"However, no fixed asset fields are available for a line if the item is in an inventory model group that uses a standard cost inventory model.","pos":[2571,2712]},{"content":"Additionally, the options that are defined in the Fixed assets parameters page determine whether you can post acquisition transactions from the purchasing modules.","pos":[2713,2876]},{"content":"When a purchase order or the Inventory to fixed assets journal is used to acquire fixed assets, the inventory value is affected.","pos":[2879,3007]},{"pos":[3012,3026],"content":"General ledger","linkify":"General ledger","nodes":[{"content":"General ledger","pos":[0,14]}]},{"content":"Any fixed asset transaction type can be posted in the General journal page.","pos":[3027,3102]},{"content":"You can also use journals in Fixed assets to post fixed asset transactions.","pos":[3103,3178]},{"pos":[3183,3233],"content":"Options for entering fixed asset transaction types","linkify":"Options for entering fixed asset transaction types","nodes":[{"content":"Options for entering fixed asset transaction types","pos":[0,50]}]},{"content":"Transaction type","pos":[3238,3254]},{"content":"Module","pos":[3276,3282]},{"content":"Options","pos":[3303,3310]},{"content":"Acquisition, Acquisition adjustment","pos":[3460,3495]},{"content":"Fixed assets","pos":[3498,3510]},{"content":"Fixed assets, Inventory to fixed assets","pos":[3525,3564]},{"content":"General ledger","pos":[3609,3623]},{"content":"General journal","pos":[3636,3651]},{"content":"Accounts payable","pos":[3720,3736]},{"content":"Invoice journal, Invoice approval journal","pos":[3747,3788]},{"content":"Procurement and sourcing","pos":[3831,3855]},{"content":"Purchase order","pos":[3858,3872]},{"content":"Depreciation","pos":[3904,3916]},{"content":"Fixed assets","pos":[3942,3954]},{"content":"Fixed assets","pos":[3969,3981]},{"content":"General ledger","pos":[4053,4067]},{"content":"General journal","pos":[4080,4095]},{"content":"Disposal","pos":[4126,4134]},{"content":"Fixed assets","pos":[4164,4176]},{"content":"Fixed assets","pos":[4191,4203]},{"content":"** **","pos":[4237,4242]},{"content":"General ledger","pos":[4275,4289]},{"content":"General journal","pos":[4302,4317]},{"content":"** **","pos":[4348,4353]},{"content":"Accounts receivable","pos":[4386,4405]},{"content":"Free text invoice","pos":[4413,4430]},{"pos":[4460,4541],"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Fixed assets integration<ept id=\"p1\">](fixed-asset-integration.md)</ept>.","source":"For more information, see [Fixed assets integration](fixed-asset-integration.md)."}]}