{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,77],"content":"Commerce essentials overview | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Commerce essentials overview | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,45]}]},{"pos":[91,468],"content":"This article provides information about Commerce essentials, which is a retail point of sale (POS) and e-commerce configuration option for Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations. Commerce essentials provides an out-of-box retail workload that can help retailers quickly go live with a Microsoft Dynamics-based retail solution and lets them focus on retail-specific capabilities.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"This article provides information about Commerce essentials, which is a retail point of sale (POS) and e-commerce configuration option for Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations. Commerce essentials provides an out-of-box retail workload that can help retailers quickly go live with a Microsoft Dynamics-based retail solution and lets them focus on retail-specific capabilities.","pos":[0,377],"nodes":[{"content":"This article provides information about Commerce essentials, which is a retail point of sale (POS) and e-commerce configuration option for Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations.","pos":[0,177]},{"content":"Commerce essentials provides an out-of-box retail workload that can help retailers quickly go live with a Microsoft Dynamics-based retail solution and lets them focus on retail-specific capabilities.","pos":[178,377]}]}]},{"pos":[903,931],"content":"Commerce essentials overview","linkify":"Commerce essentials overview","nodes":[{"content":"Commerce essentials overview","pos":[0,28]}]},{"content":"This article provides information about Commerce essentials, which is a retail point of sale (POS) and e-commerce configuration option for Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations.","pos":[933,1110]},{"content":"Commerce essentials provides an out-of-box retail workload that can help retailers quickly go live with a Microsoft Dynamics-based retail solution and lets them focus on retail-specific capabilities.","pos":[1111,1310]},{"pos":[1313,1321],"content":"Overview","linkify":"Overview","nodes":[{"content":"Overview","pos":[0,8]}]},{"content":"Business software environments often include many systems, each of which performs very specific functions.","pos":[1332,1438]},{"content":"Often, retailers want to take advantage of the retail management aspects of Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations, but don't want to replace their existing financial or Human resources (HR) system.","pos":[1439,1636]},{"content":"For these retailers, a workload that is specific to retail is required.","pos":[1637,1708]},{"content":"Commerce essentials delivers these retail-specific capabilities as a configuration option for Dynamics 365 for Operations.","pos":[1709,1831]},{"content":"After configuration is completed, all non-retail aspects of the solution are hidden from view, so that the focus can be put on what is important: managing a retail organization.","pos":[1832,2009]},{"content":"Commerce essentials was first introduced as a configuration option in Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 R3 CU8.","pos":[2010,2114]},{"content":"Since that time, many improvements have been made to make it a solution that works for omni-channel retailers, not just for brick-and-mortar organizations.","pos":[2115,2270]},{"pos":[2275,2288],"content":"Configuration","linkify":"Configuration","nodes":[{"content":"Configuration","pos":[0,13]}]},{"content":"To configure Commerce essentials, go to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>System administration<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Setup<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>License configuration<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>, and scroll down to <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Retail<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>.","pos":[2289,2432],"source":"To configure Commerce essentials, go to **System administration** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **License configuration**, and scroll down to **Retail**."},{"content":"Expand the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Retail<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> node, and select the check box for <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Commerce essentials<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[2433,2514],"source":" Expand the **Retail** node, and select the check box for **Commerce essentials**."},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Save<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, review the changes, and then refresh the page.","pos":[2515,2577],"source":" Click **Save**, review the changes, and then refresh the page."},{"content":"To switch back to the full solution, go to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Commerce essentials<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Headquarters setup<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>License configuration<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>, and scroll down to <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Retail<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>.","pos":[2578,2735],"source":" To switch back to the full solution, go to **Commerce essentials** &gt; **Headquarters setup** &gt; **License configuration**, and scroll down to **Retail**."},{"content":"Expand the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Retail<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> node, and clear the check box for <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Commerce essentials<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[2736,2816],"source":" Expand the **Retail** node, and clear the check box for **Commerce essentials**."},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Save<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, review the changes, and then refresh the page.","pos":[2817,2879],"source":" Click **Save**, review the changes, and then refresh the page."},{"pos":[2884,2901],"content":"What is included?","linkify":"What is included?","nodes":[{"content":"What is included?","pos":[0,17]}]},{"content":"Commerce essentials includes all the retail back-office capabilities that are built into the core Dynamics 365 for Operations retail solution, except call center capabilities.","pos":[2902,3077]},{"content":"All channel, worker, product, store, register, and device management capabilities are included in a single navigation node.","pos":[3078,3201]},{"content":"Additionally, all full retail workspaces are included to provide out-of-box role-specific landing pages.","pos":[3202,3306]},{"content":"Commerce essentials targets retailers who have a brick-and-mortar or mobile scenario that can benefit from Retail Modern POS (MPOS) and e-commerce channels.","pos":[3307,3463]},{"content":"By using Commerce essentials, retailers can manage these channels in a single place and therefore gain true omni-channel capabilities.","pos":[3464,3598]},{"pos":[3603,3640],"content":"How is Commerce essentials different?","linkify":"How is Commerce essentials different?","nodes":[{"content":"How is Commerce essentials different?","pos":[0,37]}]},{"content":"In addition to providing unified navigation and retail-only pages, Commerce essentials hides all non-retail page elements, such as fields and controls.","pos":[3641,3792]},{"content":"The result is a streamlined user interface that helps retailers focus on the task at hand.","pos":[3793,3883]},{"content":"Retailers that have a full product license can use Commerce essentials as a starting point for more retail-oriented users.","pos":[3884,4006]},{"content":"Other elements, such as advanced HR capabilities, can be added to Commerce essentials as they are required, according to the terms of the license agreement that is in place.","pos":[4007,4180]},{"content":"As part of the streamlining and simplification that Commerce essentials provides, accounting export capability lets retailers map totals that are accrued in Commerce essentials to the account numbers in their existing accounting system.","pos":[4181,4417]},{"content":"As the retail system generates financial data, this data can easily be exported from Commerce essentials into the retailer's accounting system.","pos":[4418,4561]},{"content":"If more advanced integration capabilities are required, Commerce essentials also includes the full Import/Export framework that is included in Dynamics 365 for Operations.","pos":[4562,4733]},{"content":"The hundreds of data entities that are included by default give Commerce essentials the flexibility to fit comfortably into a multi-tier environment where multiple specialized systems are used.","pos":[4734,4927]}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Commerce essentials overview | Microsoft Docs\ndescription: This article provides information about Commerce essentials, which is a retail point of sale (POS) and e-commerce configuration option for Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations. Commerce essentials provides an out-of-box retail workload that can help retailers quickly go live with a Microsoft Dynamics-based retail solution and lets them focus on retail-specific capabilities. \nauthor: josaw1\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 2015-12-03 22:12:39\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# keywords: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: josaw1\nms.suite: Released- Dynamics AX 7.0.0\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 16121\nms.assetid: 22767e04-dae1-4f62-b49d-9095e244c2ab\nms.region: global\nms.industry: Retail\nms.author: rubendel\n\n---\n\n# Commerce essentials overview\n\nThis article provides information about Commerce essentials, which is a retail point of sale (POS) and e-commerce configuration option for Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations. Commerce essentials provides an out-of-box retail workload that can help retailers quickly go live with a Microsoft Dynamics-based retail solution and lets them focus on retail-specific capabilities. \n\nOverview\n--------\n\nBusiness software environments often include many systems, each of which performs very specific functions. Often, retailers want to take advantage of the retail management aspects of Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations, but don't want to replace their existing financial or Human resources (HR) system. For these retailers, a workload that is specific to retail is required. Commerce essentials delivers these retail-specific capabilities as a configuration option for Dynamics 365 for Operations. After configuration is completed, all non-retail aspects of the solution are hidden from view, so that the focus can be put on what is important: managing a retail organization. Commerce essentials was first introduced as a configuration option in Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 R3 CU8. Since that time, many improvements have been made to make it a solution that works for omni-channel retailers, not just for brick-and-mortar organizations.\n\n## Configuration\nTo configure Commerce essentials, go to **System administration** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **License configuration**, and scroll down to **Retail**. Expand the **Retail** node, and select the check box for **Commerce essentials**. Click **Save**, review the changes, and then refresh the page. To switch back to the full solution, go to **Commerce essentials** &gt; **Headquarters setup** &gt; **License configuration**, and scroll down to **Retail**. Expand the **Retail** node, and clear the check box for **Commerce essentials**. Click **Save**, review the changes, and then refresh the page.\n\n## What is included?\nCommerce essentials includes all the retail back-office capabilities that are built into the core Dynamics 365 for Operations retail solution, except call center capabilities. All channel, worker, product, store, register, and device management capabilities are included in a single navigation node. Additionally, all full retail workspaces are included to provide out-of-box role-specific landing pages. Commerce essentials targets retailers who have a brick-and-mortar or mobile scenario that can benefit from Retail Modern POS (MPOS) and e-commerce channels. By using Commerce essentials, retailers can manage these channels in a single place and therefore gain true omni-channel capabilities.\n\n## How is Commerce essentials different?\nIn addition to providing unified navigation and retail-only pages, Commerce essentials hides all non-retail page elements, such as fields and controls. The result is a streamlined user interface that helps retailers focus on the task at hand. Retailers that have a full product license can use Commerce essentials as a starting point for more retail-oriented users. Other elements, such as advanced HR capabilities, can be added to Commerce essentials as they are required, according to the terms of the license agreement that is in place. As part of the streamlining and simplification that Commerce essentials provides, accounting export capability lets retailers map totals that are accrued in Commerce essentials to the account numbers in their existing accounting system. As the retail system generates financial data, this data can easily be exported from Commerce essentials into the retailer's accounting system. If more advanced integration capabilities are required, Commerce essentials also includes the full Import/Export framework that is included in Dynamics 365 for Operations. The hundreds of data entities that are included by default give Commerce essentials the flexibility to fit comfortably into a multi-tier environment where multiple specialized systems are used.\n\n"}