{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,87],"content":"Manage the Electronic reporting configuration lifecycle","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Manage the Electronic reporting configuration lifecycle","pos":[0,55]}]},{"pos":[101,249],"content":"This topic describes how to manage the lifecycle of Electronic reporting (ER) configurations for the Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations solution.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"This topic describes how to manage the lifecycle of Electronic reporting (ER) configurations for the Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations solution.","pos":[0,148]}]},{"pos":[923,978],"content":"Manage the Electronic reporting configuration lifecycle","linkify":"Manage the Electronic reporting configuration lifecycle","nodes":[{"content":"Manage the Electronic reporting configuration lifecycle","pos":[0,55]}]},{"content":"This topic describes how to manage the lifecycle of Electronic reporting (ER) configurations for the Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations solution.","pos":[980,1128]},{"pos":[1130,1138],"content":"Overview","linkify":"Overview","nodes":[{"content":"Overview","pos":[0,8]}]},{"content":"Electronic reporting (ER) is an engine that supports statutory required and country-specific electronic documents in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations.","pos":[1149,1304]},{"content":"In general, ER assumes an ability to perform the following tasks for a single electronic document.","pos":[1305,1403]},{"content":"For more details, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Electronic reporting overview<ept id=\"p1\">](general-electronic-reporting.md)</ept>.","pos":[1404,1491],"source":" For more details, see [Electronic reporting overview](general-electronic-reporting.md)."},{"content":"Design a template for an electronic document:","pos":[1497,1542]},{"content":"Identify the required sources of data that can be presented in the document:","pos":[1551,1627]},{"content":"Underlying Dynamics 365 for Operations data, such as data tables, data entities, and classes.","pos":[1640,1733]},{"content":"Process-specific properties, such as execution date and time, and time zone.","pos":[1746,1822]},{"content":"User input parameters, specified by the end user at run time.","pos":[1835,1896]},{"content":"Define the required document elements and their topology to specify a final document format.","pos":[1905,1997]},{"content":"Configure the desired flow of data from selected data sources to defined document elements (via data source bindings to document format components), and specify process control logic.","pos":[2006,2189]},{"content":"Make a template available so that it can be used in other Dynamics 365 for Operations instances:","pos":[2194,2290]},{"content":"Transform a document template that was created in Dynamics 365 for Operations into an ER configuration, and export the configuration from the current Dynamics 365 for Operations instance as an XML package that can be stored either locally or in LCS.","pos":[2299,2548]},{"content":"Transform an ER configuration into a Dynamics 365 for Operations document template.","pos":[2557,2640]},{"content":"Import an XML package that is stored either locally or in LCS into the current Dynamics 365 for Operations instance.","pos":[2649,2765]},{"content":"Customize the template of an electronic document:","pos":[2770,2819]},{"content":"Bring a template from LCS into the current Dynamics 365 for Operations instance as an ER configuration.","pos":[2828,2931]},{"content":"Design a custom version of an ER configuration, and keep a reference to the base version.","pos":[2940,3029]},{"content":"Integrate a template with a particular business process, so that it's available in Dynamics 365 for Operations:","pos":[3034,3145]},{"content":"Configure settings so that Dynamics 365 for Operations starts to use an ER configuration, by referring to that configuration in a process-related parameter.","pos":[3154,3310]},{"content":"For example, refer to the ER configuration in a specific Accounts payable payment method to generate an electronic payment message for processing invoices.","pos":[3311,3466]},{"content":"Use a template in a specific business process:","pos":[3471,3517]},{"content":"Run an ER configuration in a specific business process.","pos":[3526,3581]},{"content":"For example, to generate an electronic payment message for processing invoices when a payment method that references the ER configuration is selected.","pos":[3582,3732]},{"pos":[3737,3745],"content":"Concepts","linkify":"Concepts","nodes":[{"content":"Concepts","pos":[0,8]}]},{"content":"The following roles and related activities are associated with the ER configuration lifecycle.","pos":[3746,3840]},{"content":"Role","pos":[3844,3848]},{"content":"Activities","pos":[3889,3899]},{"content":"Description","pos":[3955,3966]},{"content":"Electronic reporting functional consultant","pos":[4516,4558]},{"content":"Create and manage ER components (models and formats).","pos":[4561,4614]},{"content":"A business person who designs ER domain–specific data models, designs the required templates for electronic documents, and binds them accordingly.","pos":[4627,4773]},{"content":"Electronic reporting developer","pos":[4852,4882]},{"content":"Create and manage data model mappings.","pos":[4897,4935]},{"content":"A Dynamics 365 for Operations specialist who selects the required Dynamics 365 for Operations data sources and binds them to ER domain–specific data models.","pos":[4963,5119]},{"content":"Accounting supervisor","pos":[5188,5209]},{"content":"Configure process-related settings that reference ER artifacts.","pos":[5233,5296]},{"pos":[5299,5519],"content":"For example, an <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Accounting supervisor<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> role that allows the settings of an ER configuration to be used in a particular Accounts payable payment method to generate an electronic payment message for processing invoices.","source":"For example, an **Accounting supervisor** role that allows the settings of an ER configuration to be used in a particular Accounts payable payment method to generate an electronic payment message for processing invoices."},{"content":"Accounts payable payments clerk","pos":[5524,5555]},{"content":"Use ER artifacts in a specific business process.","pos":[5569,5617]},{"pos":[5635,5845],"content":"For example, an <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Accounts payable payments clerk<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> role that allows electronic payment messages to be generated for processing invoices, based on the ER format that is configured for a specific payment method.","source":"For example, an **Accounts payable payments clerk** role that allows electronic payment messages to be generated for processing invoices, based on the ER format that is configured for a specific payment method."},{"pos":[5862,5900],"content":"ER configuration development lifecycle","linkify":"ER configuration development lifecycle","nodes":[{"content":"ER configuration development lifecycle","pos":[0,38]}]},{"content":"For the following ER-related reasons, we recommend that you design ER configurations in the development environment, as a separate instance of Dynamics 365 for Operations:","pos":[5901,6072]},{"content":"Users in either the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Electronic reporting developer<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> role or the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Electronic reporting functional consultant<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> role can edit configurations and run them for testing purposes.","pos":[6078,6255],"source":"Users in either the **Electronic reporting developer** role or the **Electronic reporting functional consultant** role can edit configurations and run them for testing purposes."},{"content":"This scenario can cause calls of methods of classes and tables that might harm business data and the performance of the Dynamics 365 for Operations instance.","pos":[6256,6413]},{"content":"Calls of methods of classes and tables as ER data sources of ER configurations aren't restricted by Dynamics 365 for Operations entry points and logged company content.","pos":[6418,6586]},{"content":"Therefore, users in either the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Electronic reporting developer<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> role or the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Electronic reporting functional consultant<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> role can access business-sensitive data.","pos":[6587,6752],"source":" Therefore, users in either the **Electronic reporting developer** role or the **Electronic reporting functional consultant** role can access business-sensitive data."},{"content":"ER configurations that are designed in the development environment can be uploaded to the test environment for the configuration evaluation (proper process integration, correctness of results, and performance) and quality assurance, such as correctness of role-driven access rights and segregation of duties.","pos":[6754,7062]},{"content":"The features that enable ER configuration interchange can be used for this purpose.","pos":[7063,7146]},{"content":"Finally, proven ER configurations can be uploaded either to LCS, where they can be shared with service subscribers, or to the production environment for internal use, such as shown in the following illustration.","pos":[7147,7358]},{"content":"ER configuration lifecycle","pos":[7361,7387]},{"pos":[7431,7439],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[7450,7514],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Electronic reporting overview<ept id=\"p1\">](general-electronic-reporting.md)</ept>","source":"[Electronic reporting overview](general-electronic-reporting.md)"}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Manage the Electronic reporting configuration lifecycle\ndescription: This topic describes how to manage the lifecycle of Electronic reporting (ER) configurations for the Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations solution.\nauthor: kfend\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 04/04/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: ERDataModelDesigner, ERMappedFormatDesigner, ERModelMappingDesigner, ERModelMappingTable, ERSolutionImport, ERSolutionTable, ERVendorTable, ERWorkspace\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User, Developer, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \n# ms.reviewer: 71\nms.search.scope: AX 7.0.0, Operations, Core\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 58801\nms.assetid: 35ad19ea-185d-4fce-b9cb-f94584b14f75\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: nselin\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Manage the Electronic reporting configuration lifecycle\n\nThis topic describes how to manage the lifecycle of Electronic reporting (ER) configurations for the Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations solution.\n\nOverview\n--------\n\nElectronic reporting (ER) is an engine that supports statutory required and country-specific electronic documents in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations. In general, ER assumes an ability to perform the following tasks for a single electronic document. For more details, see [Electronic reporting overview](general-electronic-reporting.md).\n\n-   Design a template for an electronic document:\n    -   Identify the required sources of data that can be presented in the document:\n        -   Underlying Dynamics 365 for Operations data, such as data tables, data entities, and classes.\n        -   Process-specific properties, such as execution date and time, and time zone.\n        -   User input parameters, specified by the end user at run time.\n    -   Define the required document elements and their topology to specify a final document format.\n    -   Configure the desired flow of data from selected data sources to defined document elements (via data source bindings to document format components), and specify process control logic.\n-   Make a template available so that it can be used in other Dynamics 365 for Operations instances:\n    -   Transform a document template that was created in Dynamics 365 for Operations into an ER configuration, and export the configuration from the current Dynamics 365 for Operations instance as an XML package that can be stored either locally or in LCS.\n    -   Transform an ER configuration into a Dynamics 365 for Operations document template.\n    -   Import an XML package that is stored either locally or in LCS into the current Dynamics 365 for Operations instance.\n-   Customize the template of an electronic document:\n    -   Bring a template from LCS into the current Dynamics 365 for Operations instance as an ER configuration.\n    -   Design a custom version of an ER configuration, and keep a reference to the base version.\n-   Integrate a template with a particular business process, so that it's available in Dynamics 365 for Operations:\n    -   Configure settings so that Dynamics 365 for Operations starts to use an ER configuration, by referring to that configuration in a process-related parameter. For example, refer to the ER configuration in a specific Accounts payable payment method to generate an electronic payment message for processing invoices.\n-   Use a template in a specific business process:\n    -   Run an ER configuration in a specific business process. For example, to generate an electronic payment message for processing invoices when a payment method that references the ER configuration is selected.\n\n## Concepts\nThe following roles and related activities are associated with the ER configuration lifecycle.\n\n| Role                                       | Activities                                                      | Description                                                                                                                                                                                                                  |\n|--------------------------------------------|-----------------------------------------------------------------|------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| Electronic reporting functional consultant | Create and manage ER components (models and formats).           | A business person who designs ER domain–specific data models, designs the required templates for electronic documents, and binds them accordingly.                                                                           |\n| Electronic reporting developer             | Create and manage data model mappings.                          | A Dynamics 365 for Operations specialist who selects the required Dynamics 365 for Operations data sources and binds them to ER domain–specific data models.                                                                 |\n| Accounting supervisor                      | Configure process-related settings that reference ER artifacts. | For example, an **Accounting supervisor** role that allows the settings of an ER configuration to be used in a particular Accounts payable payment method to generate an electronic payment message for processing invoices. |\n| Accounts payable payments clerk            | Use ER artifacts in a specific business process.                | For example, an **Accounts payable payments clerk** role that allows electronic payment messages to be generated for processing invoices, based on the ER format that is configured for a specific payment method.           |\n\n## ER configuration development lifecycle\nFor the following ER-related reasons, we recommend that you design ER configurations in the development environment, as a separate instance of Dynamics 365 for Operations:\n\n-   Users in either the **Electronic reporting developer** role or the **Electronic reporting functional consultant** role can edit configurations and run them for testing purposes. This scenario can cause calls of methods of classes and tables that might harm business data and the performance of the Dynamics 365 for Operations instance.\n-   Calls of methods of classes and tables as ER data sources of ER configurations aren't restricted by Dynamics 365 for Operations entry points and logged company content. Therefore, users in either the **Electronic reporting developer** role or the **Electronic reporting functional consultant** role can access business-sensitive data.\n\nER configurations that are designed in the development environment can be uploaded to the test environment for the configuration evaluation (proper process integration, correctness of results, and performance) and quality assurance, such as correctness of role-driven access rights and segregation of duties. The features that enable ER configuration interchange can be used for this purpose. Finally, proven ER configurations can be uploaded either to LCS, where they can be shared with service subscribers, or to the production environment for internal use, such as shown in the following illustration. ![ER configuration lifecycle](./media/ger-configuration-lifecycle.png)\n\nSee also\n--------\n\n[Electronic reporting overview](general-electronic-reporting.md)\n\n"}