{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,48],"content":"Payroll overview","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Payroll overview","pos":[0,16]}]},{"pos":[62,621],"content":"Payroll provides full gross-to-net processing for employees in the United States. With Payroll you can set up, enter, and maintain all payroll records and transactions. The comprehensive earnings and pay statement process covers federal, state, and local taxes, flexible deduction and benefits processing, and support for garnishments and tax levies. Payroll provides full reporting and inquires for W2 processing, and 940 and 941 reporting. It also lets you view current and historical payroll information for individual employees or for groups of employees.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Payroll provides full gross-to-net processing for employees in the United States. With Payroll you can set up, enter, and maintain all payroll records and transactions. The comprehensive earnings and pay statement process covers federal, state, and local taxes, flexible deduction and benefits processing, and support for garnishments and tax levies. Payroll provides full reporting and inquires for W2 processing, and 940 and 941 reporting. It also lets you view current and historical payroll information for individual employees or for groups of employees.","pos":[0,559],"nodes":[{"content":"Payroll provides full gross-to-net processing for employees in the United States.","pos":[0,81]},{"content":"With Payroll you can set up, enter, and maintain all payroll records and transactions.","pos":[82,168]},{"content":"The comprehensive earnings and pay statement process covers federal, state, and local taxes, flexible deduction and benefits processing, and support for garnishments and tax levies.","pos":[169,350]},{"content":"Payroll provides full reporting and inquires for W2 processing, and 940 and 941 reporting.","pos":[351,441]},{"content":"It also lets you view current and historical payroll information for individual employees or for groups of employees.","pos":[442,559]}]}]},{"pos":[1141,1157],"content":"Payroll overview","linkify":"Payroll overview","nodes":[{"content":"Payroll overview","pos":[0,16]}]},{"content":"Payroll provides gross-to-net processing for employees in the United States.","pos":[1159,1235]},{"content":"With Payroll you can set up, enter, and maintain all payroll records and transactions.","pos":[1236,1322]},{"content":"The comprehensive earnings and pay statement process covers federal, state, and local taxes, flexible deduction and benefits processing, and support for garnishments and tax levies.","pos":[1323,1504]},{"content":"Payroll provides full reporting and inquires for W2 processing, and 940 and 941 reporting.","pos":[1505,1595]},{"content":"It also lets you view current and historical payroll information for individual employees or for groups of employees.","pos":[1596,1713]},{"pos":[1715,1728],"content":"Payroll setup","linkify":"Payroll setup","nodes":[{"content":"Payroll setup","pos":[0,13]}]},{"content":"Basic setup for Payroll involves setting pay cycles and pay periods, calculation frequencies, and setting work schedules.","pos":[1742,1863]},{"content":"The pay cycle frequency determines how often a pay cycle is run.","pos":[1864,1928]},{"content":"Pay periods and pay dates are defined as part of the pay cycle.","pos":[1929,1992]},{"content":"You use the payroll calculation frequency to select the specific pay periods when you want certain earnings or other payroll entities to be processed.","pos":[1993,2143]},{"content":"Configuring Payroll also includes setting up earning codes and creating earning code groups, and entering information for tax withholding, benefit accrual, and setting beginning balances.","pos":[2146,2333]},{"pos":[2339,2361],"content":"Frequencies and cycles","linkify":"Frequencies and cycles","nodes":[{"content":"Frequencies and cycles","pos":[0,22]}]},{"pos":[2366,2400],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Pay cycle and pay period tasks<ept id=\"p1\">]()</ept>","source":"[Pay cycle and pay period tasks]()"},{"pos":[2405,2444],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Payroll calculation frequency tasks<ept id=\"p1\">]()</ept>","source":"[Payroll calculation frequency tasks]()"},{"pos":[2449,2482],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Work schedule and leave tasks<ept id=\"p1\">]()</ept>","source":"[Work schedule and leave tasks]()"},{"pos":[2488,2493],"content":"Codes","linkify":"Codes","nodes":[{"content":"Codes","pos":[0,5]}]},{"pos":[2498,2543],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Earning code and earning code group tasks<ept id=\"p1\">]()</ept>","source":"[Earning code and earning code group tasks]()"},{"pos":[2548,2553],"content":"Taxes","linkify":"Taxes","nodes":[{"content":"Taxes","pos":[0,5]}]},{"content":"Payroll taxes are set up in two parts.","pos":[2554,2592]},{"content":"One part covers the settings that are used throughout your organizations, such as the states where you have a connection or the rates for unemployment taxes.","pos":[2593,2750]},{"content":"The second part additional tax information that is provided for each worker.","pos":[2751,2827]},{"pos":[2834,2883],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Tax information tasks<ept id=\"p1\">](tax-information-tasks.md)</ept>","source":"[Tax information tasks](tax-information-tasks.md)"},{"pos":[2888,2938],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Tax codes, tax groups, and posting definitions<ept id=\"p1\">]()</ept>","source":"[Tax codes, tax groups, and posting definitions]()"},{"pos":[2943,2951],"content":"Benefits","linkify":"Benefits","nodes":[{"content":"Benefits","pos":[0,8]}]},{"content":"Topics related to benefits describe how to set up current and future benefits that workers and their dependents and beneficiaries can receive, and how to maintain payroll information for benefits.","pos":[2952,3148]},{"content":"Examples of benefits include medical insurance, retirement investments, workers' compensation plans, and parking benefits.","pos":[3149,3271]},{"pos":[3278,3308],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Benefit accrual plan tasks<ept id=\"p1\">]()</ept>","source":"[Benefit accrual plan tasks]()"},{"pos":[3313,3359],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Benefit setup tasks<ept id=\"p1\">](benefit-set-up-tasks.md)</ept>","source":"[Benefit setup tasks](benefit-set-up-tasks.md)"},{"pos":[3364,3410],"content":"Garnishments, tax levies, and premium earnings","linkify":"Garnishments, tax levies, and premium earnings","nodes":[{"content":"Garnishments, tax levies, and premium earnings","pos":[0,46]}]},{"content":"Premium earnings, garnishments, and tax levies won’t be used by all employees.","pos":[3411,3489]},{"content":"If your organization needs to pay premium earnings or garnish an employee’s pay, Payroll includes a framework that can help ensure that the impact of these transactions is handled correctly.","pos":[3490,3680]},{"pos":[3686,3762],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Garnishment and tax levy setup tasks<ept id=\"p1\">](garnishment-tax-levy-set-up-tasks.md)</ept>","source":"[Garnishment and tax levy setup tasks](garnishment-tax-levy-set-up-tasks.md)"},{"pos":[3767,3852],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Garnishment and tax levy enrollment tasks<ept id=\"p1\">](garnishment-tax-levy-enrollment-tasks.md)</ept>","source":"[Garnishment and tax levy enrollment tasks](garnishment-tax-levy-enrollment-tasks.md)"},{"pos":[3857,3957],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Garnishments, tax levies, and administrative fees FAQ<ept id=\"p1\">](garnishment-tax-levy-administrative-fees.md)</ept>","source":"[Garnishments, tax levies, and administrative fees FAQ](garnishment-tax-levy-administrative-fees.md)"},{"pos":[3962,4023],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Premium earning setup tasks<ept id=\"p1\">](premium-earning-setup-tasks.md)</ept>","source":"[Premium earning setup tasks](premium-earning-setup-tasks.md)"},{"pos":[4028,4052],"content":"Payroll processing tasks","linkify":"Payroll processing tasks","nodes":[{"content":"Payroll processing tasks","pos":[0,24]}]},{"content":"Running a payroll includes generating earnings and then issuing worker payments.","pos":[4053,4133]},{"content":"When those tasks have been completed, you'll post the payroll transactions and then generate vendor invoices, which result in payments being made to employees.","pos":[4134,4293]},{"pos":[4300,4341],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Generate earnings<ept id=\"p1\">](generate-earnings.md)</ept>","source":"[Generate earnings](generate-earnings.md)"},{"pos":[4346,4395],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Issue worker payments<ept id=\"p1\">](issue-worker-payments.md)</ept>","source":"[Issue worker payments](issue-worker-payments.md)"},{"pos":[4400,4485],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Post payroll and generate vendor invoices<ept id=\"p1\">](post-payroll-generate-vendor-invoices.md)</ept>","source":"[Post payroll and generate vendor invoices](post-payroll-generate-vendor-invoices.md)"},{"pos":[4490,4587],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Pay statements and the payment generation process<ept id=\"p1\">](pay-statements-payment-generation-process.md)</ept>","source":"[Pay statements and the payment generation process](pay-statements-payment-generation-process.md)"},{"content":"Several tasks must be completed after you generate pay statements for your employees.","pos":[4589,4674]},{"content":"These include releasing earnings for payment processing, and at times, holding earnings from payment processing and changing information on earnings statements.","pos":[4675,4835]},{"pos":[4841,4906],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Process existing payroll payments<ept id=\"p1\">](existing-payroll-payments.md)</ept>","source":"[Process existing payroll payments](existing-payroll-payments.md)"},{"pos":[4911,4960],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Process existing earnings<ept id=\"p1\">](existing-earnings.md)</ept>","source":"[Process existing earnings](existing-earnings.md)"},{"pos":[4965,5008],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Process pay statements<ept id=\"p1\">](pay-statements.md)</ept>","source":"[Process pay statements](pay-statements.md)"},{"pos":[5013,5038],"content":"Maintenance and reporting","linkify":"Maintenance and reporting","nodes":[{"content":"Maintenance and reporting","pos":[0,25]}]},{"content":"Maintaining your payroll data involves adjusting the carry-forward balances for accrued benefits, removing a worker from enrollment in a benefit accrual plan, or updating rates for a new plan year.","pos":[5039,5236]},{"content":"It might also be necessary to change benefits for a worker that has a qualifying life event.","pos":[5237,5329]},{"pos":[5336,5387],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Payroll data updates FAQ<ept id=\"p1\">](payroll-data-updates.md)</ept>","source":"[Payroll data updates FAQ](payroll-data-updates.md)"},{"content":"Standard payroll reports are provided to help you with payroll processing and government reporting.","pos":[5389,5488]},{"content":"Use these standard reports to create pay statements and W-2 forms that you can issue to your workers, validate payroll taxes and benefit amounts, and complete federal and state regulatory reports.","pos":[5489,5685]},{"pos":[5691,5746],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Generate payroll reports<ept id=\"p1\">](generate-payroll-reports.md)</ept>","source":"[Generate payroll reports](generate-payroll-reports.md)"}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Payroll overview\ndescription: Payroll provides full gross-to-net processing for employees in the United States. With Payroll you can set up, enter, and maintain all payroll records and transactions. The comprehensive earnings and pay statement process covers federal, state, and local taxes, flexible deduction and benefits processing, and support for garnishments and tax levies. Payroll provides full reporting and inquires for W2 processing, and 940 and 941 reporting. It also lets you view current and historical payroll information for individual employees or for groups of employees.\nauthor: rschloma\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 2016-11-01 19 - 15 - 55\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: rschloma\nms.search.scope: Operations, Core\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 248434\nms.assetid: 33dae9aa-f673-4195-9b63-7cb41534c502\nms.search.region: USA\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: rschloma\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-11-30\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 1611\n\n---\n\n# Payroll overview\n\nPayroll provides gross-to-net processing for employees in the United States. With Payroll you can set up, enter, and maintain all payroll records and transactions. The comprehensive earnings and pay statement process covers federal, state, and local taxes, flexible deduction and benefits processing, and support for garnishments and tax levies. Payroll provides full reporting and inquires for W2 processing, and 940 and 941 reporting. It also lets you view current and historical payroll information for individual employees or for groups of employees.\n\nPayroll setup\n-----------\n\nBasic setup for Payroll involves setting pay cycles and pay periods, calculation frequencies, and setting work schedules. The pay cycle frequency determines how often a pay cycle is run. Pay periods and pay dates are defined as part of the pay cycle. You use the payroll calculation frequency to select the specific pay periods when you want certain earnings or other payroll entities to be processed. \n\nConfiguring Payroll also includes setting up earning codes and creating earning code groups, and entering information for tax withholding, benefit accrual, and setting beginning balances.\n\n### Frequencies and cycles\n-   [Pay cycle and pay period tasks]()\n-   [Payroll calculation frequency tasks]()\n-   [Work schedule and leave tasks]()\n\n### Codes\n-   [Earning code and earning code group tasks]()\n\n## Taxes\nPayroll taxes are set up in two parts. One part covers the settings that are used throughout your organizations, such as the states where you have a connection or the rates for unemployment taxes. The second part additional tax information that is provided for each worker. \n\n-   [Tax information tasks](tax-information-tasks.md)\n-   [Tax codes, tax groups, and posting definitions]()\n\n## Benefits\nTopics related to benefits describe how to set up current and future benefits that workers and their dependents and beneficiaries can receive, and how to maintain payroll information for benefits. Examples of benefits include medical insurance, retirement investments, workers' compensation plans, and parking benefits. \n\n-   [Benefit accrual plan tasks]()\n-   [Benefit setup tasks](benefit-set-up-tasks.md)\n\n## Garnishments, tax levies, and premium earnings\nPremium earnings, garnishments, and tax levies won’t be used by all employees. If your organization needs to pay premium earnings or garnish an employee’s pay, Payroll includes a framework that can help ensure that the impact of these transactions is handled correctly.\n\n-   [Garnishment and tax levy setup tasks](garnishment-tax-levy-set-up-tasks.md)\n-   [Garnishment and tax levy enrollment tasks](garnishment-tax-levy-enrollment-tasks.md)\n-   [Garnishments, tax levies, and administrative fees FAQ](garnishment-tax-levy-administrative-fees.md)\n-   [Premium earning setup tasks](premium-earning-setup-tasks.md)\n\n## Payroll processing tasks\nRunning a payroll includes generating earnings and then issuing worker payments. When those tasks have been completed, you'll post the payroll transactions and then generate vendor invoices, which result in payments being made to employees. \n\n-   [Generate earnings](generate-earnings.md)\n-   [Issue worker payments](issue-worker-payments.md)\n-   [Post payroll and generate vendor invoices](post-payroll-generate-vendor-invoices.md)\n-   [Pay statements and the payment generation process](pay-statements-payment-generation-process.md)\n\nSeveral tasks must be completed after you generate pay statements for your employees. These include releasing earnings for payment processing, and at times, holding earnings from payment processing and changing information on earnings statements.\n\n-   [Process existing payroll payments](existing-payroll-payments.md)\n-   [Process existing earnings](existing-earnings.md)\n-   [Process pay statements](pay-statements.md)\n\n## Maintenance and reporting\nMaintaining your payroll data involves adjusting the carry-forward balances for accrued benefits, removing a worker from enrollment in a benefit accrual plan, or updating rates for a new plan year. It might also be necessary to change benefits for a worker that has a qualifying life event. \n\n-   [Payroll data updates FAQ](payroll-data-updates.md)\n\nStandard payroll reports are provided to help you with payroll processing and government reporting. Use these standard reports to create pay statements and W-2 forms that you can issue to your workers, validate payroll taxes and benefit amounts, and complete federal and state regulatory reports.\n\n-   [Generate payroll reports](generate-payroll-reports.md)\n\n"}