{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Batch and license plate confirmation\ndescription: This topic describes how to set up and apply batch and license plate confirmation from a mobile device.\nauthor: BibiSp\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 05/26/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form:  WHSRFAutoConfirm\naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \n# ms.reviewer: bis\n# ms.search.scope: AX 7.0.0, Operations, Core\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 269384\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: mirzaab\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Batch and license plate confirmation\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\nBatch confirmation allows you to confirm that the correct batch is being picked from the mobile device. On the initial pick of work for batch above-items only, where *batch above* indicates that batch ranges higher than location in the search hierarchy, you must verify that the batch that is picked matches the batch on the work line. \n\nLicense plate confirmation allows you to confirm that the correct license plate is being picked from the mobile device. When picking work from a stage location, you must verify that the license plate that is picked matches the license plate that is associated with the work. If the work is started by scanning a license plate, this confirmation step will be skipped.\n\n## Where it applies\nConfirmation applies in the following scenarios:\n\n- Batch confirmation applies to the initial picks of work for batch above-items.\n- License plate confirmation applies to picks from stage locations.\n\n## Set up batch and license plate confirmation\nYou can configure batch and license plate confirmation from the mobile device menu items.  \n1.  From the mobile device menu items, enter the work confirmation setup.  \n2.  Select the option for either batch or license plate confirmation. Both options are available for work type picks that do not have automatic confirmation enabled.  \n","nodes":[{"pos":[32,68],"content":"Batch and license plate confirmation","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Batch and license plate confirmation","pos":[0,36]}]},{"pos":[82,185],"content":"This topic describes how to set up and apply batch and license plate confirmation from a mobile device.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"This topic describes how to set up and apply batch and license plate confirmation from a mobile device.","pos":[0,103]}]},{"pos":[654,690],"content":"Batch and license plate confirmation","linkify":"Batch and license plate confirmation","nodes":[{"content":"Batch and license plate confirmation","pos":[0,36]}]},{"content":"Batch confirmation allows you to confirm that the correct batch is being picked from the mobile device.","pos":[735,838]},{"content":"On the initial pick of work for batch above-items only, where <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>batch above<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> indicates that batch ranges higher than location in the search hierarchy, you must verify that the batch that is picked matches the batch on the work line.","pos":[839,1070],"source":" On the initial pick of work for batch above-items only, where *batch above* indicates that batch ranges higher than location in the search hierarchy, you must verify that the batch that is picked matches the batch on the work line."},{"content":"License plate confirmation allows you to confirm that the correct license plate is being picked from the mobile device.","pos":[1073,1192]},{"content":"When picking work from a stage location, you must verify that the license plate that is picked matches the license plate that is associated with the work.","pos":[1193,1347]},{"content":"If the work is started by scanning a license plate, this confirmation step will be skipped.","pos":[1348,1439]},{"pos":[1444,1460],"content":"Where it applies","linkify":"Where it applies","nodes":[{"content":"Where it applies","pos":[0,16]}]},{"content":"Confirmation applies in the following scenarios:","pos":[1461,1509]},{"content":"Batch confirmation applies to the initial picks of work for batch above-items.","pos":[1513,1591]},{"content":"License plate confirmation applies to picks from stage locations.","pos":[1594,1659]},{"pos":[1664,1707],"content":"Set up batch and license plate confirmation","linkify":"Set up batch and license plate confirmation","nodes":[{"content":"Set up batch and license plate confirmation","pos":[0,43]}]},{"content":"You can configure batch and license plate confirmation from the mobile device menu items.","pos":[1708,1797]},{"content":"From the mobile device menu items, enter the work confirmation setup.","pos":[1804,1873]},{"content":"Select the option for either batch or license plate confirmation.","pos":[1880,1945]},{"content":"Both options are available for work type picks that do not have automatic confirmation enabled.","pos":[1946,2041]}]}