{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,87],"content":"Customer payments for a partial amount | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Customer payments for a partial amount | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,55]}]},{"pos":[101,346],"content":"Sometimes, customers make a payment that is less than the amount of an invoice. This article describes the various options for handling this situation. The options that are available to you depend on your business requirements and configuration.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Sometimes, customers make a payment that is less than the amount of an invoice. This article describes the various options for handling this situation. The options that are available to you depend on your business requirements and configuration.","pos":[0,245],"nodes":[{"content":"Sometimes, customers make a payment that is less than the amount of an invoice.","pos":[0,79]},{"content":"This article describes the various options for handling this situation.","pos":[80,151]},{"content":"The options that are available to you depend on your business requirements and configuration.","pos":[152,245]}]}]},{"pos":[780,818],"content":"Customer payments for a partial amount","linkify":"Customer payments for a partial amount","nodes":[{"content":"Customer payments for a partial amount","pos":[0,38]}]},{"content":"Sometimes, customers make a payment that is less than the amount of an invoice.","pos":[820,899]},{"content":"This article describes the various options for handling this situation.","pos":[900,971]},{"content":"The options that are available to you depend on your business requirements and configuration.","pos":[972,1065]},{"pos":[1067,1099],"content":"Partial payment with no discount","linkify":"Partial payment with no discount","nodes":[{"content":"Partial payment with no discount","pos":[0,32]}]},{"content":"Customers might make a partial payment because they just don't have enough cash on hand to pay the invoice in full, or because there is a dispute about an item on the invoice.","pos":[1134,1309]},{"content":"In this situation, the invoice can be partially settled with the payment.","pos":[1310,1383]},{"content":"The invoice will remain open and will show a balance.","pos":[1384,1437]},{"pos":[1442,1458],"content":"Discount amounts","linkify":"Discount amounts","nodes":[{"content":"Discount amounts","pos":[0,16]}]},{"content":"You can offer customers a cash discount for paying an invoice before the due date.","pos":[1459,1541]},{"content":"For example, you enter an invoice for 100.00 that specifies a 2-percent cash discount if the invoice is paid within 10 days.","pos":[1542,1666]},{"content":"The due-date terms are 30 days.","pos":[1667,1698]},{"content":"If you receive a payment of 98.00 within 10 days, you enter the payment for 98.00.","pos":[1699,1781]},{"content":"Then, when the invoice is marked for settlement, the cash discount it taken automatically.","pos":[1782,1872]},{"pos":[1877,1913],"content":"Partial payments with cash discounts","linkify":"Partial payments with cash discounts","nodes":[{"content":"Partial payments with cash discounts","pos":[0,36]}]},{"content":"When customers make a partial payment, they might plan to make an additional partial payment to fully settle the invoice.","pos":[1914,2035]},{"content":"To take a cash discount for a partial payment, you must set the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Calculate cash discounts for partial payments <ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>option to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Yes<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> on the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Accounts receivable parameters<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> page.","pos":[2036,2215],"source":" To take a cash discount for a partial payment, you must set the **Calculate cash discounts for partial payments **option to **Yes** on the **Accounts receivable parameters** page."},{"content":"For example, you offer a 2-percent cash discount if the invoice is paid within 10 days after it's issued.","pos":[2216,2321]},{"content":"An invoice is posted for 100.00.","pos":[2322,2354]},{"content":"If you receive a payment of 49.00 within 10 days, you enter a credit of 49.00 in a payment journal.","pos":[2355,2454]},{"content":"When you settle the partial payment on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Settle transactions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>1.00<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> appears in the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Cash discount amount to take<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> field.","pos":[2455,2591],"source":" When you settle the partial payment on the **Settle transactions** page, **1.00** appears in the **Cash discount amount to take** field."},{"content":"The discount amount is posted to a cash discount account.","pos":[2592,2649]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> If you enter a partial payment and leave the full invoice amount in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Amount to settle<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> field, the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Cash discount amount to take<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> field is automatically recalculated when you post the transactions.","pos":[2650,2864],"source":"**Note:** If you enter a partial payment and leave the full invoice amount in the **Amount to settle** field, the **Cash discount amount to take** field is automatically recalculated when you post the transactions."},{"pos":[2869,2896],"content":"Credit notes with discounts","linkify":"Credit notes with discounts","nodes":[{"content":"Credit notes with discounts","pos":[0,27]}]},{"content":"If customers return some of the items on an invoice, you might issue a credit note.","pos":[2897,2980]},{"content":"If a cash discount was taken on the original invoice, the credit memo to the customer should be net of the cash discount that was taken by the customer.","pos":[2981,3133]},{"content":"If the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Calculate cash discounts for credit notes<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option is set to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Yes<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> on the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Accounts receivable parameters<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> page, the discount is automatically calculated for the credit note.","pos":[3134,3321],"source":" If the **Calculate cash discounts for credit notes** option is set to **Yes** on the **Accounts receivable parameters** page, the discount is automatically calculated for the credit note."},{"content":"For example, you offered terms of payment that specify a 2-percent cash discount if the invoice is paid within 10 days after it's issued.","pos":[3322,3459]},{"content":"An invoice for 100.00 was posted, and the customer took the cash discount.","pos":[3460,3534]},{"content":"If the customer returns the goods and you issue a credit note, you can enter the credit note for -100.00.","pos":[3535,3640]},{"content":"When you view the credit note on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Settle open transactions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>98.00<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> appears in the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Amount to settle<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> field, and <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>-2.00<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept> appears in the <bpt id=\"p5\">**</bpt>Cash discount amount<ept id=\"p5\">**</ept> field.","pos":[3641,3826],"source":" When you view the credit note on the **Settle open transactions** page, **98.00** appears in the **Amount to settle** field, and **-2.00** appears in the **Cash discount amount** field."},{"content":"The discount amount is posted to a cash discount account.","pos":[3827,3884]},{"pos":[3889,3921],"content":"Overpayment/underpayment amounts","linkify":"Overpayment/underpayment amounts","nodes":[{"content":"Overpayment/underpayment amounts","pos":[0,32]}]},{"content":"When customers make a payment, there might be a very small amount that must still be settled.","pos":[3922,4015]},{"content":"For example, you invoice the customer for 1,000.00, and the customer pays 999.90.","pos":[4016,4097]},{"content":"If the remaining amount is less than the amount that is specified for overpayments or underpayments on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Accounts receivable parameters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, the difference is automatically posted to an overpayment/underpayment ledger account.","pos":[4098,4331],"source":" If the remaining amount is less than the amount that is specified for overpayments or underpayments on the **Accounts receivable parameters** page, the difference is automatically posted to an overpayment/underpayment ledger account."},{"pos":[4336,4351],"content":"Full settlement","linkify":"Full settlement","nodes":[{"content":"Full settlement","pos":[0,15]}]},{"content":"Customers might make a partial payment where the remaining amount won't be paid but is greater than the underpayment amount that is specified on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Account payable parameters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[4352,4537],"source":"Customers might make a partial payment where the remaining amount won't be paid but is greater than the underpayment amount that is specified on the **Account payable parameters** page."},{"content":"If you want to mark the invoice as fully settled, you can use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Full settlement<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Settle transaction<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page.","pos":[4538,4666],"source":" If you want to mark the invoice as fully settled, you can use the **Full settlement** option on the **Settle transaction** page."},{"content":"(You can enable the full settlement functionality by using a configuration key.) For example, an invoice is posted for 1,000.00, and the customer makes a payment of 990.00.","pos":[4667,4839]},{"content":"You've agreed that the customer doesn't have to pay the remaining 10.00.","pos":[4840,4912]},{"content":"After you mark the invoice for settlement, you can also mark select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Full settlement<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[4913,5001],"source":" After you mark the invoice for settlement, you can also mark select **Full settlement**."},{"content":"The invoice will then be considered fully settled.","pos":[5002,5052]},{"content":"The 10.00 difference is posted to a cash discount account as an additional cash discount amount.","pos":[5053,5149]}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Customer payments for a partial amount | Microsoft Docs\ndescription: Sometimes, customers make a payment that is less than the amount of an invoice. This article describes the various options for handling this situation. The options that are available to you depend on your business requirements and configuration.\nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 2015-12-01 16:39:03\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# keywords: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: twheeloc\nms.suite: Released- Dynamics AX 7.0.0\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 13011\nms.assetid: d6301a54-b4e6-4dcf-a1bd-e8a0c45fead6\nms.region: Global\n# ms.industry: \nms.author: kweekley\n\n---\n\n# Customer payments for a partial amount\n\nSometimes, customers make a payment that is less than the amount of an invoice. This article describes the various options for handling this situation. The options that are available to you depend on your business requirements and configuration.\n\nPartial payment with no discount\n--------------------------------\n\nCustomers might make a partial payment because they just don't have enough cash on hand to pay the invoice in full, or because there is a dispute about an item on the invoice. In this situation, the invoice can be partially settled with the payment. The invoice will remain open and will show a balance.\n\n## Discount amounts\nYou can offer customers a cash discount for paying an invoice before the due date. For example, you enter an invoice for 100.00 that specifies a 2-percent cash discount if the invoice is paid within 10 days. The due-date terms are 30 days. If you receive a payment of 98.00 within 10 days, you enter the payment for 98.00. Then, when the invoice is marked for settlement, the cash discount it taken automatically.\n\n## Partial payments with cash discounts\nWhen customers make a partial payment, they might plan to make an additional partial payment to fully settle the invoice. To take a cash discount for a partial payment, you must set the **Calculate cash discounts for partial payments **option to **Yes** on the **Accounts receivable parameters** page. For example, you offer a 2-percent cash discount if the invoice is paid within 10 days after it's issued. An invoice is posted for 100.00. If you receive a payment of 49.00 within 10 days, you enter a credit of 49.00 in a payment journal. When you settle the partial payment on the **Settle transactions** page, **1.00** appears in the **Cash discount amount to take** field. The discount amount is posted to a cash discount account. **Note:** If you enter a partial payment and leave the full invoice amount in the **Amount to settle** field, the **Cash discount amount to take** field is automatically recalculated when you post the transactions.\n\n## Credit notes with discounts\nIf customers return some of the items on an invoice, you might issue a credit note. If a cash discount was taken on the original invoice, the credit memo to the customer should be net of the cash discount that was taken by the customer. If the **Calculate cash discounts for credit notes** option is set to **Yes** on the **Accounts receivable parameters** page, the discount is automatically calculated for the credit note. For example, you offered terms of payment that specify a 2-percent cash discount if the invoice is paid within 10 days after it's issued. An invoice for 100.00 was posted, and the customer took the cash discount. If the customer returns the goods and you issue a credit note, you can enter the credit note for -100.00. When you view the credit note on the **Settle open transactions** page, **98.00** appears in the **Amount to settle** field, and **-2.00** appears in the **Cash discount amount** field. The discount amount is posted to a cash discount account.\n\n## Overpayment/underpayment amounts\nWhen customers make a payment, there might be a very small amount that must still be settled. For example, you invoice the customer for 1,000.00, and the customer pays 999.90. If the remaining amount is less than the amount that is specified for overpayments or underpayments on the **Accounts receivable parameters** page, the difference is automatically posted to an overpayment/underpayment ledger account.\n\n## Full settlement\nCustomers might make a partial payment where the remaining amount won't be paid but is greater than the underpayment amount that is specified on the **Account payable parameters** page. If you want to mark the invoice as fully settled, you can use the **Full settlement** option on the **Settle transaction** page. (You can enable the full settlement functionality by using a configuration key.) For example, an invoice is posted for 1,000.00, and the customer makes a payment of 990.00. You've agreed that the customer doesn't have to pay the remaining 10.00. After you mark the invoice for settlement, you can also mark select **Full settlement**. The invoice will then be considered fully settled. The 10.00 difference is posted to a cash discount account as an additional cash discount amount.\n\n"}