{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,109],"content":"Performance Benchmark Software Development Toolkit (SDK) for Dynamics AX 2012","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Performance Benchmark Software Development Toolkit (SDK) for Dynamics AX 2012","pos":[0,77]}]},{"pos":[123,337],"content":"The Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 Performance Benchmark Software Development Toolkit (SDK) provides partners and customers with extensible features to develop benchmarks that closely mimic their custom implementation.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"The Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 Performance Benchmark Software Development Toolkit (SDK) provides partners and customers with extensible features to develop benchmarks that closely mimic their custom implementation.","pos":[0,214]}]},{"pos":[827,904],"content":"Performance Benchmark Software Development Toolkit (SDK) for Dynamics AX 2012","linkify":"Performance Benchmark Software Development Toolkit (SDK) for Dynamics AX 2012","nodes":[{"content":"Performance Benchmark Software Development Toolkit (SDK) for Dynamics AX 2012","pos":[0,77]}]},{"content":"The Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 Performance Benchmark Software Development Toolkit (SDK) provides partners and customers with extensible features to develop benchmarks that closely mimic their custom implementation.","pos":[906,1120]},{"content":"The Benchmark SDK lets partners and customers quickly develop managed tests that simulate multiple-user activity on Microsoft Dynamics AX.","pos":[1122,1260]},{"content":"The Benchmark SDK is developed by using Microsoft Visual Studio 2010; therefore, you can use the Load Test functionality to run stress and performance tests for Microsoft Dynamics AX.","pos":[1261,1444]},{"content":"This lets you set benchmarks for any Microsoft Dynamics AX scenario more easily, because you can collect test results from the Benchmark SDK.","pos":[1445,1586]},{"content":"The Benchmark SDK has been moved.","pos":[1587,1620]},{"content":"It is now available from the Downloadable tools section of Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services.","pos":[1621,1718]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Go to Lifecycle Services<ept id=\"p1\">](https://lcs.dynamics.com)</ept>.","pos":[1719,1772],"source":"[Go to Lifecycle Services](https://lcs.dynamics.com)."},{"content":"The documentation for the SDK is available as a white paper.","pos":[1773,1833]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Download the paper<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=306262)</ept>","pos":[1834,1901],"source":"[Download the paper](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=306262)"}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Performance Benchmark Software Development Toolkit (SDK) for Dynamics AX 2012\ndescription: The Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 Performance Benchmark Software Development Toolkit (SDK) provides partners and customers with extensible features to develop benchmarks that closely mimic their custom implementation.\nauthor: RobinARH\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 2015-12-05 23 - 18 - 15\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Lifecycle Services\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: annbe\nms.search.scope: AX 2012\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 18921\nms.assetid: 065f11c4-88ee-48d0-b849-8bc80fdae983\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: robadawy\nms.dyn365.ops.intro: \nms.dyn365.ops.version: 2012\n\n---\n\n# Performance Benchmark Software Development Toolkit (SDK) for Dynamics AX 2012\n\nThe Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 Performance Benchmark Software Development Toolkit (SDK) provides partners and customers with extensible features to develop benchmarks that closely mimic their custom implementation.\n\nThe Benchmark SDK lets partners and customers quickly develop managed tests that simulate multiple-user activity on Microsoft Dynamics AX. The Benchmark SDK is developed by using Microsoft Visual Studio 2010; therefore, you can use the Load Test functionality to run stress and performance tests for Microsoft Dynamics AX. This lets you set benchmarks for any Microsoft Dynamics AX scenario more easily, because you can collect test results from the Benchmark SDK. The Benchmark SDK has been moved. It is now available from the Downloadable tools section of Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services. [Go to Lifecycle Services](https://lcs.dynamics.com). The documentation for the SDK is available as a white paper. [Download the paper](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=306262)\n\n"}