{"nodes":[{"pos":[2,19],"content":"Welcome to Retail","linkify":"Welcome to Retail","nodes":[{"content":"Welcome to Retail","pos":[0,17]}]},{"content":"Dynamics 365 for Operations – Retail delivers a complete shopping experience, with a seamless and differentiating omni-channel solution that is modern, mobile, and global.","pos":[20,191]},{"content":"End-to-end capabilities, from modern point of sale (POS) software solutions, store operations, merchandising, e-commerce, call center, marketing, and customer care, to supply chain, financials, and more, can be deployed in the way that makes the most sense for your business.","pos":[192,467]},{"content":"This page points to resources that will help you use Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations - Retail more effectively.","pos":[469,586]},{"content":"On the leftmost pane, select a feature area to learn more about it.","pos":[587,654]},{"pos":[660,682],"content":"Set up Retail channels","linkify":"Set up Retail channels","nodes":[{"content":"Set up Retail channels","pos":[0,22]}]},{"content":"As you set up your Retail experience, you'll decide how to define and configure your brick and mortar store (called retail store in Dynamics 365 for Operations) and online store operations.","pos":[683,872]},{"content":"Each retail store can have its own payment methods, price groups, POS solutions, income accounts and expense accounts, and staff.","pos":[875,1004]},{"content":"After you create your retail store, you assign the products that you want the store to carry.","pos":[1005,1098]},{"content":"You also assign employees, registers, and customers to the store.","pos":[1099,1164]},{"content":"Finally, you add the new store to an organization hierarchy.","pos":[1165,1225]},{"content":"When you create your online store, you must set up components such as assortments, attributes, payment methods, and shipping methods.","pos":[1227,1360]},{"content":"You can also define prices, promotions, discounts, and shipping terms that are specific to the online store.","pos":[1361,1469]},{"pos":[1475,1535],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Define retail channels<ept id=\"p1\">](define-maintain-retail-channels.md)</ept>","source":"[Define retail channels](define-maintain-retail-channels.md)"},{"pos":[1540,1581],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Online store overview<ept id=\"p1\">](online-stores.md)</ept>","source":"[Online store overview](online-stores.md)"},{"pos":[1586,1606],"content":"Set up a call center","linkify":"Set up a call center","nodes":[{"content":"Set up a call center","pos":[0,20]}]},{"content":"You can set up a call center as a type of retail channel.","pos":[1607,1664]},{"content":"In a call center, workers take orders from customers over the phone and create sales orders.","pos":[1665,1757]},{"content":"To help your workers take orders and handle customer service throughout the order fulfillment process, you can set up what a sales order will contain, how pricing will be controlled, and what data about customers, products, and pricing can be accessed.","pos":[1758,2010]},{"content":"For each call center, you can also set up users, payment methods, price groups, financial dimensions, and modes of delivery.","pos":[2011,2135]},{"pos":[2141,2198],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Call center functionality<ept id=\"p1\">](call-center-functionality.md)</ept>","source":"[Call center functionality](call-center-functionality.md)"},{"pos":[2203,2264],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Create call center catalogs<ept id=\"p1\">](create-call-center-catalogs.md)</ept>","source":"[Create call center catalogs](create-call-center-catalogs.md)"},{"pos":[2269,2303],"content":"Define your POS and MPOS solutions","linkify":"Define your POS and MPOS solutions","nodes":[{"content":"Define your POS and MPOS solutions","pos":[0,34]}]},{"content":"Retail Modern POS (MPOS) is a point-of-sale app for PCs, tablets, and phones.","pos":[2304,2381]},{"content":"Sales staff can process sales transactions, customer orders, and perform daily operations and inventory management with mobile devices anywhere in the store, as well as at PC-based registers.","pos":[2382,2573]},{"content":"Cloud POS is a browser-based POS.","pos":[2574,2607]},{"content":"There are several components you’ll set up to define the relationships among a store, the POS registers or channels within the store, and the retail peripherals that those registers or channels use to process transactions.","pos":[2610,2832]},{"content":"You’ll also define the characteristics of a specific instance of the POS, including the hardware profile or setup for retail peripherals that will be used at the register, the store that the register is mapped to, and the visual experience for the user who logs on to that register.","pos":[2833,3115]},{"pos":[3121,3250],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Define and maintain channel clients, registers, and hardware stations<ept id=\"p1\">](define-maintain-channel-clients-registers-hw-stations.md)</ept>","source":"[Define and maintain channel clients, registers, and hardware stations](define-maintain-channel-clients-registers-hw-stations.md)"},{"pos":[3255,3323],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Configure and install MPOS<ept id=\"p1\">](retail-modern-pos-device-activation.md)</ept>","source":"[Configure and install MPOS](retail-modern-pos-device-activation.md)"},{"pos":[3328,3385],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Offline POS functionality<ept id=\"p1\">](pos-offline-functionality.md)</ept>","source":"[Offline POS functionality](pos-offline-functionality.md)"},{"pos":[3390,3434],"content":"Customize and administer Retail environments","linkify":"Customize and administer Retail environments","nodes":[{"content":"Customize and administer Retail environments","pos":[0,44]}]},{"content":"If you have been asked to customize your environment, or if you are tasked with deploying and maintaining your system, check out the developer and system administrator content specific to Retail, as well as the more general content for Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations.","pos":[3435,3709]},{"pos":[3715,3815],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Dynamics 365 for Operations - Retail for IT Pros and Developers<ept id=\"p1\">](dev-itpro/dev-retail-home-page.md)</ept>","source":"[Dynamics 365 for Operations - Retail for IT Pros and Developers](dev-itpro/dev-retail-home-page.md)"},{"pos":[3820,3951],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations for Developers and IT Pros<ept id=\"p1\">](/dynamics365/operations/dev-itpro/dev-tools/developer-home-page)</ept>","source":"[Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations for Developers and IT Pros](/dynamics365/operations/dev-itpro/dev-tools/developer-home-page)"},{"pos":[3958,3972],"content":"More resources","linkify":"More resources","nodes":[{"content":"More resources","pos":[0,14]}]},{"pos":[3977,4006],"content":"What's new and in development","linkify":"What's new and in development","nodes":[{"content":"What's new and in development","pos":[0,29]}]},{"pos":[4007,4161],"content":"Go to the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;a href=\"https://roadmap.dynamics.com/\"&gt;</bpt>Dynamics 365 Roadmap<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/a&gt;</ept> to see what new features are released and what new features are in development.","source":"Go to the <a href=\"https://roadmap.dynamics.com/\">Dynamics 365 Roadmap</a> to see what new features are released and what new features are in development."},{"pos":[4168,4173],"content":"Blogs","linkify":"Blogs","nodes":[{"content":"Blogs","pos":[0,5]}]},{"pos":[4174,4397],"content":"You can find opinions, news, and other information about Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations - Retail and other solutions on the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;a href=\"https://community.dynamics.com/b/msftdynamicsblog\"&gt;</bpt>Microsoft Dynamics 365 blog<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/a&gt;</ept>.","source":"You can find opinions, news, and other information about Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations - Retail and other solutions on the <a href=\"https://community.dynamics.com/b/msftdynamicsblog\">Microsoft Dynamics 365 blog</a>."},{"content":"There are many topics about Retail on the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;a href=\"https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/dax/\"&gt;</bpt>Microsoft Dynamics AX product team blog<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/a&gt;</ept>.","pos":[4399,4533],"source":"There are many topics about Retail on the <a href=\"https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/dax/\">Microsoft Dynamics AX product team blog</a>."},{"content":"Some of these posts were written for the previous version of Dynamics 365 for Operations, but the same concepts still apply, and the procedures are similar in the current version.","pos":[4534,4713]},{"pos":[4715,4975],"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;a href=\"https://community.dynamics.com/partner/b/operationspartnercommunityblog\"&gt;</bpt>Microsoft Dynamics Operations Partner Community Blog<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/a&gt;</ept> provides Microsoft Dynamics Partners with a single resource to learn about what’s new and trending in MBS Operations.","source":"The <a href=\"https://community.dynamics.com/partner/b/operationspartnercommunityblog\">Microsoft Dynamics Operations Partner Community Blog</a> provides Microsoft Dynamics Partners with a single resource to learn about what’s new and trending in MBS Operations."}],"content":"# Welcome to Retail\nDynamics 365 for Operations – Retail delivers a complete shopping experience, with a seamless and differentiating omni-channel solution that is modern, mobile, and global. End-to-end capabilities, from modern point of sale (POS) software solutions, store operations, merchandising, e-commerce, call center, marketing, and customer care, to supply chain, financials, and more, can be deployed in the way that makes the most sense for your business.\n\nThis page points to resources that will help you use Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations - Retail more effectively. On the leftmost pane, select a feature area to learn more about it. \n\n## Set up Retail channels\nAs you set up your Retail experience, you'll decide how to define and configure your brick and mortar store (called retail store in Dynamics 365 for Operations) and online store operations. \n\nEach retail store can have its own payment methods, price groups, POS solutions, income accounts and expense accounts, and staff. After you create your retail store, you assign the products that you want the store to carry. You also assign employees, registers, and customers to the store. Finally, you add the new store to an organization hierarchy.\n\nWhen you create your online store, you must set up components such as assortments, attributes, payment methods, and shipping methods. You can also define prices, promotions, discounts, and shipping terms that are specific to the online store.\n\n-   [Define retail channels](define-maintain-retail-channels.md)\n-   [Online store overview](online-stores.md)\n\n## Set up a call center\nYou can set up a call center as a type of retail channel. In a call center, workers take orders from customers over the phone and create sales orders. To help your workers take orders and handle customer service throughout the order fulfillment process, you can set up what a sales order will contain, how pricing will be controlled, and what data about customers, products, and pricing can be accessed. For each call center, you can also set up users, payment methods, price groups, financial dimensions, and modes of delivery.\n\n-   [Call center functionality](call-center-functionality.md)\n-   [Create call center catalogs](create-call-center-catalogs.md)\n\n## Define your POS and MPOS solutions\nRetail Modern POS (MPOS) is a point-of-sale app for PCs, tablets, and phones. Sales staff can process sales transactions, customer orders, and perform daily operations and inventory management with mobile devices anywhere in the store, as well as at PC-based registers. Cloud POS is a browser-based POS. \n\nThere are several components you’ll set up to define the relationships among a store, the POS registers or channels within the store, and the retail peripherals that those registers or channels use to process transactions. You’ll also define the characteristics of a specific instance of the POS, including the hardware profile or setup for retail peripherals that will be used at the register, the store that the register is mapped to, and the visual experience for the user who logs on to that register.\n\n-   [Define and maintain channel clients, registers, and hardware stations](define-maintain-channel-clients-registers-hw-stations.md)\n-   [Configure and install MPOS](retail-modern-pos-device-activation.md)\n-   [Offline POS functionality](pos-offline-functionality.md)\n\n## Customize and administer Retail environments\nIf you have been asked to customize your environment, or if you are tasked with deploying and maintaining your system, check out the developer and system administrator content specific to Retail, as well as the more general content for Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations. \n-   [Dynamics 365 for Operations - Retail for IT Pros and Developers](dev-itpro/dev-retail-home-page.md)\n-   [Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations for Developers and IT Pros](/dynamics365/operations/dev-itpro/dev-tools/developer-home-page)\n\n\n\n## More resources\n### What's new and in development\nGo to the <a href=\"https://roadmap.dynamics.com/\">Dynamics 365 Roadmap</a> to see what new features are released and what new features are in development. \n\n### Blogs\nYou can find opinions, news, and other information about Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations - Retail and other solutions on the <a href=\"https://community.dynamics.com/b/msftdynamicsblog\">Microsoft Dynamics 365 blog</a>.\n\nThere are many topics about Retail on the <a href=\"https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/dax/\">Microsoft Dynamics AX product team blog</a>. Some of these posts were written for the previous version of Dynamics 365 for Operations, but the same concepts still apply, and the procedures are similar in the current version.\n\nThe <a href=\"https://community.dynamics.com/partner/b/operationspartnercommunityblog\">Microsoft Dynamics Operations Partner Community Blog</a> provides Microsoft Dynamics Partners with a single resource to learn about what’s new and trending in MBS Operations.\n"}