{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,68],"content":"Global address book | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Global address book | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,36]}]},{"pos":[251,284],"content":"DirPartyTable, DirPartyTableRoles","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"DirPartyTable, DirPartyTableRoles","pos":[0,33]}]},{"pos":[525,544],"content":"Global address book","linkify":"Global address book","nodes":[{"content":"Global address book","pos":[0,19]}]},{"content":"The global address book can help you understand the relationships among the people and organizations that are associated with your organization.","pos":[548,692]},{"content":"For example, a customer might also be a vendor in a marketing campaign, or a worker in your organization might also be a vendor.","pos":[693,821]},{"content":"The global address book is a centralized repository for master data that must be stored for all internal and external persons and organizations that the company interacts with.","pos":[822,998]},{"content":"The data that is associated with party records includes the party's name, address, and contact information.","pos":[999,1106]},{"content":"Other details vary, depending on whether the party is a person or an organization.","pos":[1107,1189]},{"content":"Each party record is assigned to a party, and each party can be associated with one or more party roles in a company.","pos":[1190,1307]},{"content":"Party roles include customer, prospect, worker, user, vendor, competitor, applicant, and contact.","pos":[1308,1405]},{"content":"For example, the organization party First Up Consultants, can be associated with customer, business relation, and vendor roles in the CEE company, and can also be associated with the vendor role in the CEU company.","pos":[1406,1620]},{"content":"Here are some of the benefits of this shared data:","pos":[1621,1671]},{"content":"The data shows the relationships that people and organizations have with other areas of the company.","pos":[1677,1777]},{"content":"The relationship between two organizations changes when one organization has multiple roles, such as vendor and customer.","pos":[1778,1899]},{"content":"Communication between the two organization also changes.","pos":[1900,1956]},{"content":"There might be special agreements that can be negotiated to encourage a closer partnership with the other organization.","pos":[1957,2076]},{"content":"Setup and maintenance are easier.","pos":[2081,2114]},{"content":"For example, when an address changes, the update must be made in only one place.","pos":[2115,2195]},{"content":"All the other associated records are updated automatically.","pos":[2196,2255]},{"content":"Before you begin to work with address books, you can set the default values and enable the parameters.","pos":[2257,2359]},{"content":"You can optionally grant security privileges, so that workers can access your organization's address books or party records.","pos":[2360,2484]},{"content":"You can also enable the parameters for each party record individually in the global address book.","pos":[2485,2582]},{"content":"You can create multiple address books, and assign teams or grant privileges to address books by legal entity.","pos":[2583,2692]},{"content":"Before you create address books for your organization or import information for party records, you should determine the number and types of address books that your organization requires.","pos":[2693,2879]},{"content":"You can then grant privileges to each address book.","pos":[2880,2931]},{"content":"After your organization determines the number and types of address books that it requires, and after you set the default parameters for the address books, you can create one or more address books.","pos":[2932,3128]},{"content":"These address books belong to the global address book for your organization.","pos":[3129,3205]},{"content":"You can set security parameters for the address books at any time.","pos":[3206,3272]},{"content":"You aren't required to set security restrictions to control access to address books, but if you don't, all workers in your organization can access all party records.","pos":[3273,3438]},{"content":"Address book security can be set in three ways:","pos":[3439,3486]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Secure by legal entity<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Security privileges are based on the legal entity that a party is associated with.","pos":[3492,3603],"source":"**Secure by legal entity** – Security privileges are based on the legal entity that a party is associated with."},{"content":"If you use this method, workers can access only the records that are associated with a legal entity that the worker has access to.","pos":[3604,3734]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Secure by address book<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Security privileges are based on teams.","pos":[3739,3807],"source":"**Secure by address book** – Security privileges are based on teams."},{"content":"If you use this method, only workers who are assigned to a team that has access to an address book can view the party records in that address book.","pos":[3808,3955]},{"pos":[3960,4074],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Secure by both legal entity and address book<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Security privileges are based on both legal entities and teams.","source":"**Secure by both legal entity and address book** – Security privileges are based on both legal entities and teams."},{"pos":[4079,4112],"content":"How the global address book works","linkify":"How the global address book works","nodes":[{"content":"How the global address book works","pos":[0,33]}]},{"content":"The following illustration shows how party records, party roles, locations, and transactions interact and relate to an address book.","pos":[4113,4245]},{"content":"As the illustration shows, a party record can belong to one or more address books.","pos":[4246,4328]},{"content":"Each party record can store one or more locations, or addresses, and is assigned a party role.","pos":[4329,4423]},{"content":"The role that is assigned to the party record can have specific transactions types associated with it.","pos":[4424,4526]},{"content":"The following sections provide more information about party roles, locations, and transaction types.","pos":[4527,4627]},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">\\[</ph>caption id=\"attachment<ph id=\"ph2\">\\_</ph>179501\" align=\"alignnone\" width=\"300\"<ph id=\"ph3\">\\]</ph><bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph4\">![</ph>Global address book interaction with AX entities and transactions<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/address-book-structure-300x157.png)](./media/address-book-structure.png)</ept> A graphical representation of the ways that parties, party roles, locations, and transactions interact in relation to the global address book.<ph id=\"ph5\">\\[</ph>/caption<ph id=\"ph6\">\\]</ph>","pos":[4628,4998],"source":"\\[caption id=\"attachment\\_179501\" align=\"alignnone\" width=\"300\"\\][![Global address book interaction with AX entities and transactions](./media/address-book-structure-300x157.png)](./media/address-book-structure.png) A graphical representation of the ways that parties, party roles, locations, and transactions interact in relation to the global address book.\\[/caption\\]"},{"pos":[5004,5015],"content":"Party roles","linkify":"Party roles","nodes":[{"content":"Party roles","pos":[0,11]}]},{"content":"Roles that are associated with party records are referred to as party roles.","pos":[5017,5093]},{"content":"There are several party roles, and they can be assigned to both party types, person and organization.","pos":[5094,5195]},{"content":"Here are the definitions for each party role:","pos":[5196,5241]},{"pos":[5247,5399],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Customer<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Individuals, companies, or other entities who purchase goods and services that are produced by other individuals, companies, or entities.","source":"**Customer** – Individuals, companies, or other entities who purchase goods and services that are produced by other individuals, companies, or entities."},{"pos":[5404,5485],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Prospect<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – A party that might provide a service or benefit to a legal entity.","source":"**Prospect** – A party that might provide a service or benefit to a legal entity."},{"pos":[5490,5606],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Worker<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – A person who assumes the role of an employee or a contractor, and who is paid in exchange for services.","source":"**Worker** – A person who assumes the role of an employee or a contractor, and who is paid in exchange for services."},{"pos":[5611,5659],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>User<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – A person who is a user of the system.","source":"**User** – A person who is a user of the system."},{"pos":[5664,5762],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Vendor<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – A party that supplies products to one or more legal entities in exchange for payment.","source":"**Vendor** – A party that supplies products to one or more legal entities in exchange for payment."},{"pos":[5767,5911],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Competitor<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – A person or organization that provides goods or services that are similar to the goods or services that your business provides.","source":"**Competitor** – A person or organization that provides goods or services that are similar to the goods or services that your business provides."},{"pos":[5916,6046],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Applicant<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – A person who makes a formal written or electronic request to work for or fill an open position in an organization.","source":"**Applicant** – A person who makes a formal written or electronic request to work for or fill an open position in an organization."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Contact<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – A person, either inside or outside your organization, that you have created an entry for.","pos":[6051,6154],"source":"**Contact** – A person, either inside or outside your organization, that you have created an entry for."},{"content":"In this entry, you can save information such as the person's street and email addresses, telephone and fax numbers, and webpage URLs.","pos":[6155,6288]},{"pos":[6294,6320],"content":"Creating new party records","linkify":"Creating new party records","nodes":[{"content":"Creating new party records","pos":[0,26]}]},{"content":"There are two ways to enter party records in the global address book:","pos":[6322,6391]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Creating a party record when you don't know the role<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – When you create a party record and don't know the role type (for example, you don't know whether the party is a customer or an opportunity), you create the record in the global address book.","pos":[6397,6646],"source":"**Creating a party record when you don't know the role** – When you create a party record and don't know the role type (for example, you don't know whether the party is a customer or an opportunity), you create the record in the global address book."},{"content":"You can select the role type later.","pos":[6647,6682]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Creating a party record when you know the role<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – If you know the role type for the party, you can create a record on the appropriate page for that type.","pos":[6687,6843],"source":"**Creating a party record when you know the role** – If you know the role type for the party, you can create a record on the appropriate page for that type."},{"content":"For example, if the party is a customer, you create a record on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Customer<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[6844,6930],"source":" For example, if the party is a customer, you create a record on the **Customer** page."},{"content":"When you create and save a record by using the page for the party's role type, the record is automatically created in the global address book.","pos":[6931,7073]},{"pos":[7079,7107],"content":"Party roles and transactions","linkify":"Party roles and transactions","nodes":[{"content":"Party roles and transactions","pos":[0,28]}]},{"content":"For transactions that are a part of the business processes, multiple parties might be associated with each transaction.","pos":[7109,7228]},{"content":"An example is a customer that needs to be referenced on project quotations.","pos":[7229,7304]},{"pos":[7310,7363],"content":"Parties locations, addresses, and contact information","linkify":"Parties locations, addresses, and contact information","nodes":[{"content":"Parties locations, addresses, and contact information","pos":[0,53]}]},{"content":"Each party record’s addresses, locations, and contact information are shared across all the party roles that are associated with that party.","pos":[7365,7505]},{"content":"Therefore, when any of this information is changed, all other associated records are updated accordingly.","pos":[7506,7611]},{"pos":[7617,7643],"content":"Locations and transactions","linkify":"Locations and transactions","nodes":[{"content":"Locations and transactions","pos":[0,26]}]},{"content":"When a party role is included in a transaction, the location, address, or contact information of the party can be accessed when transaction details are entered.","pos":[7645,7805]}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Global address book | Microsoft Docs\ndescription: \nauthor: kfend\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 2015-12-11 23:25:07\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nkeywords: DirPartyTable, DirPartyTableRoles\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: 51\nms.suite: Released- Dynamics AX 7.0.0\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 23521\nms.assetid: 7e2e9256-60fa-4997-8a3b-9cf8037ff320\nms.region: Global\n# ms.industry: \nms.author: kfend\n\n---\n\n# Global address book\n\n\n\nThe global address book can help you understand the relationships among the people and organizations that are associated with your organization. For example, a customer might also be a vendor in a marketing campaign, or a worker in your organization might also be a vendor. The global address book is a centralized repository for master data that must be stored for all internal and external persons and organizations that the company interacts with. The data that is associated with party records includes the party's name, address, and contact information. Other details vary, depending on whether the party is a person or an organization. Each party record is assigned to a party, and each party can be associated with one or more party roles in a company. Party roles include customer, prospect, worker, user, vendor, competitor, applicant, and contact. For example, the organization party First Up Consultants, can be associated with customer, business relation, and vendor roles in the CEE company, and can also be associated with the vendor role in the CEU company. Here are some of the benefits of this shared data:\n\n-   The data shows the relationships that people and organizations have with other areas of the company. The relationship between two organizations changes when one organization has multiple roles, such as vendor and customer. Communication between the two organization also changes. There might be special agreements that can be negotiated to encourage a closer partnership with the other organization.\n-   Setup and maintenance are easier. For example, when an address changes, the update must be made in only one place. All the other associated records are updated automatically.\n\nBefore you begin to work with address books, you can set the default values and enable the parameters. You can optionally grant security privileges, so that workers can access your organization's address books or party records. You can also enable the parameters for each party record individually in the global address book. You can create multiple address books, and assign teams or grant privileges to address books by legal entity. Before you create address books for your organization or import information for party records, you should determine the number and types of address books that your organization requires. You can then grant privileges to each address book. After your organization determines the number and types of address books that it requires, and after you set the default parameters for the address books, you can create one or more address books. These address books belong to the global address book for your organization. You can set security parameters for the address books at any time. You aren't required to set security restrictions to control access to address books, but if you don't, all workers in your organization can access all party records. Address book security can be set in three ways:\n\n-   **Secure by legal entity** – Security privileges are based on the legal entity that a party is associated with. If you use this method, workers can access only the records that are associated with a legal entity that the worker has access to.\n-   **Secure by address book** – Security privileges are based on teams. If you use this method, only workers who are assigned to a team that has access to an address book can view the party records in that address book.\n-   **Secure by both legal entity and address book** – Security privileges are based on both legal entities and teams.\n\n## How the global address book works\nThe following illustration shows how party records, party roles, locations, and transactions interact and relate to an address book. As the illustration shows, a party record can belong to one or more address books. Each party record can store one or more locations, or addresses, and is assigned a party role. The role that is assigned to the party record can have specific transactions types associated with it. The following sections provide more information about party roles, locations, and transaction types. \\[caption id=\"attachment\\_179501\" align=\"alignnone\" width=\"300\"\\][![Global address book interaction with AX entities and transactions](./media/address-book-structure-300x157.png)](./media/address-book-structure.png) A graphical representation of the ways that parties, party roles, locations, and transactions interact in relation to the global address book.\\[/caption\\]\n\n### Party roles\n\nRoles that are associated with party records are referred to as party roles. There are several party roles, and they can be assigned to both party types, person and organization. Here are the definitions for each party role:\n\n-   **Customer** – Individuals, companies, or other entities who purchase goods and services that are produced by other individuals, companies, or entities.\n-   **Prospect** – A party that might provide a service or benefit to a legal entity.\n-   **Worker** – A person who assumes the role of an employee or a contractor, and who is paid in exchange for services.\n-   **User** – A person who is a user of the system.\n-   **Vendor** – A party that supplies products to one or more legal entities in exchange for payment.\n-   **Competitor** – A person or organization that provides goods or services that are similar to the goods or services that your business provides.\n-   **Applicant** – A person who makes a formal written or electronic request to work for or fill an open position in an organization.\n-   **Contact** – A person, either inside or outside your organization, that you have created an entry for. In this entry, you can save information such as the person's street and email addresses, telephone and fax numbers, and webpage URLs.\n\n### Creating new party records\n\nThere are two ways to enter party records in the global address book:\n\n-   **Creating a party record when you don't know the role** – When you create a party record and don't know the role type (for example, you don't know whether the party is a customer or an opportunity), you create the record in the global address book. You can select the role type later.\n-   **Creating a party record when you know the role** – If you know the role type for the party, you can create a record on the appropriate page for that type. For example, if the party is a customer, you create a record on the **Customer** page. When you create and save a record by using the page for the party's role type, the record is automatically created in the global address book.\n\n### Party roles and transactions\n\nFor transactions that are a part of the business processes, multiple parties might be associated with each transaction. An example is a customer that needs to be referenced on project quotations.\n\n### Parties locations, addresses, and contact information\n\nEach party record’s addresses, locations, and contact information are shared across all the party roles that are associated with that party. Therefore, when any of this information is changed, all other associated records are updated accordingly.\n\n### Locations and transactions\n\nWhen a party role is included in a transaction, the location, address, or contact information of the party can be accessed when transaction details are entered.\n\n"}