{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Create vendor payments by using a payment proposal\ndescription: This topic provides an overview of the payment proposal options and includes some examples that show how payment proposals work. Payment proposals are often used to create vendor payments, because the query can be used to quickly select vendor invoices for payment, based on criteria such as the due date and cash discount. \nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 04/04/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: LedgerJournalTransVendPaym\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \n# ms.reviewer: 101\nms.search.scope: AX 7.0.0, Operations, Core\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 14312\nms.assetid: 585d5b0b-1b79-4a03-ab18-528918070377\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: kweekley\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Create vendor payments by using a payment proposal\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThis topic provides an overview of the payment proposal options and includes some examples that show how payment proposals work. Payment proposals are often used to create vendor payments, because the query can be used to quickly select vendor invoices for payment, based on criteria such as the due date and cash discount. \n\nOrganizations often use payment proposals to create vendor payments, because the payment proposal query can be used to quickly select vendor invoices for payment, based on the due date, cash discount, and other criteria. \n\nThe payment proposal query contains various tabs, each of which has different options for selecting invoices to pay. The **Parameter** tab contains options that a majority of organization use most often. On the **Records to include** FastTab, you can specify which invoices or vendors to include for payment by defining ranges for various characteristics. For example, if you want to pay only a specific range of vendors, you can define a filter for the vendor range. This functionality is often used to select invoices for a specific of method of payment. For example, if you define a filter where **Method of payment** = **Check**, only invoices that have that method of payment are selected for payment, provided that they also meet other criteria that are specified in the query. The **Advanced parameters** tab contains additional options, some of which might not be relevant to your organization. For example, this tab contains the options for paying invoices for centralized payments.\n\n## Parameters\n-   **Select invoices by** – Invoices within the date range that is specified by the **From date** and **To date** fields can be selected by due date, cash discount date, or both. If you use the cash discount date, the system first looks for invoices that have a cash discount date between the from date and to date. The system then determines whether the invoice is eligible for the cash discount by using the session date to make sure that the cash discount date hasn’t already passed.\n-   **From date** and **To date** – Invoices that have a due date or cash discount date within this date range are selected for payment.\n-   **Payment date** – If a date is defined, all payments are created on this date. The **Minimum payment date** field is ignored.\n-   **Minimum payment date** – Enter the minimum payment date. For example, the **From date** and **To date** fields specify a range from September 1 to September 10, and the minimum payment date is September 5. In this case, all invoices that have a due date from September 1 to September 5 have a payment date of September 5. However, all invoices that have a due date from September 5 to September 10 have a payment date that is equal to the due date of each invoice.\n-   **Amount limit** – Enter the maximum total amount for all payments.\n-   **Create payments without invoice preview** – If this option is set to **Yes**, payments will be created immediately on the **Vendor payments** page. The **Payment proposal** page will be skipped. Therefore, payments will be created more quickly. Payments can still be modified from the **Vendor payments** page. Alternatively, you can return to the **Payment proposal** page by using the **Edit invoices for select payment** button.\n\n## Advanced options\n-   **Check vendor balance** – If this option is set to **Yes**, the system verifies that a vendor doesn’t have a debit balance before any invoice is paid. If a vendor does have a debit balance, no payment is created. For example, the vendor might have credit memos, or payments that have been posted but haven't been settled yet. In these cases, the vendor should not be paid. Instead, the credit memos or payments should be settled against the outstanding invoices.\n-   **Delete negative payments** – This option works differently, depending on whether payments are made for individual invoices or for the sum of invoices that meet the payment criteria. This behavior is defined on the method of payment.\n-   **Payment for each invoice** – If the **Delete negative payments** option is set to **Yes**, and an unsettled invoice and payment exist for a vendor, only the invoice is selected for payment. The existing payment isn't settled against the invoice. If the **Delete negative payments** option is set to **No**, and an invoice and a payment aren't settled, both the invoice and the payment are selected for payment. A payment is created for the payment, and a refund (negative payment) is created for the payment.\n-   **Payment for sum of invoices** – If the **Delete negative payments** option is set to **Yes**, and an unsettled invoice and payment exist for a vendor, both the unsettled invoice and the payment are selected for payment, and the amounts are added together to produce the total payment amount. The only exception occurs if the sum results in a refund. In this case, neither the invoice nor the payment is selected. If the **Delete negative payments **option is set to **No**, and an invoice and a payment aren't settled, both the invoice and the payment are selected for payment, and the amounts are added together to produce the total payment amount.\n-   **Print report only** – Set this option to **Yes** to see the results of the payment proposal on a report, but without creating any payments.\n-   **Include vendor invoices from other legal entities** – If your organization has a centralized process for payment, and the payment proposal should include invoices from other legal entities that are included in the search criteria, set this option to **Yes**.\n-   **Propose separate vendor payment per legal entity** – If this option is set to **Yes**, a separate payment is created for each legal entity per vendor. The vendor on the payment is the vendor from the invoice from each legal entity. If this option is set to **No**, and the same vendor has invoices in multiple legal entities, one payment is created for the total amount of the selected invoices. The vendor on the payment is the vendor in the current legal entity. If the vendor account doesn’t exist in the current legal entity, the vendor account of the first invoice that must be paid is used.\n-   **Payment currency** – This field specifies the currency that all payments are created in. If a currency isn’t defined, each invoice is paid in the currency of the invoice.\n-   **Payment weekday** – Enter the day of the week when the payment should be made. This field is used only if the method of payment is set up to total invoices for payment on a specific day of the week.\n-   **Offset account type** and **Offset account** – Set these fields to define a specific account type (such as **Ledger** or **Bank**) and offset account (such as a specific bank account). The method of payment for the invoice defines the default offset account type and offset account, but you can use these fields to override the default values.\n-   **Additional filters** – On the **Records to include** FastTab, you can define additional ranges of criteria. For example, if you want to pay only a range of vendors, you can define a filter for the vendor range. This functionality is often used to select invoices for a specific of method of payment. For example, if you define a filter where **Method of payment** = **Check**, only invoices that have that method of payment are selected for payment, provided that they also meet other criteria that are specified in the query.\n\n## Scenarios\n| Vendor | Invoice | Invoice date | Invoice amount | Due date | Cash discount date | Cash discount amount |\n|--------|---------|--------------|----------------|----------|--------------------|----------------------|\n| 3050   | 1001    | June 15      | 500.00         | July 15  | June 29            | 10.00                |\n| 3050   | 1002    | June 20      | 600.00         | July 20  | July 4             | 12.00                |\n| 3075   | 1003    | June 15      | 250.00         | June 29  |                    | 0.00                 |\n| 3100   | 1004    | June 17      | 100.00         | July 17  | July 1             | 1.00                 |\n\nOn July 1, April pays vendors. She uses a payment proposal to help her complete this task more efficiently.\n\n### Option 1: By cash discount\n\nApril selects **Cash discount** as the proposal type. She enters a date range of June 26 to July 10. The following invoices are included in the proposal:\n\n-   1002, because the discount date of July 4 is in the range of payment dates.\n-   1004, because the discount date of July 1 is in the range of payment dates.\n\nThe following invoices aren't included in the proposal:\n\n-   1001, because the discount date of June 29 has already expired, so this invoice is no longer eligible for the cash discount.\n-   1003, because this invoice doesn't have a discount date.\n\n### Option 2: By due date\n\nApril selects **Per due date** as the proposal type. She enters a date range of June 26 to July 10. The following invoices are included in the proposal:\n\n-   1003, because the due date of June 29 is in the range of payment dates.\n\nThe following invoices aren't included in the proposal:\n\n-   1001, because the due date of July 15 is outside the range of payment dates.\n-   1002, because the due date of July 20 is outside the range of payment dates.\n-   1004, because the due date of July 17 is outside the range of payment dates.\n\n### Option 3: By due date and cash discount\n\nApril selects **Due date and cash discount** as the proposal type. She enters a date range of June 26 to July 10. The following invoices are included in the proposal:\n\n-   1003, because the due date of June 29 is in the range of payment dates.\n-   1002, because the discount date of July 4 is in the range of payment dates.\n-   1004, because the discount date of July 1 is in the range of payment dates.\n\nThe following invoices aren't included in the proposal:\n\n-   1001, because the discount date of June 29 has already expired, so this invoice is no longer eligible for the cash discount, and the due date of July 15 is also outside the date range.\n\n## Country specific considerations\n### Norway\n\n#### Dimension control\n\nDimension control allows you to control grouping of generated lines by payment proposal and set default dimensions based on financial dimensions used for the applied invoices. Under Norwegian country context for each method of payment there is financial dimension tab where you can activate dimension control as well as enable grouping for each dimension. Possible options are:\n\n-   **Dimension control** field is disabled. The payment proposal behaves as for any other country.\n-   **Dimension control** field is activated without further defining the dimensions. The payment proposal will be created without taking dimensions into consideration. The created transaction inherits no dimensions from the applied entry.\n-   **Dimension control** field is activated and the further dimensions are enabled. Now you define how the dimensions will be copied to the journal. For example: • Select the **BusinessUnit** check box to create a payment proposal per business unit for the method of payment, • Select the **CostCenter** check box to create a payment proposal per cost center for the method of payment\n\n**Note:** If you select more than one dimension in the third option, a payment proposal is created for the dimension combination.\n\n#### Bank account selection\n\nYou can define a standard debiting payment account per method of payment regardless country context. This will be set in payment lines generated by a proposal. With the bank account feature, you can define multiple debiting bank accounts managed by dimension and currency or a combination of these to use different debiting bank accounts, depending on each combination. You can set up these combinations in **Methods of payments** page by using the **Bank accounts** button available for each method of payment with **Posting account type** = **Bank**.\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[32,82],"content":"Create vendor payments by using a payment proposal","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Create vendor payments by using a payment proposal","pos":[0,50]}]},{"pos":[96,419],"content":"This topic provides an overview of the payment proposal options and includes some examples that show how payment proposals work. Payment proposals are often used to create vendor payments, because the query can be used to quickly select vendor invoices for payment, based on criteria such as the due date and cash discount.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"This topic provides an overview of the payment proposal options and includes some examples that show how payment proposals work. Payment proposals are often used to create vendor payments, because the query can be used to quickly select vendor invoices for payment, based on criteria such as the due date and cash discount.","pos":[0,323],"nodes":[{"content":"This topic provides an overview of the payment proposal options and includes some examples that show how payment proposals work.","pos":[0,128]},{"content":"Payment proposals are often used to create vendor payments, because the query can be used to quickly select vendor invoices for payment, based on criteria such as the due date and cash discount.","pos":[129,323]}]}]},{"pos":[956,1006],"content":"Create vendor payments by using a payment proposal","linkify":"Create vendor payments by using a payment proposal","nodes":[{"content":"Create vendor payments by using a payment proposal","pos":[0,50]}]},{"content":"This topic provides an overview of the payment proposal options and includes some examples that show how payment proposals work.","pos":[1052,1180]},{"content":"Payment proposals are often used to create vendor payments, because the query can be used to quickly select vendor invoices for payment, based on criteria such as the due date and cash discount.","pos":[1181,1375]},{"content":"Organizations often use payment proposals to create vendor payments, because the payment proposal query can be used to quickly select vendor invoices for payment, based on the due date, cash discount, and other criteria.","pos":[1378,1598]},{"content":"The payment proposal query contains various tabs, each of which has different options for selecting invoices to pay.","pos":[1601,1717]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Parameter<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab contains options that a majority of organization use most often.","pos":[1718,1804],"source":" The **Parameter** tab contains options that a majority of organization use most often."},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Records to include<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> FastTab, you can specify which invoices or vendors to include for payment by defining ranges for various characteristics.","pos":[1805,1956],"source":" On the **Records to include** FastTab, you can specify which invoices or vendors to include for payment by defining ranges for various characteristics."},{"content":"For example, if you want to pay only a specific range of vendors, you can define a filter for the vendor range.","pos":[1957,2068]},{"content":"This functionality is often used to select invoices for a specific of method of payment.","pos":[2069,2157]},{"content":"For example, if you define a filter where <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Method of payment<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph1\"> = </ph><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Check<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, only invoices that have that method of payment are selected for payment, provided that they also meet other criteria that are specified in the query.","pos":[2158,2384],"source":" For example, if you define a filter where **Method of payment** = **Check**, only invoices that have that method of payment are selected for payment, provided that they also meet other criteria that are specified in the query."},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Advanced parameters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab contains additional options, some of which might not be relevant to your organization.","pos":[2385,2503],"source":" The **Advanced parameters** tab contains additional options, some of which might not be relevant to your organization."},{"content":"For example, this tab contains the options for paying invoices for centralized payments.","pos":[2504,2592]},{"pos":[2597,2607],"content":"Parameters","linkify":"Parameters","nodes":[{"content":"Parameters","pos":[0,10]}]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Select invoices by<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Invoices within the date range that is specified by the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>From date<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>To date<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> fields can be selected by due date, cash discount date, or both.","pos":[2612,2787],"source":"**Select invoices by** – Invoices within the date range that is specified by the **From date** and **To date** fields can be selected by due date, cash discount date, or both."},{"content":"If you use the cash discount date, the system first looks for invoices that have a cash discount date between the from date and to date.","pos":[2788,2924]},{"content":"The system then determines whether the invoice is eligible for the cash discount by using the session date to make sure that the cash discount date hasn’t already passed.","pos":[2925,3095]},{"pos":[3100,3232],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>From date<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>To date<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> – Invoices that have a due date or cash discount date within this date range are selected for payment.","source":"**From date** and **To date** – Invoices that have a due date or cash discount date within this date range are selected for payment."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Payment date<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – If a date is defined, all payments are created on this date.","pos":[3237,3316],"source":"**Payment date** – If a date is defined, all payments are created on this date."},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Minimum payment date<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field is ignored.","pos":[3317,3363],"source":" The **Minimum payment date** field is ignored."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Minimum payment date<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Enter the minimum payment date.","pos":[3368,3426],"source":"**Minimum payment date** – Enter the minimum payment date."},{"content":"For example, the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>From date<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>To date<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> fields specify a range from September 1 to September 10, and the minimum payment date is September 5.","pos":[3427,3575],"source":" For example, the **From date** and **To date** fields specify a range from September 1 to September 10, and the minimum payment date is September 5."},{"content":"In this case, all invoices that have a due date from September 1 to September 5 have a payment date of September 5.","pos":[3576,3691]},{"content":"However, all invoices that have a due date from September 5 to September 10 have a payment date that is equal to the due date of each invoice.","pos":[3692,3834]},{"pos":[3839,3906],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Amount limit<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Enter the maximum total amount for all payments.","source":"**Amount limit** – Enter the maximum total amount for all payments."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Create payments without invoice preview<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – If this option is set to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Yes<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, payments will be created immediately on the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Vendor payments<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> page.","pos":[3911,4060],"source":"**Create payments without invoice preview** – If this option is set to **Yes**, payments will be created immediately on the **Vendor payments** page."},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Payment proposal<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page will be skipped.","pos":[4061,4107],"source":" The **Payment proposal** page will be skipped."},{"content":"Therefore, payments will be created more quickly.","pos":[4108,4157]},{"content":"Payments can still be modified from the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Vendor payments<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[4158,4223],"source":" Payments can still be modified from the **Vendor payments** page."},{"content":"Alternatively, you can return to the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Payment proposal<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page by using the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Edit invoices for select payment<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> button.","pos":[4224,4344],"source":" Alternatively, you can return to the **Payment proposal** page by using the **Edit invoices for select payment** button."},{"pos":[4349,4365],"content":"Advanced options","linkify":"Advanced options","nodes":[{"content":"Advanced options","pos":[0,16]}]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Check vendor balance<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – If this option is set to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Yes<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, the system verifies that a vendor doesn’t have a debit balance before any invoice is paid.","pos":[4370,4521],"source":"**Check vendor balance** – If this option is set to **Yes**, the system verifies that a vendor doesn’t have a debit balance before any invoice is paid."},{"content":"If a vendor does have a debit balance, no payment is created.","pos":[4522,4583]},{"content":"For example, the vendor might have credit memos, or payments that have been posted but haven't been settled yet.","pos":[4584,4696]},{"content":"In these cases, the vendor should not be paid.","pos":[4697,4743]},{"content":"Instead, the credit memos or payments should be settled against the outstanding invoices.","pos":[4744,4833]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Delete negative payments<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – This option works differently, depending on whether payments are made for individual invoices or for the sum of invoices that meet the payment criteria.","pos":[4838,5021],"source":"**Delete negative payments** – This option works differently, depending on whether payments are made for individual invoices or for the sum of invoices that meet the payment criteria."},{"content":"This behavior is defined on the method of payment.","pos":[5022,5072]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Payment for each invoice<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – If the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Delete negative payments<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> option is set to <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Yes<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>, and an unsettled invoice and payment exist for a vendor, only the invoice is selected for payment.","pos":[5077,5268],"source":"**Payment for each invoice** – If the **Delete negative payments** option is set to **Yes**, and an unsettled invoice and payment exist for a vendor, only the invoice is selected for payment."},{"content":"The existing payment isn't settled against the invoice.","pos":[5269,5324]},{"content":"If the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Delete negative payments<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option is set to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>No<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, and an invoice and a payment aren't settled, both the invoice and the payment are selected for payment.","pos":[5325,5489],"source":" If the **Delete negative payments** option is set to **No**, and an invoice and a payment aren't settled, both the invoice and the payment are selected for payment."},{"content":"A payment is created for the payment, and a refund (negative payment) is created for the payment.","pos":[5490,5587]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Payment for sum of invoices<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – If the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Delete negative payments<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> option is set to <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Yes<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>, and an unsettled invoice and payment exist for a vendor, both the unsettled invoice and the payment are selected for payment, and the amounts are added together to produce the total payment amount.","pos":[5592,5885],"source":"**Payment for sum of invoices** – If the **Delete negative payments** option is set to **Yes**, and an unsettled invoice and payment exist for a vendor, both the unsettled invoice and the payment are selected for payment, and the amounts are added together to produce the total payment amount."},{"content":"The only exception occurs if the sum results in a refund.","pos":[5886,5943]},{"content":"In this case, neither the invoice nor the payment is selected.","pos":[5944,6006]},{"content":"If the **Delete negative payments **option is set to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>No<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, and an invoice and a payment aren't settled, both the invoice and the payment are selected for payment, and the amounts are added together to produce the total payment amount.","pos":[6007,6243],"source":" If the **Delete negative payments **option is set to **No**, and an invoice and a payment aren't settled, both the invoice and the payment are selected for payment, and the amounts are added together to produce the total payment amount."},{"pos":[6248,6389],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Print report only<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Set this option to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Yes<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to see the results of the payment proposal on a report, but without creating any payments.","source":"**Print report only** – Set this option to **Yes** to see the results of the payment proposal on a report, but without creating any payments."},{"pos":[6394,6654],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Include vendor invoices from other legal entities<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – If your organization has a centralized process for payment, and the payment proposal should include invoices from other legal entities that are included in the search criteria, set this option to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Yes<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","source":"**Include vendor invoices from other legal entities** – If your organization has a centralized process for payment, and the payment proposal should include invoices from other legal entities that are included in the search criteria, set this option to **Yes**."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Propose separate vendor payment per legal entity<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – If this option is set to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Yes<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, a separate payment is created for each legal entity per vendor.","pos":[6659,6811],"source":"**Propose separate vendor payment per legal entity** – If this option is set to **Yes**, a separate payment is created for each legal entity per vendor."},{"content":"The vendor on the payment is the vendor from the invoice from each legal entity.","pos":[6812,6892]},{"content":"If this option is set to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>No<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, and the same vendor has invoices in multiple legal entities, one payment is created for the total amount of the selected invoices.","pos":[6893,7056],"source":" If this option is set to **No**, and the same vendor has invoices in multiple legal entities, one payment is created for the total amount of the selected invoices."},{"content":"The vendor on the payment is the vendor in the current legal entity.","pos":[7057,7125]},{"content":"If the vendor account doesn’t exist in the current legal entity, the vendor account of the first invoice that must be paid is used.","pos":[7126,7257]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Payment currency<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – This field specifies the currency that all payments are created in.","pos":[7262,7352],"source":"**Payment currency** – This field specifies the currency that all payments are created in."},{"content":"If a currency isn’t defined, each invoice is paid in the currency of the invoice.","pos":[7353,7434]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Payment weekday<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Enter the day of the week when the payment should be made.","pos":[7439,7519],"source":"**Payment weekday** – Enter the day of the week when the payment should be made."},{"content":"This field is used only if the method of payment is set up to total invoices for payment on a specific day of the week.","pos":[7520,7639]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Offset account type<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Offset account<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> – Set these fields to define a specific account type (such as <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Ledger<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> or <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Bank<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>) and offset account (such as a specific bank account).","pos":[7644,7830],"source":"**Offset account type** and **Offset account** – Set these fields to define a specific account type (such as **Ledger** or **Bank**) and offset account (such as a specific bank account)."},{"content":"The method of payment for the invoice defines the default offset account type and offset account, but you can use these fields to override the default values.","pos":[7831,7989]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Additional filters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – On the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Records to include<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> FastTab, you can define additional ranges of criteria.","pos":[7994,8103],"source":"**Additional filters** – On the **Records to include** FastTab, you can define additional ranges of criteria."},{"content":"For example, if you want to pay only a range of vendors, you can define a filter for the vendor range.","pos":[8104,8206]},{"content":"This functionality is often used to select invoices for a specific of method of payment.","pos":[8207,8295]},{"content":"For example, if you define a filter where <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Method of payment<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph1\"> = </ph><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Check<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, only invoices that have that method of payment are selected for payment, provided that they also meet other criteria that are specified in the query.","pos":[8296,8522],"source":" For example, if you define a filter where **Method of payment** = **Check**, only invoices that have that method of payment are selected for payment, provided that they also meet other criteria that are specified in the query."},{"pos":[8527,8536],"content":"Scenarios","linkify":"Scenarios","nodes":[{"content":"Scenarios","pos":[0,9]}]},{"content":"Vendor","pos":[8539,8545]},{"content":"Invoice","pos":[8548,8555]},{"content":"Invoice date","pos":[8558,8570]},{"content":"Invoice amount","pos":[8573,8587]},{"content":"Due date","pos":[8590,8598]},{"content":"Cash discount date","pos":[8601,8619]},{"content":"Cash discount amount","pos":[8622,8642]},{"content":"3050","pos":[8755,8759]},{"content":"1001","pos":[8764,8768]},{"content":"June 15","pos":[8774,8781]},{"content":"500.00","pos":[8789,8795]},{"content":"July 15","pos":[8806,8813]},{"content":"June 29","pos":[8817,8824]},{"content":"10.00","pos":[8838,8843]},{"content":"3050","pos":[8863,8867]},{"content":"1002","pos":[8872,8876]},{"content":"June 20","pos":[8882,8889]},{"content":"600.00","pos":[8897,8903]},{"content":"July 20","pos":[8914,8921]},{"content":"July 4","pos":[8925,8931]},{"content":"12.00","pos":[8946,8951]},{"content":"3075","pos":[8971,8975]},{"content":"1003","pos":[8980,8984]},{"content":"June 15","pos":[8990,8997]},{"content":"250.00","pos":[9005,9011]},{"content":"June 29","pos":[9022,9029]},{"content":"0.00","pos":[9054,9058]},{"content":"3100","pos":[9079,9083]},{"content":"1004","pos":[9088,9092]},{"content":"June 17","pos":[9098,9105]},{"content":"100.00","pos":[9113,9119]},{"content":"July 17","pos":[9130,9137]},{"content":"July 1","pos":[9141,9147]},{"content":"1.00","pos":[9162,9166]},{"content":"On July 1, April pays vendors.","pos":[9186,9216]},{"content":"She uses a payment proposal to help her complete this task more efficiently.","pos":[9217,9293]},{"pos":[9299,9325],"content":"Option 1: By cash discount","linkify":"Option 1: By cash discount","nodes":[{"content":"Option 1: By cash discount","pos":[0,26]}]},{"content":"April selects <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cash discount<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> as the proposal type.","pos":[9327,9380],"source":"April selects **Cash discount** as the proposal type."},{"content":"She enters a date range of June 26 to July 10.","pos":[9381,9427]},{"content":"The following invoices are included in the proposal:","pos":[9428,9480]},{"content":"1002, because the discount date of July 4 is in the range of payment dates.","pos":[9486,9561]},{"content":"1004, because the discount date of July 1 is in the range of payment dates.","pos":[9566,9641]},{"content":"The following invoices aren't included in the proposal:","pos":[9643,9698]},{"content":"1001, because the discount date of June 29 has already expired, so this invoice is no longer eligible for the cash discount.","pos":[9704,9828]},{"content":"1003, because this invoice doesn't have a discount date.","pos":[9833,9889]},{"pos":[9895,9916],"content":"Option 2: By due date","linkify":"Option 2: By due date","nodes":[{"content":"Option 2: By due date","pos":[0,21]}]},{"content":"April selects <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Per due date<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> as the proposal type.","pos":[9918,9970],"source":"April selects **Per due date** as the proposal type."},{"content":"She enters a date range of June 26 to July 10.","pos":[9971,10017]},{"content":"The following invoices are included in the proposal:","pos":[10018,10070]},{"content":"1003, because the due date of June 29 is in the range of payment dates.","pos":[10076,10147]},{"content":"The following invoices aren't included in the proposal:","pos":[10149,10204]},{"content":"1001, because the due date of July 15 is outside the range of payment dates.","pos":[10210,10286]},{"content":"1002, because the due date of July 20 is outside the range of payment dates.","pos":[10291,10367]},{"content":"1004, because the due date of July 17 is outside the range of payment dates.","pos":[10372,10448]},{"pos":[10454,10493],"content":"Option 3: By due date and cash discount","linkify":"Option 3: By due date and cash discount","nodes":[{"content":"Option 3: By due date and cash discount","pos":[0,39]}]},{"content":"April selects <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Due date and cash discount<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> as the proposal type.","pos":[10495,10561],"source":"April selects **Due date and cash discount** as the proposal type."},{"content":"She enters a date range of June 26 to July 10.","pos":[10562,10608]},{"content":"The following invoices are included in the proposal:","pos":[10609,10661]},{"content":"1003, because the due date of June 29 is in the range of payment dates.","pos":[10667,10738]},{"content":"1002, because the discount date of July 4 is in the range of payment dates.","pos":[10743,10818]},{"content":"1004, because the discount date of July 1 is in the range of payment dates.","pos":[10823,10898]},{"content":"The following invoices aren't included in the proposal:","pos":[10900,10955]},{"content":"1001, because the discount date of June 29 has already expired, so this invoice is no longer eligible for the cash discount, and the due date of July 15 is also outside the date range.","pos":[10961,11145]},{"pos":[11150,11181],"content":"Country specific considerations","linkify":"Country specific considerations","nodes":[{"content":"Country specific considerations","pos":[0,31]}]},{"pos":[11186,11192],"content":"Norway","linkify":"Norway","nodes":[{"content":"Norway","pos":[0,6]}]},{"pos":[11199,11216],"content":"Dimension control","linkify":"Dimension control","nodes":[{"content":"Dimension control","pos":[0,17]}]},{"content":"Dimension control allows you to control grouping of generated lines by payment proposal and set default dimensions based on financial dimensions used for the applied invoices.","pos":[11218,11393]},{"content":"Under Norwegian country context for each method of payment there is financial dimension tab where you can activate dimension control as well as enable grouping for each dimension.","pos":[11394,11573]},{"content":"Possible options are:","pos":[11574,11595]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Dimension control<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field is disabled.","pos":[11601,11641],"source":"**Dimension control** field is disabled."},{"content":"The payment proposal behaves as for any other country.","pos":[11642,11696]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Dimension control<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field is activated without further defining the dimensions.","pos":[11701,11782],"source":"**Dimension control** field is activated without further defining the dimensions."},{"content":"The payment proposal will be created without taking dimensions into consideration.","pos":[11783,11865]},{"content":"The created transaction inherits no dimensions from the applied entry.","pos":[11866,11936]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Dimension control<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field is activated and the further dimensions are enabled.","pos":[11941,12021],"source":"**Dimension control** field is activated and the further dimensions are enabled."},{"content":"Now you define how the dimensions will be copied to the journal.","pos":[12022,12086]},{"content":"For example: • Select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>BusinessUnit<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> check box to create a payment proposal per business unit for the method of payment, • Select the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>CostCenter<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> check box to create a payment proposal per cost center for the method of payment","pos":[12087,12322],"source":" For example: • Select the **BusinessUnit** check box to create a payment proposal per business unit for the method of payment, • Select the **CostCenter** check box to create a payment proposal per cost center for the method of payment"},{"pos":[12324,12453],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> If you select more than one dimension in the third option, a payment proposal is created for the dimension combination.","source":"**Note:** If you select more than one dimension in the third option, a payment proposal is created for the dimension combination."},{"pos":[12460,12482],"content":"Bank account selection","linkify":"Bank account selection","nodes":[{"content":"Bank account selection","pos":[0,22]}]},{"content":"You can define a standard debiting payment account per method of payment regardless country context.","pos":[12484,12584]},{"content":"This will be set in payment lines generated by a proposal.","pos":[12585,12643]},{"content":"With the bank account feature, you can define multiple debiting bank accounts managed by dimension and currency or a combination of these to use different debiting bank accounts, depending on each combination.","pos":[12644,12853]},{"content":"You can set up these combinations in <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Methods of payments<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page by using the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Bank accounts<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> button available for each method of payment with <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Posting account type<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph1\"> = </ph><bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Bank<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>.","pos":[12854,13036],"source":" You can set up these combinations in **Methods of payments** page by using the **Bank accounts** button available for each method of payment with **Posting account type** = **Bank**."}]}