{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,78],"content":"Purchase orders for a project | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Purchase orders for a project | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,46]}]},{"pos":[92,330],"content":"This article describes the various methods that you can use to create purchase orders for a project. The method that you use depends on the purpose of the purchase order, and when the purchased items are consumed and charged to a project.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"This article describes the various methods that you can use to create purchase orders for a project. The method that you use depends on the purpose of the purchase order, and when the purchased items are consumed and charged to a project.","pos":[0,238],"nodes":[{"content":"This article describes the various methods that you can use to create purchase orders for a project.","pos":[0,100]},{"content":"The method that you use depends on the purpose of the purchase order, and when the purchased items are consumed and charged to a project.","pos":[101,238]}]}]},{"pos":[748,777],"content":"Purchase orders for a project","linkify":"Purchase orders for a project","nodes":[{"content":"Purchase orders for a project","pos":[0,29]}]},{"content":"In Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations, you can use multiple methods to create purchase orders for a project.","pos":[779,890]},{"content":"The method that you use depends on the purpose of the purchase order, when the purchased items are consumed, and when the purchased items are charged to a project.","pos":[891,1054]},{"pos":[1060,1097],"content":"Methods for creating a purchase order","linkify":"Methods for creating a purchase order","nodes":[{"content":"Methods for creating a purchase order","pos":[0,37]}]},{"content":"You can use one of the following methods to create a purchase order in Project management and accounting.","pos":[1099,1204]},{"content":"The purpose of the purchase order determines when the purchase order is consumed and, therefore, when items are charged to a project.","pos":[1205,1338]},{"content":"Method","pos":[1463,1469]},{"content":"Purpose","pos":[1479,1486]},{"content":"Consumption of items","pos":[1496,1516]},{"content":"Create a purchase order directly from a project.","pos":[1566,1614]},{"content":"Use this method to purchase items from an external vendor for consumption on a project.","pos":[1624,1711]},{"content":"You can create the purchase order in two ways:","pos":[1712,1758],"source":" You can create the purchase order in two ways:\n"},{"content":"From the project itself.","pos":[1768,1792]},{"content":"In this case, the project is already defined for the purchase order.","pos":[1793,1861]},{"content":"By navigating to the project purchase order.","pos":[1871,1915]},{"content":"(Click <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Project management and accounting<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Common<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Item tasks<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> <ph id=\"ph3\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p4\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Project purchase orders<ept id=\"p4\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.) You must select both the vendor and the project to create the purchase order for.","pos":[1916,2165],"source":" (Click <strong>Project management and accounting</strong> &gt; <strong>Common</strong> &gt; <strong>Item tasks</strong> &gt; <strong>Project purchase orders</strong>.) You must select both the vendor and the project to create the purchase order for."},{"content":"Items are consumed when the vendor invoice is updated.","pos":[2186,2240]},{"content":"Create a purchase order from a sales order.","pos":[2274,2317]},{"content":"Use this method to purchase items when you create a sales order from a project.","pos":[2327,2406]},{"content":"Items are consumed when the sales order is invoiced to the customer.","pos":[2416,2484]},{"content":"Create a purchase order from an item requirement.","pos":[2517,2566]},{"content":"Use this method to purchase items when you create an item requirement from a project.","pos":[2576,2661]},{"content":"Items are consumed when the item requirement packing slip is updated.","pos":[2671,2740]},{"pos":[2771,2900],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> When you update the vendor invoice or packing slip, you're prompted to update the packing slip on the item requirement.","source":"**Note:** When you update the vendor invoice or packing slip, you're prompted to update the packing slip on the item requirement."}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Purchase orders for a project | Microsoft Docs\ndescription: This article describes the various methods that you can use to create purchase orders for a project. The method that you use depends on the purpose of the purchase order, and when the purchased items are consumed and charged to a project.\nauthor: annbe\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 2016-04-29 22:02:01\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# keywords: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: 51\nms.suite: Released- Dynamics AX 7.0.0\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 83972\nms.assetid: 2a9b6f5d-ddbf-4f4d-b78e-6385f7add53e\n# ms.region: \n# ms.industry: \nms.author: annbe\n\n---\n\n# Purchase orders for a project\n\nIn Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations, you can use multiple methods to create purchase orders for a project. The method that you use depends on the purpose of the purchase order, when the purchased items are consumed, and when the purchased items are charged to a project.\n\n### Methods for creating a purchase order\n\nYou can use one of the following methods to create a purchase order in Project management and accounting. The purpose of the purchase order determines when the purchase order is consumed and, therefore, when items are charged to a project.\n\n<table>\n<colgroup>\n<col width=\"33%\" />\n<col width=\"33%\" />\n<col width=\"33%\" />\n</colgroup>\n<thead>\n<tr class=\"header\">\n<th>Method</th>\n<th>Purpose</th>\n<th>Consumption of items</th>\n</tr>\n</thead>\n<tbody>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Create a purchase order directly from a project.</td>\n<td>Use this method to purchase items from an external vendor for consumption on a project. You can create the purchase order in two ways:\n<ul>\n<li>From the project itself. In this case, the project is already defined for the purchase order.</li>\n<li>By navigating to the project purchase order. (Click <strong>Project management and accounting</strong> &gt; <strong>Common</strong> &gt; <strong>Item tasks</strong> &gt; <strong>Project purchase orders</strong>.) You must select both the vendor and the project to create the purchase order for.</li>\n</ul></td>\n<td>Items are consumed when the vendor invoice is updated.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Create a purchase order from a sales order.</td>\n<td>Use this method to purchase items when you create a sales order from a project.</td>\n<td>Items are consumed when the sales order is invoiced to the customer.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Create a purchase order from an item requirement.</td>\n<td>Use this method to purchase items when you create an item requirement from a project.</td>\n<td>Items are consumed when the item requirement packing slip is updated.</td>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n</table>\n\n**Note:** When you update the vendor invoice or packing slip, you're prompted to update the packing slip on the item requirement.\n\n"}