{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,93],"content":"Pay a vendor by endorsing a bill of exchange | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Pay a vendor by endorsing a bill of exchange | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,61]}]},{"pos":[107,306],"content":"In Japan, bills of exchange (BOEs) are often endorsed to a vendor and used as a method of payment. In Microsoft Dynamics AX, a list page for BOEs provides centralized management of the BOE lifecycle.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"In Japan, bills of exchange (BOEs) are often endorsed to a vendor and used as a method of payment. In Microsoft Dynamics AX, a list page for BOEs provides centralized management of the BOE lifecycle.","pos":[0,199],"nodes":[{"content":"In Japan, bills of exchange (BOEs) are often endorsed to a vendor and used as a method of payment.","pos":[0,98]},{"content":"In Microsoft Dynamics AX, a list page for BOEs provides centralized management of the BOE lifecycle.","pos":[99,199]}]}]},{"pos":[475,543],"content":"CustBillOfExchangeEndorseListPage, CustBillOfExchangeEndorseToVendor","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"CustBillOfExchangeEndorseListPage, CustBillOfExchangeEndorseToVendor","pos":[0,68]}]},{"pos":[801,845],"content":"Pay a vendor by endorsing a bill of exchange","linkify":"Pay a vendor by endorsing a bill of exchange","nodes":[{"content":"Pay a vendor by endorsing a bill of exchange","pos":[0,44]}]},{"content":"To start managing a BOE in Dynamics AX, open the Draw bill of exchange journal.","pos":[847,926]},{"content":"When this type of journal is posted, if the status of the BOE is <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Drawn<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, users can manage the BOE lifecycle in following stages.","pos":[927,1058],"source":" When this type of journal is posted, if the status of the BOE is **Drawn**, users can manage the BOE lifecycle in following stages."},{"pos":[1063,1088],"content":"Endorse a BOE to a vendor","linkify":"Endorse a BOE to a vendor","nodes":[{"content":"Endorse a BOE to a vendor","pos":[0,25]}]},{"content":"The list page shows customer BOEs that have been drawn.","pos":[1089,1144]},{"content":"You can select one or more BOEs to endorse to a vendor.","pos":[1145,1200]},{"content":"However, if multiple BOEs are selected, they all must have a status of <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Drawn<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> before you can endorse them.","pos":[1201,1310],"source":" However, if multiple BOEs are selected, they all must have a status of **Drawn** before you can endorse them."},{"content":"An accounting voucher will be generated to record the balance change in the endorsed BOE account and the accounts payable account.","pos":[1311,1441]},{"pos":[1446,1472],"content":"Settle vendor transactions","linkify":"Settle vendor transactions","nodes":[{"content":"Settle vendor transactions","pos":[0,26]}]},{"content":"When a BOE is endorsed, its status changes to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Endorsed<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[1473,1532],"source":"When a BOE is endorsed, its status changes to **Endorsed**."},{"content":"An Accounts payable user can then settle the vendor transaction against a vendor invoice.","pos":[1533,1622]},{"content":"The status of the BOE itself doesn't change when the vendor transaction is settled.","pos":[1623,1706]},{"pos":[1711,1731],"content":"Settle endorsed BOEs","linkify":"Settle endorsed BOEs","nodes":[{"content":"Settle endorsed BOEs","pos":[0,20]}]},{"content":"The lifecycle of a BOE ends when the BOE is paid or expires.","pos":[1732,1792]},{"content":"For endorsed BOEs, you can select the BOE and settle the endorsement.","pos":[1793,1862]},{"content":"An accounting voucher will be generated to record the balance change in the endorsed BOE account and the drawn BOE account.","pos":[1863,1986]},{"pos":[1991,2010],"content":"Reserve endorsement","linkify":"Reserve endorsement","nodes":[{"content":"Reserve endorsement","pos":[0,19]}]},{"pos":[2011,2086],"content":"If the status of a BOE is <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Endorsed<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, a user can reserve its endorsement.","source":"If the status of a BOE is **Endorsed**, a user can reserve its endorsement."}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Pay a vendor by endorsing a bill of exchange | Microsoft Docs\ndescription: In Japan, bills of exchange (BOEs) are often endorsed to a vendor and used as a method of payment. In Microsoft Dynamics AX, a list page for BOEs provides centralized management of the BOE lifecycle.\nauthor: annbe\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 2016-01-06 20:53:35\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nkeywords: CustBillOfExchangeEndorseListPage, CustBillOfExchangeEndorseToVendor\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \n# ms.reviewer: \nms.suite: Released- Dynamics AX 7.0.0\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 28791\nms.assetid: fb256279-e97b-474f-991b-05605725ebb8\nms.region: Japan\n# ms.industry: \nms.author: ShylaThompson\n\n---\n\n# Pay a vendor by endorsing a bill of exchange\n\nTo start managing a BOE in Dynamics AX, open the Draw bill of exchange journal. When this type of journal is posted, if the status of the BOE is **Drawn**, users can manage the BOE lifecycle in following stages.\n\n## Endorse a BOE to a vendor\nThe list page shows customer BOEs that have been drawn. You can select one or more BOEs to endorse to a vendor. However, if multiple BOEs are selected, they all must have a status of **Drawn** before you can endorse them. An accounting voucher will be generated to record the balance change in the endorsed BOE account and the accounts payable account.\n\n## Settle vendor transactions\nWhen a BOE is endorsed, its status changes to **Endorsed**. An Accounts payable user can then settle the vendor transaction against a vendor invoice. The status of the BOE itself doesn't change when the vendor transaction is settled.\n\n## Settle endorsed BOEs\nThe lifecycle of a BOE ends when the BOE is paid or expires. For endorsed BOEs, you can select the BOE and settle the endorsement. An accounting voucher will be generated to record the balance change in the endorsed BOE account and the drawn BOE account.\n\n## Reserve endorsement\nIf the status of a BOE is **Endorsed**, a user can reserve its endorsement.\n\n"}