{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,85],"content":"Garnishment and tax levy setup tasks | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Garnishment and tax levy setup tasks | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,53]}]},{"pos":[99,363],"content":"This topic explains how to set up garnishments and tax levies. Garnishments and tax levies are created and managed by using the benefit framework. This framework helps guarantee that the effect that garnishments and tax levies have on payroll is handled correctly.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"This topic explains how to set up garnishments and tax levies. Garnishments and tax levies are created and managed by using the benefit framework. This framework helps guarantee that the effect that garnishments and tax levies have on payroll is handled correctly.","pos":[0,264],"nodes":[{"content":"This topic explains how to set up garnishments and tax levies.","pos":[0,62]},{"content":"Garnishments and tax levies are created and managed by using the benefit framework.","pos":[63,146]},{"content":"This framework helps guarantee that the effect that garnishments and tax levies have on payroll is handled correctly.","pos":[147,264]}]}]},{"pos":[532,591],"content":"HcmBenefit, HcmBenefitElementSetup, PayrollDisposableIncome","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"HcmBenefit, HcmBenefitElementSetup, PayrollDisposableIncome","pos":[0,59]}]},{"pos":[866,902],"content":"Garnishment and tax levy setup tasks","linkify":"Garnishment and tax levy setup tasks","nodes":[{"content":"Garnishment and tax levy setup tasks","pos":[0,36]}]},{"content":"If you have questions about garnishments that aren't answered in this topic, or in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Garnishment and tax levy enrollment tasks<ept id=\"p1\">](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/garnishment-and-tax-levy-enrollment-tasks/)</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Garnishments, tax levies, and administrative fees<ept id=\"p2\">](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/garnishments-tax-levies-and-administrative-fees/)</ept>, contact your legal advisor.","pos":[904,1280],"source":"If you have questions about garnishments that aren't answered in this topic, or in [Garnishment and tax levy enrollment tasks](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/garnishment-and-tax-levy-enrollment-tasks/) or [Garnishments, tax levies, and administrative fees](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/garnishments-tax-levies-and-administrative-fees/), contact your legal advisor."},{"content":"The following illustration shows the steps for setting up the system to process garnishments and tax levies.","pos":[1281,1389]},{"content":"The numbered steps in the illustration correspond to sections of this topic.","pos":[1390,1466]},{"content":"![Steps for setting up garnishments] Here is a summary of each step in the process:","pos":[1467,1550]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Set up disposable income definitions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – When the court imposes an order to garnish a worker's wages, the actual amount of the garnishment is limited to a percentage of the worker's disposable income.","pos":[1556,1758],"source":"**Set up disposable income definitions** – When the court imposes an order to garnish a worker's wages, the actual amount of the garnishment is limited to a percentage of the worker's disposable income."},{"content":"The federal definition of disposable income is built into the payroll calculation.","pos":[1759,1841]},{"content":"However, some states require additional reductions to disposable income.","pos":[1842,1914]},{"content":"You can use disposable income definitions to identify those reductions and help guarantee that the correct earnings and deductions are included when the worker's disposable income is calculated.","pos":[1915,2109]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Set up benefit elements for garnishments, tax levies, and administrative fees<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Because garnishments and tax levies are processed as benefits, each garnishment or tax levy consists of a benefit type, plan, and option.","pos":[2114,2335],"source":"**Set up benefit elements for garnishments, tax levies, and administrative fees** – Because garnishments and tax levies are processed as benefits, each garnishment or tax levy consists of a benefit type, plan, and option."},{"content":"Together, these elements create a single instance of a garnishment or tax levy.","pos":[2336,2415]},{"content":"Administrative fees aren't permitted in every state.","pos":[2416,2468]},{"content":"Even in states where administrative fees are permitted, they are never mandatory.","pos":[2469,2550]},{"content":"Your organization must decide whether to charge them.","pos":[2551,2604]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Create benefits for garnishments, tax levies, and administrative fees<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – You must have at least one benefit for garnishments and at least one benefit for tax levies.","pos":[2609,2777],"source":"**Create benefits for garnishments, tax levies, and administrative fees** – You must have at least one benefit for garnishments and at least one benefit for tax levies."},{"content":"If a worker has more than one garnishment of the same type, you must have more than one garnishment benefit of that type.","pos":[2778,2899]},{"content":"If your organization charges an administrative fee for handling garnishments and tax levies, you must have at least one benefit for the fee.","pos":[2900,3040]},{"content":"You can also optionally have additional benefits for other administrative fees.","pos":[3041,3120]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> In this topic, the term <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>garnishment<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept> implies both garnishments and tax levies, unless the text specifies otherwise.","pos":[3122,3248],"source":"**Note:** In this topic, the term *garnishment* implies both garnishments and tax levies, unless the text specifies otherwise."},{"content":"For more information about the concepts that are discussed in this topic, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Garnishments, tax levies, and administrative fees<ept id=\"p1\">](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/garnishments-tax-levies-and-administrative-fees/)</ept>.","pos":[3249,3465],"source":" For more information about the concepts that are discussed in this topic, see [Garnishments, tax levies, and administrative fees](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/garnishments-tax-levies-and-administrative-fees/)."},{"pos":[3470,3510],"content":"Setting up disposable income definitions","linkify":"Setting up disposable income definitions","nodes":[{"content":"Setting up disposable income definitions","pos":[0,40]}]},{"content":"When the court imposes an order to garnish a worker's wages, the actual amount of the garnishment is limited to a percentage of the worker's disposable income.","pos":[3511,3670]},{"content":"Under the federal definition, the disposable income is determined by subtracting all deductions that are required by law from a worker's gross earnings or income.","pos":[3671,3833]},{"content":"Gross earnings include wages, commissions, bonuses, paid time off (PTO) pay, and periodic pension statements.","pos":[3834,3943]},{"content":"Here are some of the deductions that are required by law:","pos":[3944,4001]},{"content":"Federal, state, and local income tax","pos":[4007,4043]},{"content":"Social Security and Medicare tax","pos":[4048,4080]},{"content":"State unemployment or disability tax","pos":[4085,4121]},{"content":"State-mandated payments for state employee retirement systems","pos":[4126,4187]},{"content":"Under the federal formula, voluntary deductions (for example, deductions for life insurance, union dues, and retirement plan contributions) aren't subtracted from earnings.","pos":[4189,4361]},{"content":"The federal formula has been built into the Payroll system.","pos":[4362,4421]},{"content":"Many states use the federal definition of disposable income.","pos":[4422,4482]},{"content":"However, some states have their own definition that exempts some additional earnings from total wages and subtracts other deductions, to further reduce what is considered disposable income.","pos":[4483,4672]},{"content":"You don't have to create a definition by using the federal formula.","pos":[4673,4740]},{"content":"(The federal formula is built into the Payroll calculations.) However, you must create additional disposable income definitions to comply with each state's formula.","pos":[4741,4905]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Important:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> State definitions are subject to change every year.","pos":[4906,4972],"source":"**Important:** State definitions are subject to change every year."},{"content":"Because it can be difficult to match your organization's earning codes and benefits to the definitions that are used by a specific state, we recommend that your legal advisors determine the earning codes and benefits that must be included in each disposable income definition.","pos":[4973,5249]},{"content":"We also recommend that your legal advisors review the definitions every year.","pos":[5250,5327]},{"content":"When you create a disposable income definition, you specify the earnings and the benefits to reduce the worker's disposable income by.","pos":[5328,5462]},{"content":"You don't have to specify the taxes.","pos":[5463,5499]},{"content":"All mandatory taxes are automatically subtracted from the total wages.","pos":[5500,5570]},{"content":"Tax levies and other garnishments aren't automatically excluded from the worker's disposable income.","pos":[5571,5671]},{"content":"To exclude them, you must specify them in the benefit section of the disposable income definition.","pos":[5672,5770]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Important:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Disposable income definitions don't have date-effective versions.","pos":[5771,5851],"source":"**Important:** Disposable income definitions don't have date-effective versions."},{"content":"When you change a definition, the change takes effect immediately.","pos":[5852,5918]},{"content":"Therefore, we recommend that you not change any existing disposable income definitions that you've used.","pos":[5919,6023]},{"content":"You create a new disposable income definition on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Disposable income definition<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[6024,6115],"source":" You create a new disposable income definition on the **Disposable income definition** page."},{"content":"Enter a name and description for the new disposable income definition.","pos":[6116,6186]},{"content":"Because disposable income definitions are typically defined for each state, consider using the two-letter state abbreviation as the first two letters of the name of every disposable income definition.","pos":[6187,6387]},{"content":"For example, when you create a disposable income definition for garnishments from Texas, enter a name that starts with <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>TX<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[6388,6514],"source":" For example, when you create a disposable income definition for garnishments from Texas, enter a name that starts with **TX**."},{"content":"Then, when you receive a new garnishment order, you can quickly see whether you already have the required disposable income definition, or whether you must create it.","pos":[6515,6681]},{"content":"When total wages are calculated, earning lines that are designated by the earning code are excluded.","pos":[6682,6782]},{"content":"Click the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Add<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button above the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Reduce total wages by the following earnings<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> grid, and select an earning code that represents the earnings that the state has identified as exempt from disposable income.","pos":[6783,6992],"source":" Click the **Add** button above the **Reduce total wages by the following earnings** grid, and select an earning code that represents the earnings that the state has identified as exempt from disposable income."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Important:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> It can be difficult to match your organization's earning codes to the definitions that a specific state uses.","pos":[6993,7117],"source":"**Important:** It can be difficult to match your organization's earning codes to the definitions that a specific state uses."},{"content":"Therefore, we recommend that your legal advisors determine the earning codes that should be included in each disposable income definition.","pos":[7118,7256]},{"content":"When total wages are calculated, deductions for selected benefits are excluded.","pos":[7257,7336]},{"content":"Click the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Add<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button above the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Reduce disposable income by deductions for the following benefits<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> grid, and select benefits that the state has identified as exempt from disposable income.","pos":[7337,7531],"source":" Click the **Add** button above the **Reduce disposable income by deductions for the following benefits** grid, and select benefits that the state has identified as exempt from disposable income."},{"content":"Remember that the system handles garnishments and tax levies as benefits.","pos":[7532,7605]},{"content":"Therefore, to exclude the amount of garnishments or tax levies from a disposable income definition, you must add the garnishment or tax levy benefits here.","pos":[7606,7761]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Important:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> We recommend that you work with your legal advisors to determine the benefits that should be included in each disposable income definition.","pos":[7762,7916],"source":"**Important:** We recommend that you work with your legal advisors to determine the benefits that should be included in each disposable income definition."},{"content":"If you delete an earning code or benefit, it's automatically removed from all disposable income definitions.","pos":[7917,8025]},{"content":"New earning codes and benefits that you create aren't automatically added.","pos":[8026,8100]},{"content":"When you maintain earning codes and benefits, you must consider the effect that any changes will have on the disposable income definitions.","pos":[8101,8240]},{"pos":[8245,8272],"content":"Setting up benefit elements","linkify":"Setting up benefit elements","nodes":[{"content":"Setting up benefit elements","pos":[0,27]}]},{"content":"Garnishments and tax levies are handled as benefits.","pos":[8273,8325]},{"content":"A benefit is a unique combination of a benefit type, plan, and option.","pos":[8326,8396]},{"content":"Use this set of tasks to create the following benefit elements that are required in order to create garnishment and tax levy benefits:","pos":[8397,8531]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Benefit types<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – You must create two benefit types: one for garnishments and one for tax levies.","pos":[8537,8636],"source":"**Benefit types** – You must create two benefit types: one for garnishments and one for tax levies."},{"content":"If your organization charges administrative fees for garnishments and tax levies, you must also create a benefit type for the administrative fees.","pos":[8637,8783]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Benefit plans<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Most organizations create a benefit plan for each type of garnishment and tax levy.","pos":[8788,8891],"source":"**Benefit plans** – Most organizations create a benefit plan for each type of garnishment and tax levy."},{"content":"You can create additional benefit plans.","pos":[8892,8932]},{"content":"For example, you might create a separate benefit plan for tax levies from each state.","pos":[8933,9018]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Benefit options<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – When you create benefit options, we recommend that you create a set of numbered options for garnishments and tax levies.","pos":[9023,9165],"source":"**Benefit options** – When you create benefit options, we recommend that you create a set of numbered options for garnishments and tax levies."},{"content":"For example, you might create options 01, 02, and 03.","pos":[9166,9219]},{"content":"By numbering the options in this manner, you can quickly see the order that the garnishments were entered in.","pos":[9220,9329]},{"content":"When you set up the benefit elements for garnishments and tax levies, remember that multiple garnishments can be in effect for a worker at the same time, but the worker can have only one enrollment in each benefit at any time.","pos":[9331,9557]},{"content":"Therefore, you must create multiple garnishment benefits.","pos":[9558,9615]},{"content":"To create multiple garnishment benefits, you can set up multiple benefit plans or multiple benefit options.","pos":[9616,9723]},{"content":"The easier method is to set up multiple benefit options, as described in the following set of tasks.","pos":[9724,9824]},{"pos":[9830,9908],"content":"Setting up benefit types for garnishments, tax levies, and administrative fees","linkify":"Setting up benefit types for garnishments, tax levies, and administrative fees","nodes":[{"content":"Setting up benefit types for garnishments, tax levies, and administrative fees","pos":[0,78]}]},{"content":"You set up benefit types for garnishments, tax levies, and administrative fees on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Benefit elements<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[9910,10022],"source":"You set up benefit types for garnishments, tax levies, and administrative fees on the **Benefit elements** page."},{"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Type<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section of the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Benefit elements<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page, enter the following information.","pos":[10023,10113],"source":" In the **Type** section of the **Benefit elements** page, enter the following information."},{"content":"Field","pos":[10218,10223]},{"content":"Description","pos":[10233,10244]},{"content":"Name Description","pos":[10294,10310]},{"content":"Enter a name and a description for the type of garnishment benefit.","pos":[10320,10387]},{"content":"For example, you might enter <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Garnishment<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> as the name and <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Court-ordered garnishment<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> as the description.","pos":[10388,10524],"source":" For example, you might enter <strong>Garnishment</strong> as the name and <strong>Court-ordered garnishment</strong> as the description."},{"content":"Concurrent enrollment","pos":[10558,10579]},{"content":"Select <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Multiple enrollments per type<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.","pos":[10589,10643],"source":"Select <strong>Multiple enrollments per type</strong>."},{"content":"This value is required, so that you can enroll a worker in more than one garnishment benefit or more than one tax levy at the same time.","pos":[10644,10780]},{"content":"Payroll category","pos":[10813,10829]},{"content":"Select one of the following payroll categories for the benefit type:","pos":[10839,10907],"source":"Select one of the following payroll categories for the benefit type:\n"},{"content":"For garnishments, select <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Garnishment<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.","pos":[10917,10971],"source":"For garnishments, select <strong>Garnishment</strong>."},{"content":"For tax levies, select <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Tax levy<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.","pos":[10981,11030],"source":"For tax levies, select <strong>Tax levy</strong>."},{"content":"Optional: For administrative fees, select <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Standard<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.","pos":[11040,11108],"source":"Optional: For administrative fees, select <strong>Standard</strong>."},{"content":"The payroll category helps guarantee that the benefit follows the processing requirements that the government defines for garnishments or tax levies.","pos":[11120,11269],"source":"\nThe payroll category helps guarantee that the benefit follows the processing requirements that the government defines for garnishments or tax levies."},{"content":"The payroll category also determines which settings are available in the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Plans<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> area of this page.","pos":[11270,11384],"source":" The payroll category also determines which settings are available in the <strong>Plans</strong> area of this page."},{"content":"Settings that don't apply to the selected payroll category aren't available.","pos":[11385,11461]},{"content":"After you've created the benefit type for garnishments, repeat this setup to create a benefit type for tax levies and a benefit type for administrative fees, if your organization uses administrative fees.","pos":[11492,11696]},{"pos":[11702,11722],"content":"Set up benefit plans","linkify":"Set up benefit plans","nodes":[{"content":"Set up benefit plans","pos":[0,20]}]},{"content":"You also set up benefit plans on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Benefit elements<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[11724,11787],"source":"You also set up benefit plans on the **Benefit elements** page."},{"content":"At the side of the page, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Plans<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to show the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Define benefit plans<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> area.","pos":[11788,11871],"source":" At the side of the page, click **Plans** to show the **Define benefit plans** area."},{"content":"You must create at least one benefit plan for garnishments and one benefit plan for tax levies.","pos":[11872,11967]},{"content":"However, we recommend that you create one benefit plan for each garnishment type and one benefit plan for each tax levy type.","pos":[11968,12093]},{"content":"If you use this approach, create the following benefit plans:","pos":[12094,12155]},{"content":"Support order","pos":[12161,12174]},{"content":"Bankruptcy","pos":[12179,12189]},{"content":"Federal administrative","pos":[12194,12216]},{"content":"Student loan","pos":[12221,12233]},{"content":"Creditor","pos":[12238,12246]},{"content":"Federal tax levy","pos":[12251,12267]},{"content":"State tax levy","pos":[12272,12286]},{"content":"Local tax levy","pos":[12291,12305]},{"content":"Optional: Administrative fees","pos":[12310,12339]},{"content":"Enter the following information.","pos":[12341,12373]},{"content":"Field","pos":[12377,12382]},{"content":"Description","pos":[12396,12407]},{"content":"Name Description","pos":[13011,13027]},{"content":"Enter a name and a description for the benefit plan.","pos":[13030,13082]},{"content":"For example, for the bankruptcy plan, you might enter <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Bankruptcy<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> as the name and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Bankruptcy order<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> as the description.","pos":[13083,13208],"source":" For example, for the bankruptcy plan, you might enter **Bankruptcy** as the name and **Bankruptcy order** as the description."},{"content":"For an administrative fee plan, you might enter <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Admin fee<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> as the name and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Garnishments<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> as the description.","pos":[13209,13323],"source":" For an administrative fee plan, you might enter **Admin fee** as the name and **Garnishments** as the description."},{"content":"Benefit type","pos":[13328,13340]},{"content":"Select the appropriate benefit type.","pos":[13347,13383]},{"content":"This benefit type is one of the benefit types that you created in the previous section, \"Setting up benefit types for garnishments, tax levies, and administrative fees.\"","pos":[13384,13553]},{"content":"Payroll impact","pos":[13645,13659]},{"pos":[13664,13690],"content":"Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Deduction only<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"Select **Deduction only**."},{"pos":[13961,14022],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tax rule<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> FastTab, enter the following information.","source":"On the **Tax rule** FastTab, enter the following information."},{"content":"Field","pos":[14026,14031]},{"content":"Description","pos":[14041,14052]},{"content":"Pretax basis","pos":[14098,14110]},{"pos":[14113,14129],"content":"Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>None<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"Select **None**."},{"pos":[14133,14201],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Payroll details<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> FastTab, enter the following information.","source":"On the **Payroll details** FastTab, enter the following information."},{"content":"Field","pos":[14306,14311]},{"content":"Description","pos":[14321,14332]},{"content":"Lock pay statement","pos":[14382,14400]},{"content":"Select this option to prevent changes to pay statement lines that include the garnishment or tax levy.","pos":[14410,14512]},{"content":"When this option is selected, you can add lines that include the garnishment or tax levy to the pay statement, or delete them from the pay statement.","pos":[14513,14662]},{"content":"However, you can't change the garnishment or tax levy lines that are on the pay statement.","pos":[14663,14753]},{"content":"If you don't select this option, you can change garnishment and tax levy lines directly on the pay statement.","pos":[14754,14863]},{"content":"Deduction method","pos":[14897,14913]},{"content":"By default, this field is set to <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Partial<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.","pos":[14923,14981],"source":"By default, this field is set to <strong>Partial</strong>."},{"content":"When the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Partial<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> deduction method is used, part of the garnishment amount is automatically deducted from a worker's pay if the whole amount can't be deducted legally.","pos":[14982,15165],"source":" When the <strong>Partial</strong> deduction method is used, part of the garnishment amount is automatically deducted from a worker's pay if the whole amount can't be deducted legally."},{"content":"Payroll types","pos":[15198,15211]},{"content":"Make sure that at least one of the following payment types is selected:","pos":[15221,15292],"source":"Make sure that at least one of the following payment types is selected:\n"},{"content":"Primary","pos":[15302,15309]},{"content":"Additional","pos":[15319,15329]},{"content":"Gross up","pos":[15339,15347]},{"content":"Deductions for the garnishment or tax levy are included in payroll runs of the selected type.","pos":[15359,15452],"source":"\nDeductions for the garnishment or tax levy are included in payroll runs of the selected type."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Important:<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> Many states have laws that specify how garnishments for child support are handled when a worker receives a lump-sum payment, such as a bonus, severance pay, or a vacation payout.","pos":[15453,15659],"source":"<strong>Important:</strong> Many states have laws that specify how garnishments for child support are handled when a worker receives a lump-sum payment, such as a bonus, severance pay, or a vacation payout."},{"content":"The laws vary, but they typically include a provision that the state must be notified before a lump-sum payment is made.","pos":[15660,15780]},{"content":"The state then gives the employer specific instructions about whether to calculate the garnishment and how to calculate it.","pos":[15781,15904]},{"content":"In some cases, the whole lump-sum payment is subject to garnishment.","pos":[15905,15973]},{"content":"Deduction priority","pos":[16007,16025]},{"content":"This field determines the order that the garnishment or tax levy is deducted from pay in, relative to other deductions.","pos":[16035,16154]},{"content":"The default value is <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>100<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.","pos":[16155,16197],"source":" The default value is <strong>100</strong>."},{"content":"Don't change the default value on this page.","pos":[16198,16242]},{"content":"Instead, to adjust the value, you must use the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Maintain benefits<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> page for each worker when the worker is enrolled in the garnishment or tax levy.","pos":[16243,16405],"source":" Instead, to adjust the value, you must use the <strong>Maintain benefits</strong> page for each worker when the worker is enrolled in the garnishment or tax levy."},{"content":"Limit period Limit amount","pos":[16438,16463]},{"content":"The limit period and limit amount differ for each worker, and for each garnishment or tax levy.","pos":[16473,16568]},{"content":"These values are set for each worker when the worker is enrolled.","pos":[16569,16634]},{"content":"Therefore, on this page, leave the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Limit period<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field blank, and leave the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Limit amount<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field set to <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>0.00<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.","pos":[16635,16792],"source":" Therefore, on this page, leave the <strong>Limit period</strong> field blank, and leave the <strong>Limit amount</strong> field set to <strong>0.00</strong>."},{"pos":[16823,16971],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Accounting<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> FastTab, set up accounting information for each legal entity that has workers who are enrolled in the garnishment or tax levy.","source":"On the **Accounting** FastTab, set up accounting information for each legal entity that has workers who are enrolled in the garnishment or tax levy."},{"content":"Field","pos":[16975,16980]},{"content":"Description","pos":[16990,17001]},{"content":"Category","pos":[17197,17205]},{"content":"Leave this field blank.","pos":[17212,17235]},{"content":"Vendor","pos":[17308,17314]},{"content":"Leave this field blank.","pos":[17323,17346]},{"content":"Main account","pos":[17419,17431]},{"content":"Select the general ledger account to apply the payroll deductions to for this benefit plan.","pos":[17434,17525]},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Accounting<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> FastTab, you can also optionally enter the default financial dimension values for the benefit plan.","pos":[17529,17650],"source":"On the **Accounting** FastTab, you can also optionally enter the default financial dimension values for the benefit plan."},{"content":"If there is more than one legal entity in your organization, repeat the setup on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Accounting<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> FastTab for each legal entity.","pos":[17651,17781],"source":" If there is more than one legal entity in your organization, repeat the setup on the **Accounting** FastTab for each legal entity."},{"pos":[17787,17813],"content":"Setting up benefit options","linkify":"Setting up benefit options","nodes":[{"content":"Setting up benefit options","pos":[0,26]}]},{"content":"You also set up benefit options on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Benefit elements<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[17815,17880],"source":"You also set up benefit options on the **Benefit elements** page."},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Options<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to show the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Define benefit options<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> area.","pos":[17881,17943],"source":" Click **Options** to show the **Define benefit options** area."},{"content":"To create a new benefit option, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>New<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, and enter the following information.","pos":[17944,18027],"source":" To create a new benefit option, click **New**, and enter the following information."},{"content":"Field","pos":[18031,18036]},{"content":"Description","pos":[18089,18100]},{"content":"Option Description","pos":[19241,19259]},{"content":"Enter a name and a description for the option.","pos":[19299,19345]},{"content":"For example, you might enter <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>01<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> as the name and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Garnishment/tax levy<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> as the description.","pos":[19346,19442],"source":" For example, you might enter **01** as the name and **Garnishment/tax levy** as the description."},{"content":"When you create benefit options for garnishments, we recommend that you create a set of numbered options for garnishments and tax levies.","pos":[19443,19580]},{"content":"For example, you might create options 01, 02, and 03.","pos":[19581,19634]},{"content":"By numbering the options in this manner, you can quickly see the order that the garnishments were entered in.","pos":[19635,19744]},{"content":"You can optionally create a separate numbered sequence for each type of garnishment or tax levy.","pos":[19745,19841]},{"content":"Allow dependent coverage Allow beneficiary designations","pos":[19846,19901]},{"content":"Dependent coverage and beneficiary designations don't apply to garnishments or tax levies.","pos":[19904,19994]},{"content":"Therefore, don't select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Allow dependent coverage<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>allow beneficiary designations<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> check boxes.","pos":[19995,20103],"source":" Therefore, don't select the **Allow dependent coverage** and **allow beneficiary designations** check boxes."},{"pos":[20453,20502],"content":"Creating benefits for garnishments and tax levies","linkify":"Creating benefits for garnishments and tax levies","nodes":[{"content":"Creating benefits for garnishments and tax levies","pos":[0,49]}]},{"content":"After you set up the benefit types, plans, and options, you must create the benefits for garnishments and tax levies.","pos":[20503,20620]},{"content":"If your organization charges administrative fees for garnishments and tax levies, you must also create a benefit for the administrative fees.","pos":[20621,20762]},{"content":"When you create a benefit, you link a benefit plan and an option, designate a benefit period, and assign eligibility rules to the benefit.","pos":[20763,20901]},{"content":"You create benefits for garnishments and tax levies on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Benefits<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[20902,20979],"source":" You create benefits for garnishments and tax levies on the **Benefits** page."},{"content":"To create a new benefit, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>New<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, and enter the following information.","pos":[20980,21056],"source":" To create a new benefit, click **New**, and enter the following information."},{"content":"Field","pos":[21060,21065]},{"content":"Description","pos":[21083,21094]},{"content":"Create a new benefit","pos":[21218,21238]},{"content":"Select a plan and an option.","pos":[21241,21269]},{"content":"Effective Expiration","pos":[21297,21317]},{"content":"Specify dates that are appropriate for the benefit.","pos":[21320,21371]},{"content":"After you've entered this information, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Create benefit<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[21375,21439],"source":"After you've entered this information, click **Create benefit**."},{"content":"Next, on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Eligibility rules<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> FastTab, change the eligibility from <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>All workers are eligible<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Bypass eligibility process<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.","pos":[21440,21575],"source":" Next, on the **Eligibility rules** FastTab, change the eligibility from **All workers are eligible** to **Bypass eligibility process**."},{"content":"The benefit eligibility process is used to determine which workers can enroll in a benefit, and when they can enroll.","pos":[21576,21693]},{"content":"Because anyone can be enrolled in a garnishment at any time, there is no reason to use the benefit eligibility process.","pos":[21694,21813]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> When eligibility is set to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Bypass eligibility process<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, eligibility overrides have no effect.","pos":[21814,21920],"source":"**Note:** When eligibility is set to **Bypass eligibility process**, eligibility overrides have no effect."},{"content":"Therefore, you can skip the fields on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Eligibility overrides<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> FastTab.","pos":[21921,21997],"source":" Therefore, you can skip the fields on the **Eligibility overrides** FastTab."},{"content":"Next, on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Payroll details<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> FastTab, enter the following payroll information.","pos":[21998,22080],"source":" Next, on the **Payroll details** FastTab, enter the following payroll information."},{"content":"The values that you enter here are used as default values when you enroll a worker in the garnishment or tax levy.","pos":[22081,22195]},{"content":"Field","pos":[22199,22204]},{"content":"Description","pos":[22243,22254]},{"content":"Frequency","pos":[22937,22946]},{"content":"Select how often payroll calculations should occur.","pos":[22981,23032]},{"content":"The frequency determines the pay periods that the selected benefit is calculated in.","pos":[23033,23117]},{"content":"Most often, garnishments and tax levies use <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>All<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[23118,23170],"source":" Most often, garnishments and tax levies use **All**."},{"content":"Basis","pos":[23306,23311]},{"content":"Leave this field set to the default value, <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Fixed amount<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[23350,23410],"source":"Leave this field set to the default value, **Fixed amount**."},{"content":"When the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Fixed amount<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> basis is used, the payroll process starts with a fixed deduction amount, regardless of the amount of earnings.","pos":[23411,23547],"source":" When the **Fixed amount** basis is used, the payroll process starts with a fixed deduction amount, regardless of the amount of earnings."},{"content":"You can change the value to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Percent of earnings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, as required, when you enroll a worker in the garnishment or tax levy.","pos":[23548,23670],"source":" You can change the value to **Percent of earnings**, as required, when you enroll a worker in the garnishment or tax levy."},{"content":"Amount or rate (Garnishment and tax levy)","pos":[23675,23716]},{"content":"For garnishment and tax levy benefits, leave this field set to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>0.0000<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[23719,23793],"source":"For garnishment and tax levy benefits, leave this field set to **0.0000**."},{"content":"The correct amount or rate is set on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Maintain benefits<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page for a specific worker when the worker is enrolled in the garnishment or tax levy.","pos":[23794,23943],"source":" The correct amount or rate is set on the **Maintain benefits** page for a specific worker when the worker is enrolled in the garnishment or tax levy."},{"content":"Amount or rate (Administrative fees)","pos":[24044,24080]},{"content":"For administrative fee benefits, enter the amount of the fee that your organization charges.","pos":[24088,24180]},{"content":"If you charge different administrative fees under different circumstances, you might want to create separate administrative fee benefits for each fee amount.","pos":[24181,24338]},{"content":"Finally, on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Earning basis<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> FastTab, enter the earning codes that can be included when the basis is <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Percent of earnings<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[24412,24542],"source":"Finally, on the **Earning basis** FastTab, enter the earning codes that can be included when the basis is **Percent of earnings**."},{"content":"To enter an earning code, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Add<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, and then select the earning code in the list.","pos":[24543,24629],"source":" To enter an earning code, click **Add**, and then select the earning code in the list."},{"content":"Typically, your legal department determines the appropriate earning codes.","pos":[24630,24704]},{"content":"Don't enter earning codes if the basis is <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Fixed amount<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, or if the benefit is for administrative fees.","pos":[24705,24810],"source":" Don't enter earning codes if the basis is **Fixed amount**, or if the benefit is for administrative fees."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Caution:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> You can't change the list of earning codes on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Maintain benefits<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page for a specific worker.","pos":[24811,24923],"source":"**Caution:** You can't change the list of earning codes on the **Maintain benefits** page for a specific worker."},{"content":"However, you can change the basis.","pos":[24924,24958]},{"content":"If you change the basis to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Percent of earnings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, but no earning codes are entered here, the calculated amount of the deduction for the garnishment or tax levy is 0 (zero).","pos":[24959,25133],"source":" If you change the basis to **Percent of earnings**, but no earning codes are entered here, the calculated amount of the deduction for the garnishment or tax levy is 0 (zero)."},{"pos":[25138,25147],"content":"Next step","linkify":"Next step","nodes":[{"content":"Next step","pos":[0,9]}]},{"content":"The next step is to enroll workers in garnishments and tax levies.","pos":[25148,25214]},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Garnishment and tax levy enrollment tasks<ept id=\"p1\">](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/garnishment-and-tax-levy-enrollment-tasks/)</ept>.","pos":[25215,25365],"source":" For more information, see [Garnishment and tax levy enrollment tasks](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/garnishment-and-tax-levy-enrollment-tasks/)."},{"pos":[25371,25379],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[25390,25513],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Garnishment and tax levy enrollment tasks<ept id=\"p1\">](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/garnishment-and-tax-levy-enrollment-tasks/)</ept>","source":"[Garnishment and tax levy enrollment tasks](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/garnishment-and-tax-levy-enrollment-tasks/)"},{"pos":[25515,25594],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Benefit setup tasks<ept id=\"p1\">](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/benefit-setup-tasks/)</ept>","source":"[Benefit setup tasks](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/benefit-setup-tasks/)"},{"pos":[25596,25703],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Worker and position payroll tasks<ept id=\"p1\">](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/worker-and-position-payroll-tasks/)</ept>","source":"[Worker and position payroll tasks](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/worker-and-position-payroll-tasks/)"}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Garnishment and tax levy setup tasks | Microsoft Docs\ndescription: This topic explains how to set up garnishments and tax levies. Garnishments and tax levies are created and managed by using the benefit framework. This framework helps guarantee that the effect that garnishments and tax levies have on payroll is handled correctly.\nauthor: annbe\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 2016-10-31 15:41:54\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nkeywords: HcmBenefit, HcmBenefitElementSetup, PayrollDisposableIncome\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \n# ms.reviewer: \nms.suite: Released- Dynamics 365 for Operations version 1611\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 221114\nms.assetid: aee907d0-bce3-4eac-b939-82686dfd4fd4\nms.region: USA\n# ms.industry: \nms.author: rschloma\n\n---\n\n# Garnishment and tax levy setup tasks\n\nIf you have questions about garnishments that aren't answered in this topic, or in [Garnishment and tax levy enrollment tasks](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/garnishment-and-tax-levy-enrollment-tasks/) or [Garnishments, tax levies, and administrative fees](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/garnishments-tax-levies-and-administrative-fees/), contact your legal advisor. The following illustration shows the steps for setting up the system to process garnishments and tax levies. The numbered steps in the illustration correspond to sections of this topic. ![Steps for setting up garnishments] Here is a summary of each step in the process:\n\n1.  **Set up disposable income definitions** – When the court imposes an order to garnish a worker's wages, the actual amount of the garnishment is limited to a percentage of the worker's disposable income. The federal definition of disposable income is built into the payroll calculation. However, some states require additional reductions to disposable income. You can use disposable income definitions to identify those reductions and help guarantee that the correct earnings and deductions are included when the worker's disposable income is calculated.\n2.  **Set up benefit elements for garnishments, tax levies, and administrative fees** – Because garnishments and tax levies are processed as benefits, each garnishment or tax levy consists of a benefit type, plan, and option. Together, these elements create a single instance of a garnishment or tax levy. Administrative fees aren't permitted in every state. Even in states where administrative fees are permitted, they are never mandatory. Your organization must decide whether to charge them.\n3.  **Create benefits for garnishments, tax levies, and administrative fees** – You must have at least one benefit for garnishments and at least one benefit for tax levies. If a worker has more than one garnishment of the same type, you must have more than one garnishment benefit of that type. If your organization charges an administrative fee for handling garnishments and tax levies, you must have at least one benefit for the fee. You can also optionally have additional benefits for other administrative fees.\n\n**Note:** In this topic, the term *garnishment* implies both garnishments and tax levies, unless the text specifies otherwise. For more information about the concepts that are discussed in this topic, see [Garnishments, tax levies, and administrative fees](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/garnishments-tax-levies-and-administrative-fees/).\n\n## Setting up disposable income definitions\nWhen the court imposes an order to garnish a worker's wages, the actual amount of the garnishment is limited to a percentage of the worker's disposable income. Under the federal definition, the disposable income is determined by subtracting all deductions that are required by law from a worker's gross earnings or income. Gross earnings include wages, commissions, bonuses, paid time off (PTO) pay, and periodic pension statements. Here are some of the deductions that are required by law:\n\n-   Federal, state, and local income tax\n-   Social Security and Medicare tax\n-   State unemployment or disability tax\n-   State-mandated payments for state employee retirement systems\n\nUnder the federal formula, voluntary deductions (for example, deductions for life insurance, union dues, and retirement plan contributions) aren't subtracted from earnings. The federal formula has been built into the Payroll system. Many states use the federal definition of disposable income. However, some states have their own definition that exempts some additional earnings from total wages and subtracts other deductions, to further reduce what is considered disposable income. You don't have to create a definition by using the federal formula. (The federal formula is built into the Payroll calculations.) However, you must create additional disposable income definitions to comply with each state's formula. **Important:** State definitions are subject to change every year. Because it can be difficult to match your organization's earning codes and benefits to the definitions that are used by a specific state, we recommend that your legal advisors determine the earning codes and benefits that must be included in each disposable income definition. We also recommend that your legal advisors review the definitions every year. When you create a disposable income definition, you specify the earnings and the benefits to reduce the worker's disposable income by. You don't have to specify the taxes. All mandatory taxes are automatically subtracted from the total wages. Tax levies and other garnishments aren't automatically excluded from the worker's disposable income. To exclude them, you must specify them in the benefit section of the disposable income definition. **Important:** Disposable income definitions don't have date-effective versions. When you change a definition, the change takes effect immediately. Therefore, we recommend that you not change any existing disposable income definitions that you've used. You create a new disposable income definition on the **Disposable income definition** page. Enter a name and description for the new disposable income definition. Because disposable income definitions are typically defined for each state, consider using the two-letter state abbreviation as the first two letters of the name of every disposable income definition. For example, when you create a disposable income definition for garnishments from Texas, enter a name that starts with **TX**. Then, when you receive a new garnishment order, you can quickly see whether you already have the required disposable income definition, or whether you must create it. When total wages are calculated, earning lines that are designated by the earning code are excluded. Click the **Add** button above the **Reduce total wages by the following earnings** grid, and select an earning code that represents the earnings that the state has identified as exempt from disposable income. **Important:** It can be difficult to match your organization's earning codes to the definitions that a specific state uses. Therefore, we recommend that your legal advisors determine the earning codes that should be included in each disposable income definition. When total wages are calculated, deductions for selected benefits are excluded. Click the **Add** button above the **Reduce disposable income by deductions for the following benefits** grid, and select benefits that the state has identified as exempt from disposable income. Remember that the system handles garnishments and tax levies as benefits. Therefore, to exclude the amount of garnishments or tax levies from a disposable income definition, you must add the garnishment or tax levy benefits here. **Important:** We recommend that you work with your legal advisors to determine the benefits that should be included in each disposable income definition. If you delete an earning code or benefit, it's automatically removed from all disposable income definitions. New earning codes and benefits that you create aren't automatically added. When you maintain earning codes and benefits, you must consider the effect that any changes will have on the disposable income definitions.\n\n## Setting up benefit elements\nGarnishments and tax levies are handled as benefits. A benefit is a unique combination of a benefit type, plan, and option. Use this set of tasks to create the following benefit elements that are required in order to create garnishment and tax levy benefits:\n\n-   **Benefit types** – You must create two benefit types: one for garnishments and one for tax levies. If your organization charges administrative fees for garnishments and tax levies, you must also create a benefit type for the administrative fees.\n-   **Benefit plans** – Most organizations create a benefit plan for each type of garnishment and tax levy. You can create additional benefit plans. For example, you might create a separate benefit plan for tax levies from each state.\n-   **Benefit options** – When you create benefit options, we recommend that you create a set of numbered options for garnishments and tax levies. For example, you might create options 01, 02, and 03. By numbering the options in this manner, you can quickly see the order that the garnishments were entered in.\n\nWhen you set up the benefit elements for garnishments and tax levies, remember that multiple garnishments can be in effect for a worker at the same time, but the worker can have only one enrollment in each benefit at any time. Therefore, you must create multiple garnishment benefits. To create multiple garnishment benefits, you can set up multiple benefit plans or multiple benefit options. The easier method is to set up multiple benefit options, as described in the following set of tasks.\n\n### Setting up benefit types for garnishments, tax levies, and administrative fees\n\nYou set up benefit types for garnishments, tax levies, and administrative fees on the **Benefit elements** page. In the **Type** section of the **Benefit elements** page, enter the following information.\n\n<table>\n<colgroup>\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n</colgroup>\n<thead>\n<tr class=\"header\">\n<th>Field</th>\n<th>Description</th>\n</tr>\n</thead>\n<tbody>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Name Description</td>\n<td>Enter a name and a description for the type of garnishment benefit. For example, you might enter <strong>Garnishment</strong> as the name and <strong>Court-ordered garnishment</strong> as the description.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Concurrent enrollment</td>\n<td>Select <strong>Multiple enrollments per type</strong>. This value is required, so that you can enroll a worker in more than one garnishment benefit or more than one tax levy at the same time.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Payroll category</td>\n<td>Select one of the following payroll categories for the benefit type:\n<ul>\n<li>For garnishments, select <strong>Garnishment</strong>.</li>\n<li>For tax levies, select <strong>Tax levy</strong>.</li>\n<li>Optional: For administrative fees, select <strong>Standard</strong>.</li>\n</ul>\nThe payroll category helps guarantee that the benefit follows the processing requirements that the government defines for garnishments or tax levies. The payroll category also determines which settings are available in the <strong>Plans</strong> area of this page. Settings that don't apply to the selected payroll category aren't available.</td>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n</table>\n\nAfter you've created the benefit type for garnishments, repeat this setup to create a benefit type for tax levies and a benefit type for administrative fees, if your organization uses administrative fees.\n\n### Set up benefit plans\n\nYou also set up benefit plans on the **Benefit elements** page. At the side of the page, click **Plans** to show the **Define benefit plans** area. You must create at least one benefit plan for garnishments and one benefit plan for tax levies. However, we recommend that you create one benefit plan for each garnishment type and one benefit plan for each tax levy type. If you use this approach, create the following benefit plans:\n\n-   Support order\n-   Bankruptcy\n-   Federal administrative\n-   Student loan\n-   Creditor\n-   Federal tax levy\n-   State tax levy\n-   Local tax levy\n-   Optional: Administrative fees\n\nEnter the following information.\n\n| Field            | Description                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                           |\n|------------------|-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| Name Description | Enter a name and a description for the benefit plan. For example, for the bankruptcy plan, you might enter **Bankruptcy** as the name and **Bankruptcy order** as the description. For an administrative fee plan, you might enter **Admin fee** as the name and **Garnishments** as the description. |\n| Benefit type     | Select the appropriate benefit type. This benefit type is one of the benefit types that you created in the previous section, \"Setting up benefit types for garnishments, tax levies, and administrative fees.\"                                                                                        |\n| Payroll impact   | Select **Deduction only**.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            |\n\nOn the **Tax rule** FastTab, enter the following information.\n\n| Field        | Description      |\n|--------------|------------------|\n| Pretax basis | Select **None**. |\n\nOn the **Payroll details** FastTab, enter the following information.\n\n<table>\n<colgroup>\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n</colgroup>\n<thead>\n<tr class=\"header\">\n<th>Field</th>\n<th>Description</th>\n</tr>\n</thead>\n<tbody>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Lock pay statement</td>\n<td>Select this option to prevent changes to pay statement lines that include the garnishment or tax levy. When this option is selected, you can add lines that include the garnishment or tax levy to the pay statement, or delete them from the pay statement. However, you can't change the garnishment or tax levy lines that are on the pay statement. If you don't select this option, you can change garnishment and tax levy lines directly on the pay statement.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Deduction method</td>\n<td>By default, this field is set to <strong>Partial</strong>. When the <strong>Partial</strong> deduction method is used, part of the garnishment amount is automatically deducted from a worker's pay if the whole amount can't be deducted legally.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Payroll types</td>\n<td>Make sure that at least one of the following payment types is selected:\n<ul>\n<li>Primary</li>\n<li>Additional</li>\n<li>Gross up</li>\n</ul>\nDeductions for the garnishment or tax levy are included in payroll runs of the selected type. <strong>Important:</strong> Many states have laws that specify how garnishments for child support are handled when a worker receives a lump-sum payment, such as a bonus, severance pay, or a vacation payout. The laws vary, but they typically include a provision that the state must be notified before a lump-sum payment is made. The state then gives the employer specific instructions about whether to calculate the garnishment and how to calculate it. In some cases, the whole lump-sum payment is subject to garnishment.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Deduction priority</td>\n<td>This field determines the order that the garnishment or tax levy is deducted from pay in, relative to other deductions. The default value is <strong>100</strong>. Don't change the default value on this page. Instead, to adjust the value, you must use the <strong>Maintain benefits</strong> page for each worker when the worker is enrolled in the garnishment or tax levy.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Limit period Limit amount</td>\n<td>The limit period and limit amount differ for each worker, and for each garnishment or tax levy. These values are set for each worker when the worker is enrolled. Therefore, on this page, leave the <strong>Limit period</strong> field blank, and leave the <strong>Limit amount</strong> field set to <strong>0.00</strong>.</td>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n</table>\n\nOn the **Accounting** FastTab, set up accounting information for each legal entity that has workers who are enrolled in the garnishment or tax levy.\n\n| Field        | Description                                                                                 |\n|--------------|---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| Category     | Leave this field blank.                                                                     |\n| Vendor       | Leave this field blank.                                                                     |\n| Main account | Select the general ledger account to apply the payroll deductions to for this benefit plan. |\n\nOn the **Accounting** FastTab, you can also optionally enter the default financial dimension values for the benefit plan. If there is more than one legal entity in your organization, repeat the setup on the **Accounting** FastTab for each legal entity.\n\n### Setting up benefit options\n\nYou also set up benefit options on the **Benefit elements** page. Click **Options** to show the **Define benefit options** area. To create a new benefit option, click **New**, and enter the following information.\n\n| Field                                                   | Description                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    |\n|---------------------------------------------------------|----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| Option Description                                      | Enter a name and a description for the option. For example, you might enter **01** as the name and **Garnishment/tax levy** as the description. When you create benefit options for garnishments, we recommend that you create a set of numbered options for garnishments and tax levies. For example, you might create options 01, 02, and 03. By numbering the options in this manner, you can quickly see the order that the garnishments were entered in. You can optionally create a separate numbered sequence for each type of garnishment or tax levy. |\n| Allow dependent coverage Allow beneficiary designations | Dependent coverage and beneficiary designations don't apply to garnishments or tax levies. Therefore, don't select the **Allow dependent coverage** and **allow beneficiary designations** check boxes.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        |\n\n## Creating benefits for garnishments and tax levies\nAfter you set up the benefit types, plans, and options, you must create the benefits for garnishments and tax levies. If your organization charges administrative fees for garnishments and tax levies, you must also create a benefit for the administrative fees. When you create a benefit, you link a benefit plan and an option, designate a benefit period, and assign eligibility rules to the benefit. You create benefits for garnishments and tax levies on the **Benefits** page. To create a new benefit, click **New**, and enter the following information.\n\n| Field                | Description                                         |\n|----------------------|-----------------------------------------------------|\n| Create a new benefit | Select a plan and an option.                        |\n| Effective Expiration | Specify dates that are appropriate for the benefit. |\n\nAfter you've entered this information, click **Create benefit**. Next, on the **Eligibility rules** FastTab, change the eligibility from **All workers are eligible** to **Bypass eligibility process**. The benefit eligibility process is used to determine which workers can enroll in a benefit, and when they can enroll. Because anyone can be enrolled in a garnishment at any time, there is no reason to use the benefit eligibility process. **Note:** When eligibility is set to **Bypass eligibility process**, eligibility overrides have no effect. Therefore, you can skip the fields on the **Eligibility overrides** FastTab. Next, on the **Payroll details** FastTab, enter the following payroll information. The values that you enter here are used as default values when you enroll a worker in the garnishment or tax levy.\n\n| Field                                     | Description                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                      |\n|-------------------------------------------|----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| Frequency                                 | Select how often payroll calculations should occur. The frequency determines the pay periods that the selected benefit is calculated in. Most often, garnishments and tax levies use **All**.                                                                                                                                    |\n| Basis                                     | Leave this field set to the default value, **Fixed amount**. When the **Fixed amount** basis is used, the payroll process starts with a fixed deduction amount, regardless of the amount of earnings. You can change the value to **Percent of earnings**, as required, when you enroll a worker in the garnishment or tax levy. |\n| Amount or rate (Garnishment and tax levy) | For garnishment and tax levy benefits, leave this field set to **0.0000**. The correct amount or rate is set on the **Maintain benefits** page for a specific worker when the worker is enrolled in the garnishment or tax levy.                                                                                                 |\n| Amount or rate (Administrative fees)      | For administrative fee benefits, enter the amount of the fee that your organization charges. If you charge different administrative fees under different circumstances, you might want to create separate administrative fee benefits for each fee amount.                                                                       |\n\nFinally, on the **Earning basis** FastTab, enter the earning codes that can be included when the basis is **Percent of earnings**. To enter an earning code, click **Add**, and then select the earning code in the list. Typically, your legal department determines the appropriate earning codes. Don't enter earning codes if the basis is **Fixed amount**, or if the benefit is for administrative fees. **Caution:** You can't change the list of earning codes on the **Maintain benefits** page for a specific worker. However, you can change the basis. If you change the basis to **Percent of earnings**, but no earning codes are entered here, the calculated amount of the deduction for the garnishment or tax levy is 0 (zero).\n\n## Next step\nThe next step is to enroll workers in garnishments and tax levies. For more information, see [Garnishment and tax levy enrollment tasks](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/garnishment-and-tax-levy-enrollment-tasks/).    \n\nSee also\n--------\n\n[Garnishment and tax levy enrollment tasks](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/garnishment-and-tax-levy-enrollment-tasks/)\n\n[Benefit setup tasks](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/benefit-setup-tasks/)\n\n[Worker and position payroll tasks](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/worker-and-position-payroll-tasks/)\n\n"}