{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,73],"content":"Accounting distributions | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Accounting distributions | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,41]}]},{"pos":[87,331],"content":"This article provides information about accounting distributions and describes the options that are available for processing them. Accounting distributions are used to allocate monetary amounts for a source document to specific ledger accounts.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"This article provides information about accounting distributions and describes the options that are available for processing them. Accounting distributions are used to allocate monetary amounts for a source document to specific ledger accounts.","pos":[0,244],"nodes":[{"content":"This article provides information about accounting distributions and describes the options that are available for processing them.","pos":[0,130]},{"content":"Accounting distributions are used to allocate monetary amounts for a source document to specific ledger accounts.","pos":[131,244]}]}]},{"pos":[501,523],"content":"AccountingDistribution","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"AccountingDistribution","pos":[0,22]}]},{"pos":[773,797],"content":"Accounting distributions","linkify":"Accounting distributions","nodes":[{"content":"Accounting distributions","pos":[0,24]}]},{"content":"Accounting distributions are a program-wide capability that is used and extended by each source document, such as a purchase order, vendor invoice, expense report, and free text invoice.","pos":[799,985]},{"content":"By default, a default accounting distribution is generated for each source document line and monetary amount, and is conditionally enabled for modification.","pos":[986,1142]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note: <ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Some documents also support header document monetary amounts, such as charges for orders and invoices.","pos":[1143,1256],"source":"**Note: ** Some documents also support header document monetary amounts, such as charges for orders and invoices."},{"content":"The generic accounting distribution capabilities provide the following options for processing accounting distributions:","pos":[1257,1376]},{"pos":[1382,1540],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Distribute amounts<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – View and modify the accounting distributions for an individual document header or line and any child lines, such as taxes or charges.","source":"**Distribute amounts** – View and modify the accounting distributions for an individual document header or line and any child lines, such as taxes or charges."},{"content":"For the top monetary amount distributions (parent distributions), the main account and financial dimensions might be editable directly in the segmented entry control in the grid.","pos":[1549,1727]},{"content":"The extended price is a typical example of such a parent distribution.","pos":[1728,1798]},{"content":"The distributions amounts are based on the term currency for the document.","pos":[1807,1881]},{"content":"Typically, this currency is the transaction currency.","pos":[1882,1935]},{"content":"Accounting and reporting currency amounts are generated as part of subledger accounting.","pos":[1936,2024]},{"content":"The distributions display the accounting date and accounting event.","pos":[2033,2100]},{"content":"Typically, the accounting event is set to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>None<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> until the document is posted/journalized.","pos":[2101,2193],"source":" Typically, the accounting event is set to **None** until the document is posted/journalized."},{"content":"At that point, the accounting event becomes <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Original<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[2194,2251],"source":" At that point, the accounting event becomes **Original**."},{"content":"After the distributions have been posted, you can't modify the distributions.","pos":[2252,2329]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Split<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button might be enabled for parent distributions.","pos":[2338,2397],"source":"**Split** button might be enabled for parent distributions."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Split<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> generates new accounting distributions, and the split can be based on percentage, amount, or quantity.","pos":[2398,2510],"source":"**Split** generates new accounting distributions, and the split can be based on percentage, amount, or quantity."},{"pos":[2519,2665],"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Distribute equally<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button can be used in combination with <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Split<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to automatically allocate the amount equally across all distributions.","source":"The **Distribute equally** button can be used in combination with **Split** to automatically allocate the amount equally across all distributions."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Reset<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button might be enabled for parent distributions when more than one distributions exists.","pos":[2674,2773],"source":"**Reset** button might be enabled for parent distributions when more than one distributions exists."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Reset<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> reverses any manual modification to the distribution by deleting all existing distributions and re-generating the default distributions.","pos":[2774,2920],"source":"**Reset** reverses any manual modification to the distribution by deleting all existing distributions and re-generating the default distributions."},{"content":"Any child distribution, such as discount, charge, and sales tax, always follows the parent distribution.","pos":[2929,3033]},{"content":"You can view the parent/child relation at <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Reference<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Parent information<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[3034,3118],"source":" You can view the parent/child relation at **Reference** &gt; **Parent information**."},{"content":"The main account and financial dimension might be editable for children too.","pos":[3127,3203]},{"content":"The financial dimensions on the accounting distributions follow a defaulting pattern that a document can extended.","pos":[3212,3326]},{"content":"For more details, see the related articles.","pos":[3327,3370]},{"content":"Variance distributions might be generated in matching scenarios, such as matching between a vendor invoice and a purchase order.","pos":[3379,3507]},{"content":"You can view the matching relations between accounting distribution at <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Reference<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Document information<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[3508,3623],"source":" You can view the matching relations between accounting distribution at **Reference** &gt; **Document information**."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Correct<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button appears and is enabled for documents that support corrections.","pos":[3632,3713],"source":"**Correct** button appears and is enabled for documents that support corrections."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Correct<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> creates new distributions.","pos":[3714,3752],"source":"**Correct** creates new distributions."},{"content":"First, distributions are created that reverse the original distributions.","pos":[3753,3826]},{"content":"These distributions can't be modified.","pos":[3827,3865]},{"content":"Next, new correct accounting distributions are created.","pos":[3866,3921]},{"content":"These distributions can be modified if the original distributions could be modified.","pos":[3922,4006]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Project details<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button is enabled as an extension when a line is related to a project.","pos":[4015,4109],"source":"The **Project details** button is enabled as an extension when a line is related to a project."},{"content":"Project accounting distributions let you modify details such as the funding source and line property.","pos":[4110,4211]},{"content":"You can view the current document accounting status in <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Reference<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[4220,4289],"source":"You can view the current document accounting status in **Reference**."},{"content":"The status is for the entire document, and indicates whether the document is in process or completed.","pos":[4290,4391]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt> View distributions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – View the accounting distributions for the all lines and monetary amounts on the document.","pos":[4396,4511],"source":"** View distributions** – View the accounting distributions for the all lines and monetary amounts on the document."},{"content":"You can't modify the accounting distributions from this view.","pos":[4512,4573]},{"pos":[4576,4584],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[4595,4791],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Accounting distributions and subledger journal entries for free text invoices<ept id=\"p1\">](https://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/accounting-distributions-and-subledger-journal-entries-for-free-text-invoices/)</ept>","source":"[Accounting distributions and subledger journal entries for free text invoices](https://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/accounting-distributions-and-subledger-journal-entries-for-free-text-invoices/)"},{"pos":[4793,4995],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Dimension defaulting in accounting distributions (blog)<ept id=\"p1\">](http://blogs.msdn.com/b/ax_gfm_framework_team_blog/archive/2013/12/16/dimension-defaulting-in-accounting-distributions-blog-1-introduction.aspx)</ept>","source":"[Dimension defaulting in accounting distributions (blog)](http://blogs.msdn.com/b/ax_gfm_framework_team_blog/archive/2013/12/16/dimension-defaulting-in-accounting-distributions-blog-1-introduction.aspx)"}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Accounting distributions | Microsoft Docs\ndescription: This article provides information about accounting distributions and describes the options that are available for processing them. Accounting distributions are used to allocate monetary amounts for a source document to specific ledger accounts. \nauthor: annbe\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 2015-12-04 16:01:41\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nkeywords: AccountingDistribution\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \n# ms.reviewer: \nms.suite: Released- Dynamics AX 7.0.0\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 17231\nms.assetid: d15eab26-9668-4cfe-abca-b4f59403f52b\n# ms.region: \n# ms.industry: \nms.author: twheeloc\n\n---\n\n# Accounting distributions\n\nAccounting distributions are a program-wide capability that is used and extended by each source document, such as a purchase order, vendor invoice, expense report, and free text invoice. By default, a default accounting distribution is generated for each source document line and monetary amount, and is conditionally enabled for modification. **Note: ** Some documents also support header document monetary amounts, such as charges for orders and invoices. The generic accounting distribution capabilities provide the following options for processing accounting distributions:\n\n-   **Distribute amounts** – View and modify the accounting distributions for an individual document header or line and any child lines, such as taxes or charges.\n    -   For the top monetary amount distributions (parent distributions), the main account and financial dimensions might be editable directly in the segmented entry control in the grid. The extended price is a typical example of such a parent distribution.\n    -   The distributions amounts are based on the term currency for the document. Typically, this currency is the transaction currency. Accounting and reporting currency amounts are generated as part of subledger accounting.\n    -   The distributions display the accounting date and accounting event. Typically, the accounting event is set to **None** until the document is posted/journalized. At that point, the accounting event becomes **Original**. After the distributions have been posted, you can't modify the distributions.\n    -   **Split** button might be enabled for parent distributions. **Split** generates new accounting distributions, and the split can be based on percentage, amount, or quantity.\n    -   The **Distribute equally** button can be used in combination with **Split** to automatically allocate the amount equally across all distributions.\n    -   **Reset** button might be enabled for parent distributions when more than one distributions exists. **Reset** reverses any manual modification to the distribution by deleting all existing distributions and re-generating the default distributions.\n    -   Any child distribution, such as discount, charge, and sales tax, always follows the parent distribution. You can view the parent/child relation at **Reference** &gt; **Parent information**.\n    -   The main account and financial dimension might be editable for children too.\n    -   The financial dimensions on the accounting distributions follow a defaulting pattern that a document can extended. For more details, see the related articles.\n    -   Variance distributions might be generated in matching scenarios, such as matching between a vendor invoice and a purchase order. You can view the matching relations between accounting distribution at **Reference** &gt; **Document information**.\n    -   **Correct** button appears and is enabled for documents that support corrections. **Correct** creates new distributions. First, distributions are created that reverse the original distributions. These distributions can't be modified. Next, new correct accounting distributions are created. These distributions can be modified if the original distributions could be modified.\n    -   The **Project details** button is enabled as an extension when a line is related to a project. Project accounting distributions let you modify details such as the funding source and line property.\n    -   You can view the current document accounting status in **Reference**. The status is for the entire document, and indicates whether the document is in process or completed.\n-   ** View distributions** – View the accounting distributions for the all lines and monetary amounts on the document. You can't modify the accounting distributions from this view.\n\n\nSee also\n--------\n\n[Accounting distributions and subledger journal entries for free text invoices](https://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/accounting-distributions-and-subledger-journal-entries-for-free-text-invoices/)\n\n[Dimension defaulting in accounting distributions (blog)](http://blogs.msdn.com/b/ax_gfm_framework_team_blog/archive/2013/12/16/dimension-defaulting-in-accounting-distributions-blog-1-introduction.aspx)\n\n"}