{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Deploy a sandbox environment\ndescription: This topic explains why and how you should deploy a demo environment during the Analyze phase of your project for upgrading from Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 to Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations.\nauthor: tariqbell\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 05/30/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: margoc\nms.search.scope: Operations, Platform, AX Platform\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 106163\nms.assetid: \nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: tabell\nms.search.validFrom: 2017-05-31\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Platform update 8\n\n---\n\n# Deploy a sandbox environment\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\nThis topic explains why and how you should deploy a demo environment during the Analyze phase of your project for upgrading from Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 to Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations.\n\nBy deploying a demo Dynamics 365 for Operations environment, you gain hands-on experience with the program and can explore new features that you might be interested in. You also have an opportunity to validate differences in the program for your business processes, so that you can identify potential gaps or confirm that no gaps exist. At this stage in your upgrade project, your data and code won’t be available in the environment. Therefore, you will have limited ability to validate that everything conforms to your business process. However, this step is the first step in that work stream.\n\nIf you haven’t yet purchased licenses for Dynamics 365 for Operations, and you’re using a free trial, you can follow the steps in [Deploy a Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations demo environment](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-gb/dynamics365/operations/dev-itpro/deployment/deploy-demo-environment) to deploy a demo environment to a Microsoft Azure subscription that you bring yourself.\n\nIf you’ve already purchased licenses for Dynamics 365 for Operations, you received a link to configure a special type of project in Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS): an implementation project. The implementation project will let you deploy a dev/test environment and a sandbox environment. For more information about this type of environment deployment, see TODO.\n","nodes":[{"content":"Deploy a sandbox environment","nodes":[{"pos":[0,28],"content":"Deploy a sandbox environment","nodes":[{"content":"Deploy a sandbox environment","pos":[0,28]}]}],"pos":[31,60],"yaml":true},{"content":"This topic explains why and how you should deploy a demo environment during the Analyze phase of your project for upgrading from Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 to Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,197],"content":"This topic explains why and how you should deploy a demo environment during the Analyze phase of your project for upgrading from Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 to Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations.","nodes":[{"content":"This topic explains why and how you should deploy a demo environment during the Analyze phase of your project for upgrading from Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 to Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations.","pos":[0,197]}]}],"pos":[73,271],"yaml":true},{"pos":[756,784],"content":"Deploy a sandbox environment","linkify":"Deploy a sandbox environment","nodes":[{"content":"Deploy a sandbox environment","pos":[0,28]}]},{"content":"This topic explains why and how you should deploy a demo environment during the Analyze phase of your project for upgrading from Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 to Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations.","pos":[829,1026]},{"content":"By deploying a demo Dynamics 365 for Operations environment, you gain hands-on experience with the program and can explore new features that you might be interested in.","pos":[1028,1196]},{"content":"You also have an opportunity to validate differences in the program for your business processes, so that you can identify potential gaps or confirm that no gaps exist.","pos":[1197,1364]},{"content":"At this stage in your upgrade project, your data and code won’t be available in the environment.","pos":[1365,1461]},{"content":"Therefore, you will have limited ability to validate that everything conforms to your business process.","pos":[1462,1565]},{"content":"However, this step is the first step in that work stream.","pos":[1566,1623]},{"pos":[1625,2010],"content":"If you haven’t yet purchased licenses for Dynamics 365 for Operations, and you’re using a free trial, you can follow the steps in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Deploy a Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations demo environment<ept id=\"p1\">](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-gb/dynamics365/operations/dev-itpro/deployment/deploy-demo-environment)</ept> to deploy a demo environment to a Microsoft Azure subscription that you bring yourself.","source":"If you haven’t yet purchased licenses for Dynamics 365 for Operations, and you’re using a free trial, you can follow the steps in [Deploy a Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations demo environment](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-gb/dynamics365/operations/dev-itpro/deployment/deploy-demo-environment) to deploy a demo environment to a Microsoft Azure subscription that you bring yourself."},{"content":"If you’ve already purchased licenses for Dynamics 365 for Operations, you received a link to configure a special type of project in Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS): an implementation project.","pos":[2012,2215]},{"content":"The implementation project will let you deploy a dev/test environment and a sandbox environment.","pos":[2216,2312]},{"content":"For more information about this type of environment deployment, see TODO.","pos":[2313,2386]}]}