{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,96],"content":"Comply with the Americans with Disabilities Act | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Comply with the Americans with Disabilities Act | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,64]}]},{"pos":[110,321],"content":"This article describes features that can assist your organization in complying with the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA). This information applies only to legal entities doing business in the United States.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"This article describes features that can assist your organization in complying with the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA). This information applies only to legal entities doing business in the United States.","pos":[0,211],"nodes":[{"content":"This article describes features that can assist your organization in complying with the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA).","pos":[0,126]},{"content":"This information applies only to legal entities doing business in the United States.","pos":[127,211]}]}]},{"pos":[493,510],"content":"HcmADARequirement","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"HcmADARequirement","pos":[0,17]}]},{"pos":[773,820],"content":"Comply with the Americans with Disabilities Act","linkify":"Comply with the Americans with Disabilities Act","nodes":[{"content":"Comply with the Americans with Disabilities Act","pos":[0,47]}]},{"content":"This article describes features that can assist your organization in complying with the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA).","pos":[822,948]},{"content":"This information applies only to legal entities doing business in the United States.","pos":[949,1033]},{"content":"You can use the following features to manage information that can help you comply with the ADA.","pos":[1035,1130]},{"content":"Enter and track requirements for physical activity, visual acuity, and working conditions that are related to positions","pos":[1135,1254]},{"content":"Request and grant special accommodations that enable a person to perform tasks that a specific position requires","pos":[1259,1371]},{"content":"The U.S. government offers financial incentives, such as tax credits and deductions, to companies that provide special accommodations to workers who have disabilities, or hire individuals who have disabilities, and were referred by qualified governmental agencies.","pos":[1373,1637]},{"pos":[1642,1707],"content":"Recording physical requirements for position groups and positions","linkify":"Recording physical requirements for position groups and positions","nodes":[{"content":"Recording physical requirements for position groups and positions","pos":[0,65]}]},{"content":"You can enter physical requirements that are related to position groups and positions, such as:","pos":[1708,1803]},{"content":"The level of physical activity that is required.","pos":[1808,1856]},{"content":"Specific physical requirements.","pos":[1861,1892]},{"content":"Requirements for visual acuity.","pos":[1897,1928]},{"content":"This includes color, depth perception, and field of vision.","pos":[1929,1988]},{"content":"One or more work conditions that a worker will be subjected to.","pos":[1993,2056]},{"content":"You can select one or more conditions in several categories.","pos":[2057,2117]},{"content":"If you entered information about a position group, you can then copy that information to positions that are assigned to the position group.","pos":[2119,2258]},{"content":"To print a checklist that contains information about physical requirements, select the position, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ADA<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, and then click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Print<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> requirements.","pos":[2259,2409],"source":" To print a checklist that contains information about physical requirements, select the position, click **ADA**, and then click **Print** requirements."},{"content":"To reset all physical retirements to their default settings, select the position, and open the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Jobs,<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> select a job, then expand the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>ADA<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> tab.","pos":[2410,2557],"source":" To reset all physical retirements to their default settings, select the position, and open the **Jobs,** select a job, then expand the **ADA** tab."},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ADA requirements<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Reset<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> requirement.","pos":[2558,2620],"source":" On the **ADA requirements** page, click **Reset** requirement."},{"pos":[2625,2662],"content":"About work environment accommodations","linkify":"About work environment accommodations","nodes":[{"content":"About work environment accommodations","pos":[0,37]}]},{"content":"Accommodations represent changes to work environments or business operations that achieve equal employment opportunity for a person who has a disability.","pos":[2663,2816]},{"content":"You can enter requests for special work environment accommodations that are made by employees and applicants with regard to one or more specific tasks that are required by a position.","pos":[2817,3000]},{"content":"You can then evaluate whether the accommodation is reasonable or if it will impose unnecessary cost, and then either grant or deny the accommodation request.","pos":[3001,3158]},{"content":"If you hire an applicant for whom you granted an accommodation, the person keeps the accommodation information after he or she is hired.","pos":[3159,3295]},{"content":"Before you can start working with accommodations, you must first create one or more accommodation types.","pos":[3296,3400]},{"content":"This lets you sort accommodations by type to find a particular accommodation quickly.","pos":[3401,3486]},{"pos":[3495,3503],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[3514,3609],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Human resources<ept id=\"p1\">](https://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/?post_type=incsub_wiki&amp;p=197861&amp;preview=true)</ept>","source":"[Human resources](https://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/?post_type=incsub_wiki&p=197861&preview=true)"}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Comply with the Americans with Disabilities Act | Microsoft Docs\ndescription: This article describes features that can assist your organization in complying with the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA). This information applies only to legal entities doing business in the United States.\nauthor: rschloma\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 2015-09-10 15:08:58\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nkeywords: HcmADARequirement\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: rschloma\nms.suite: Released- Dynamics AX 7.0.0\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 2741\nms.assetid: 590bd9c6-ef5f-45c7-9a58-3af79a5797b2\nms.region: United States\n# ms.industry: \nms.author: kherr\n\n---\n\n# Comply with the Americans with Disabilities Act\n\nThis article describes features that can assist your organization in complying with the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA). This information applies only to legal entities doing business in the United States.\n\nYou can use the following features to manage information that can help you comply with the ADA.\n-   Enter and track requirements for physical activity, visual acuity, and working conditions that are related to positions\n-   Request and grant special accommodations that enable a person to perform tasks that a specific position requires\n\nThe U.S. government offers financial incentives, such as tax credits and deductions, to companies that provide special accommodations to workers who have disabilities, or hire individuals who have disabilities, and were referred by qualified governmental agencies.\n\n## Recording physical requirements for position groups and positions\nYou can enter physical requirements that are related to position groups and positions, such as:\n-   The level of physical activity that is required.\n-   Specific physical requirements.\n-   Requirements for visual acuity. This includes color, depth perception, and field of vision.\n-   One or more work conditions that a worker will be subjected to. You can select one or more conditions in several categories.\n\nIf you entered information about a position group, you can then copy that information to positions that are assigned to the position group. To print a checklist that contains information about physical requirements, select the position, click **ADA**, and then click **Print** requirements. To reset all physical retirements to their default settings, select the position, and open the **Jobs,** select a job, then expand the **ADA** tab. On the **ADA requirements** page, click **Reset** requirement.\n\n## About work environment accommodations\nAccommodations represent changes to work environments or business operations that achieve equal employment opportunity for a person who has a disability. You can enter requests for special work environment accommodations that are made by employees and applicants with regard to one or more specific tasks that are required by a position. You can then evaluate whether the accommodation is reasonable or if it will impose unnecessary cost, and then either grant or deny the accommodation request. If you hire an applicant for whom you granted an accommodation, the person keeps the accommodation information after he or she is hired. Before you can start working with accommodations, you must first create one or more accommodation types. This lets you sort accommodations by type to find a particular accommodation quickly.\n\n \n-\n\n\n\nSee also\n--------\n\n[Human resources](https://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/?post_type=incsub_wiki&p=197861&preview=true)\n\n"}