{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,68],"content":"Production feedback | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Production feedback | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,36]}]},{"pos":[82,291],"content":"This article provides information about production feedback, which gives workers feedback about production jobs. The article includes information about the various ways that production feedback can be updated.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"This article provides information about production feedback, which gives workers feedback about production jobs. The article includes information about the various ways that production feedback can be updated.","pos":[0,209],"nodes":[{"content":"This article provides information about production feedback, which gives workers feedback about production jobs.","pos":[0,112]},{"content":"The article includes information about the various ways that production feedback can be updated.","pos":[113,209]}]}]},{"pos":[460,543],"content":"JmgRegistration, ProdJournalTransJob, ProdJournalTransRoute, ProdParmReportFinished","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"JmgRegistration, ProdJournalTransJob, ProdJournalTransRoute, ProdParmReportFinished","pos":[0,83]}]},{"pos":[808,827],"content":"Production feedback","linkify":"Production feedback","nodes":[{"content":"Production feedback","pos":[0,19]}]},{"content":"Production feedback gives workers feedback about production jobs.","pos":[829,894]},{"content":"It records time and material consumption on production orders, operation quantities and status, and errors that cause a job or operation to fail.","pos":[895,1040]},{"content":"Production feedback can be updated in journals that are related to production orders.","pos":[1041,1126]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Production job card<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Production route card<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> journals are used to report time and quantities per job or operation.","pos":[1127,1254],"source":" The **Production job card** and **Production route card** journals are used to report time and quantities per job or operation."},{"content":"For reporting about the last job or operation, quantities on the finished product can be reported as finished.","pos":[1255,1365]},{"content":"Production feedback can also be updated on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Job card terminal<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Job card device<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> pages.","pos":[1366,1465],"source":" Production feedback can also be updated on the **Job card terminal** and **Job card device** pages."},{"content":"These pages enable production feedback to be updated on the shop floor and are part of the manufacturing execution functionality in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Production control <ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>module.","pos":[1466,1632],"source":" These pages enable production feedback to be updated on the shop floor and are part of the manufacturing execution functionality in the **Production control **module."},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Job card terminal<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page has a configurable user interface that shows a list of the released jobs in a prioritized order for a selected work area.","pos":[1633,1785],"source":" The **Job card terminal** page has a configurable user interface that shows a list of the released jobs in a prioritized order for a selected work area."},{"content":"It also offers advanced options such as job bundling and team work.","pos":[1786,1853]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Job card device<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page has a touch-optimized user interface.","pos":[1854,1920],"source":" The **Job card device** page has a touch-optimized user interface."},{"content":"Production feedback on both pages is updated from the production journals.","pos":[1921,1995]}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Production feedback | Microsoft Docs\ndescription: This article provides information about production feedback, which gives workers feedback about production jobs. The article includes information about the various ways that production feedback can be updated.\nauthor: annbe\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 2015-12-07 09:19:15\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nkeywords: JmgRegistration, ProdJournalTransJob, ProdJournalTransRoute, ProdParmReportFinished\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \n# ms.reviewer: \nms.suite: Released- Dynamics AX 7.0.0\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 19351\nms.assetid: c201341d-f240-4317-9810-a292210edb29\n# ms.region: \nms.industry: Manufacturing\nms.author: YuyuScheller\n\n---\n\n# Production feedback\n\nProduction feedback gives workers feedback about production jobs. It records time and material consumption on production orders, operation quantities and status, and errors that cause a job or operation to fail. Production feedback can be updated in journals that are related to production orders. The **Production job card** and **Production route card** journals are used to report time and quantities per job or operation. For reporting about the last job or operation, quantities on the finished product can be reported as finished. Production feedback can also be updated on the **Job card terminal** and **Job card device** pages. These pages enable production feedback to be updated on the shop floor and are part of the manufacturing execution functionality in the **Production control **module. The **Job card terminal** page has a configurable user interface that shows a list of the released jobs in a prioritized order for a selected work area. It also offers advanced options such as job bundling and team work. The **Job card device** page has a touch-optimized user interface. Production feedback on both pages is updated from the production journals.\n\n"}