{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,124],"content":"Lifecycle Services (LCS) for Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations partners | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Lifecycle Services (LCS) for Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations partners | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,92]}]},{"pos":[138,238],"content":"This article explains how partners can get started with Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS).","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"This article explains how partners can get started with Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS).","pos":[0,100]}]},{"pos":[655,730],"content":"Lifecycle Services (LCS) for Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations partners","linkify":"Lifecycle Services (LCS) for Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations partners","nodes":[{"content":"Lifecycle Services (LCS) for Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations partners","pos":[0,75]}]},{"pos":[732,1013],"content":"As a Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations partner, you can access the current version  by following the steps in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Sign up for a Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations subscription<ept id=\"p1\">](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/sign-up-for-a-microsoft-dynamics-rainier-preview-subscription/)</ept>.","source":"As a Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations partner, you can access the current version  by following the steps in [Sign up for a Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations subscription](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/sign-up-for-a-microsoft-dynamics-rainier-preview-subscription/)."},{"pos":[1019,1047],"content":"Projects for partners in LCS","linkify":"Projects for partners in LCS","nodes":[{"content":"Projects for partners in LCS","pos":[0,28]}]},{"content":"After you sign up for the current version of Dynamics 365 for Operations as a partner, you can create two types of projects:","pos":[1049,1173]},{"content":"Prospective presales","pos":[1179,1199]},{"content":"Migrate, create solutions, and learn Dynamics 365 for Operations","pos":[1204,1268]},{"pos":[1275,1303],"content":"Prospective presales project","linkify":"Prospective presales project","nodes":[{"content":"Prospective presales project","pos":[0,28]}]},{"content":"Work with new prospects to help them understand the business processes that are available in Dynamics 365 for Operations, and to help them evaluate their subscription needs.","pos":[1305,1478]},{"content":"Note that only partners can provision a new Dynamics 365 for Operations cloud environment.","pos":[1479,1569]},{"content":"Prospective presales project","pos":[1572,1600]},{"pos":[1680,1751],"content":"Migrate, create solutions, and learn Dynamics 365 for Operationsproject","linkify":"Migrate, create solutions, and learn Dynamics 365 for Operationsproject","nodes":[{"content":"Migrate, create solutions, and learn Dynamics 365 for Operationsproject","pos":[0,71]}]},{"content":"Create a Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 project workspace.","pos":[1753,1807]},{"content":"You can use the project to support the upgrade from Dynamics AX 2012 to the current version of Dynamics 365 for Operations.","pos":[1808,1931]},{"content":"You can also use the project to learn how to use the current version of Dynamics 365 for Operations or create solutions in Microsoft Dynamics AX Lifecycle Services (LCS).","pos":[1932,2102]},{"content":"![lcsforpartnersbrandingupdateart]","pos":[2103,2137]},{"pos":[2143,2172],"content":"Projects for customers in LCS","linkify":"Projects for customers in LCS","nodes":[{"content":"Projects for customers in LCS","pos":[0,29]}]},{"content":"For every customer who signs up for LCS, an Implementation project workspace is automatically created during the sign-up process.","pos":[2174,2303]},{"content":"As a partner, you can't create an Implementation project.","pos":[2304,2361]},{"content":"For more information about the Implementation project workspace, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How Lifecycle Services for Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations works (LCS)<ept id=\"p1\">](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/how-lifecycle-services-for-microsoft-dynamics-ax-works-lcs/)</ept>.","pos":[2362,2607],"source":" For more information about the Implementation project workspace, see [How Lifecycle Services for Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations works (LCS)](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/how-lifecycle-services-for-microsoft-dynamics-ax-works-lcs/)."},{"content":"Services within project workspaces behave in the same manner.","pos":[2608,2669]},{"content":"However, an important difference between an Implementation project and other project types is the ability to configure the current version of Dynamics 365 for Operations, which is managed by Microsoft.","pos":[2670,2871]}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Lifecycle Services (LCS) for Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations partners | Microsoft Docs\ndescription: This article explains how partners can get started with Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS). \nauthor: annbe\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 2016-05-05 20:29:07\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Lifecycle Services\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# keywords: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: 51\nms.suite: Released- Dynamics AX 7.0.0\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 84681\nms.assetid: 666d1400-df8d-4819-b70d-9912491579c6\n# ms.region: \n# ms.industry: \nms.author: annbe\n\n---\n\n# Lifecycle Services (LCS) for Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations partners\n\nAs a Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations partner, you can access the current version  by following the steps in [Sign up for a Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations subscription](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/sign-up-for-a-microsoft-dynamics-rainier-preview-subscription/).\n\n### Projects for partners in LCS\n\nAfter you sign up for the current version of Dynamics 365 for Operations as a partner, you can create two types of projects:\n\n-   Prospective presales\n-   Migrate, create solutions, and learn Dynamics 365 for Operations\n\n#### Prospective presales project\n\nWork with new prospects to help them understand the business processes that are available in Dynamics 365 for Operations, and to help them evaluate their subscription needs. Note that only partners can provision a new Dynamics 365 for Operations cloud environment. ![Prospective presales project](https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/2016/05/27-1024x514.png)\n\n#### Migrate, create solutions, and learn Dynamics 365 for Operationsproject\n\nCreate a Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 project workspace. You can use the project to support the upgrade from Dynamics AX 2012 to the current version of Dynamics 365 for Operations. You can also use the project to learn how to use the current version of Dynamics 365 for Operations or create solutions in Microsoft Dynamics AX Lifecycle Services (LCS). ![lcsforpartnersbrandingupdateart]\n\n### Projects for customers in LCS\n\nFor every customer who signs up for LCS, an Implementation project workspace is automatically created during the sign-up process. As a partner, you can't create an Implementation project. For more information about the Implementation project workspace, see [How Lifecycle Services for Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations works (LCS)](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/how-lifecycle-services-for-microsoft-dynamics-ax-works-lcs/). Services within project workspaces behave in the same manner. However, an important difference between an Implementation project and other project types is the ability to configure the current version of Dynamics 365 for Operations, which is managed by Microsoft.\n\n"}