{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,68],"content":"Configuration rules | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Configuration rules | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,36]}]},{"pos":[82,302],"content":"This article provides general information about configuration rules. Configuration rules define relationships between items in a bill of materials (BOM) for products that use the dimension-based configuration technology.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"This article provides general information about configuration rules. Configuration rules define relationships between items in a bill of materials (BOM) for products that use the dimension-based configuration technology.","pos":[0,220],"nodes":[{"content":"This article provides general information about configuration rules.","pos":[0,68]},{"content":"Configuration rules define relationships between items in a bill of materials (BOM) for products that use the dimension-based configuration technology.","pos":[69,220]}]}]},{"pos":[471,484],"content":"BOMConfigRule","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"BOMConfigRule","pos":[0,13]}]},{"pos":[738,757],"content":"Configuration rules","linkify":"Configuration rules","nodes":[{"content":"Configuration rules","pos":[0,19]}]},{"content":"Configuration rules are available when you define dimension-based configuration models.","pos":[759,846]},{"content":"Configuration rules are used to either enforce or prohibit specific item combinations in a bill of materials (BOM).","pos":[847,962]},{"content":"After a BOM has been created and the relevant items have been assigned to their respective configuration groups, one or more configuration rules can be defined.","pos":[963,1123]},{"content":"If two items belong together, the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Select<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> operator is used to ensure inclusion.","pos":[1124,1206],"source":" If two items belong together, the **Select** operator is used to ensure inclusion."},{"content":"If two items are mutually exclusive, the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Deselect<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> operator is used to ensure exclusion.","pos":[1207,1298],"source":" If two items are mutually exclusive, the **Deselect** operator is used to ensure exclusion."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> This information applies only to product masters that use the dimension-based configuration technology.","pos":[1299,1412],"source":"**Note:** This information applies only to product masters that use the dimension-based configuration technology."},{"content":"Existing configurations aren't affected by subsequent changes to the configuration rules.","pos":[1413,1502]},{"content":"However, it's important that you set the rules before you define a new configuration, and that you check the rules if you think they have been changed.","pos":[1503,1654]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> For the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Select<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> method, the derived configuration group, item number, and configuration are automatically selected.","pos":[1655,1783],"source":"**Note:** For the **Select** method, the derived configuration group, item number, and configuration are automatically selected."},{"content":"For the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Deselect<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> method, the derived configuration group, item number, and configuration can't be selected.","pos":[1784,1895],"source":" For the **Deselect** method, the derived configuration group, item number, and configuration can't be selected."},{"pos":[1897,1905],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[1916,2020],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Dimension-based product configuration<ept id=\"p1\">](https://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/?post_type=incsub_wiki&amp;p=231054)</ept>","source":"[Dimension-based product configuration](https://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/?post_type=incsub_wiki&p=231054)"}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Configuration rules | Microsoft Docs\ndescription: This article provides general information about configuration rules. Configuration rules define relationships between items in a bill of materials (BOM) for products that use the dimension-based configuration technology.\nauthor: annbe\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 2015-12-07 17:51:44\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nkeywords: BOMConfigRule\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \n# ms.reviewer: \nms.suite: Released- Dynamics AX 7.0.0\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 19761\nms.assetid: d50791a2-d29e-4b35-bbf3-beb99067ae9a\n# ms.region: \n# ms.industry: \nms.author: YuyuScheller\n\n---\n\n# Configuration rules\n\nConfiguration rules are available when you define dimension-based configuration models. Configuration rules are used to either enforce or prohibit specific item combinations in a bill of materials (BOM). After a BOM has been created and the relevant items have been assigned to their respective configuration groups, one or more configuration rules can be defined. If two items belong together, the **Select** operator is used to ensure inclusion. If two items are mutually exclusive, the **Deselect** operator is used to ensure exclusion. **Note:** This information applies only to product masters that use the dimension-based configuration technology. Existing configurations aren't affected by subsequent changes to the configuration rules. However, it's important that you set the rules before you define a new configuration, and that you check the rules if you think they have been changed. **Note:** For the **Select** method, the derived configuration group, item number, and configuration are automatically selected. For the **Deselect** method, the derived configuration group, item number, and configuration can't be selected.\n\nSee also\n--------\n\n[Dimension-based product configuration](https://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/?post_type=incsub_wiki&p=231054)\n\n"}