{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: NF-e process overview for Brazil\ndescription: This topic provides an overview of the process for setting up and submitting a Nota fiscal eletrônica (NF-e) to register the movement of items and services between two parties.\nauthor: sndray\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 04/04/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: EFDocContingencyMode_BR, EFDocContingencyModeHistory_BR, EFDocCorrectionLetter_BR, EFDocEmailAccountConfiguration_BR, EFDocEmailStatus_BR, EFDocHist_BR, EFDocParameters_BR, EFDocServiceInquire_BR, FiscalDocument_BR\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: shylaw\nms.search.scope: Operations, Core\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 269114\nms.assetid: 7cb522a4-2f84-4399-a60d-8692df6e08f3\nms.search.region: Brazil\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: sndray\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-11-30\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 1611\n\n---\n\n# NF-e process overview for Brazil\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThis topic provides an overview of the process for setting up and submitting a Nota fiscal eletrônica (NF-e) to register the movement of items and services between two parties.\n\nYou can use a Nota fiscal eletrônica (NF-e) to register the movement of items and services between two parties. You can generate an NF-e from any of the following fiscal documents:\n\n-   Sales orders\n-   Purchase orders for non-taxpayer vendors\n-   Project invoices\n-   Tax fiscal documents\n-   Free text invoices\n\nBefore you can generate an NF-e, you must complete the following tasks:\n\n-   Set up web services, rejection codes, and schemas for a domain.\n-   For each fiscal establishment, set up a certificate, an environment, an NF-e version, an authority, a template, schema validation, and a contingency mode for NF-e. Additionally, set up automatic printing of the Documento auxiliar da Nota fiscal eletrônica (DANFE), so that the DANFE is automatically printed after NF-e approval.\n-   Set up web services that are related to a fiscal authority.\n-   Set up a fiscal document type for an NF-e.\n\nAfter you generate an NF-e, you can submit the digitally signed NF-e to the Secretaria da Fazenda (SEFAZ) in an XML message. The items can be delivered after the NF-e is electronically approved by SEFAZ. The NF-e process includes the following steps:\n\n1.  The fiscal establishment posts a fiscal document by using a fiscal document type that is set up for fiscal document model 55 to generate an NF-e.\n2.  The NF-e export or import process detects the posted fiscal document for the fiscal document model 55 and generates an XML message in the specified format. A separate XML message is generated for each NF-e. The XML message is transmitted to SEFAZ.\n3.  SEFAZ processes the XML message and returns a protocol and status for each NF-e. The NF-e status and protocol are then assigned to the NF-e that is used in the NF-e export or import process. The status that is returned can be **Approved**, **Denied**, **Discarded**, **Canceled**, **Rejected non fixable**, or **Rejected**. This information is used to update the fiscal document status in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations.\n\nAfter the status of the NF-e is received from SEFAZ, you can perform the following tasks, depending on the status:\n\n-   If the NF-e is approved, you can print the DANFE. Alternatively, if the **Print DANFE when NF-e is approved** option is selected on the **NF-e federal** FastTab of the **Fiscal establishments** page, the DANFE is printed automatically.\n-   If the NF-e is denied, you must cancel the NF-e.\n-   If the NF-e is rejected and can be fixed, you can correct the incorrect information, and then click **Resend** on the **NF-e federal** tab of the **Fiscal document** page to resend the NF-e to SEFAZ.\n-   If the NF-e is rejected and can't be fixed, you must cancel the discarded NF-e that has discarded number. The NF-e export or import process detects the fiscal document that is posted and marked for discard, and then generates an XML message in the specified format for the discarded NF-e number. This XML message is then transmitted to SEFAZ, and the fiscal document status is set to **Discarded**.\n\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[32,64],"content":"NF-e process overview for Brazil","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"NF-e process overview for Brazil","pos":[0,32]}]},{"pos":[78,254],"content":"This topic provides an overview of the process for setting up and submitting a Nota fiscal eletrônica (NF-e) to register the movement of items and services between two parties.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"This topic provides an overview of the process for setting up and submitting a Nota fiscal eletrônica (NF-e) to register the movement of items and services between two parties.","pos":[0,176]}]},{"pos":[973,1005],"content":"NF-e process overview for Brazil","linkify":"NF-e process overview for Brazil","nodes":[{"content":"NF-e process overview for Brazil","pos":[0,32]}]},{"content":"This topic provides an overview of the process for setting up and submitting a Nota fiscal eletrônica (NF-e) to register the movement of items and services between two parties.","pos":[1051,1227]},{"content":"You can use a Nota fiscal eletrônica (NF-e) to register the movement of items and services between two parties.","pos":[1229,1340]},{"content":"You can generate an NF-e from any of the following fiscal documents:","pos":[1341,1409]},{"content":"Sales orders","pos":[1415,1427]},{"content":"Purchase orders for non-taxpayer vendors","pos":[1432,1472]},{"content":"Project invoices","pos":[1477,1493]},{"content":"Tax fiscal documents","pos":[1498,1518]},{"content":"Free text invoices","pos":[1523,1541]},{"content":"Before you can generate an NF-e, you must complete the following tasks:","pos":[1543,1614]},{"content":"Set up web services, rejection codes, and schemas for a domain.","pos":[1620,1683]},{"content":"For each fiscal establishment, set up a certificate, an environment, an NF-e version, an authority, a template, schema validation, and a contingency mode for NF-e.","pos":[1688,1851]},{"content":"Additionally, set up automatic printing of the Documento auxiliar da Nota fiscal eletrônica (DANFE), so that the DANFE is automatically printed after NF-e approval.","pos":[1852,2016]},{"content":"Set up web services that are related to a fiscal authority.","pos":[2021,2080]},{"content":"Set up a fiscal document type for an NF-e.","pos":[2085,2127]},{"content":"After you generate an NF-e, you can submit the digitally signed NF-e to the Secretaria da Fazenda (SEFAZ) in an XML message.","pos":[2129,2253]},{"content":"The items can be delivered after the NF-e is electronically approved by SEFAZ.","pos":[2254,2332]},{"content":"The NF-e process includes the following steps:","pos":[2333,2379]},{"content":"The fiscal establishment posts a fiscal document by using a fiscal document type that is set up for fiscal document model 55 to generate an NF-e.","pos":[2385,2530]},{"content":"The NF-e export or import process detects the posted fiscal document for the fiscal document model 55 and generates an XML message in the specified format.","pos":[2535,2690]},{"content":"A separate XML message is generated for each NF-e.","pos":[2691,2741]},{"content":"The XML message is transmitted to SEFAZ.","pos":[2742,2782]},{"content":"SEFAZ processes the XML message and returns a protocol and status for each NF-e.","pos":[2787,2867]},{"content":"The NF-e status and protocol are then assigned to the NF-e that is used in the NF-e export or import process.","pos":[2868,2977]},{"content":"The status that is returned can be <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Approved<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Denied<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Discarded<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Canceled<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p5\">**</bpt>Rejected non fixable<ept id=\"p5\">**</ept>, or <bpt id=\"p6\">**</bpt>Rejected<ept id=\"p6\">**</ept>.","pos":[2978,3110],"source":" The status that is returned can be **Approved**, **Denied**, **Discarded**, **Canceled**, **Rejected non fixable**, or **Rejected**."},{"content":"This information is used to update the fiscal document status in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations.","pos":[3111,3214]},{"content":"After the status of the NF-e is received from SEFAZ, you can perform the following tasks, depending on the status:","pos":[3216,3330]},{"content":"If the NF-e is approved, you can print the DANFE.","pos":[3336,3385]},{"content":"Alternatively, if the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Print DANFE when NF-e is approved<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option is selected on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>NF-e federal<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> FastTab of the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Fiscal establishments<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> page, the DANFE is printed automatically.","pos":[3386,3571],"source":" Alternatively, if the **Print DANFE when NF-e is approved** option is selected on the **NF-e federal** FastTab of the **Fiscal establishments** page, the DANFE is printed automatically."},{"content":"If the NF-e is denied, you must cancel the NF-e.","pos":[3576,3624]},{"pos":[3629,3828],"content":"If the NF-e is rejected and can be fixed, you can correct the incorrect information, and then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Resend<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>NF-e federal<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> tab of the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Fiscal document<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> page to resend the NF-e to SEFAZ.","source":"If the NF-e is rejected and can be fixed, you can correct the incorrect information, and then click **Resend** on the **NF-e federal** tab of the **Fiscal document** page to resend the NF-e to SEFAZ."},{"content":"If the NF-e is rejected and can't be fixed, you must cancel the discarded NF-e that has discarded number.","pos":[3833,3938]},{"content":"The NF-e export or import process detects the fiscal document that is posted and marked for discard, and then generates an XML message in the specified format for the discarded NF-e number.","pos":[3939,4128]},{"content":"This XML message is then transmitted to SEFAZ, and the fiscal document status is set to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Discarded<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[4129,4231],"source":" This XML message is then transmitted to SEFAZ, and the fiscal document status is set to **Discarded**."}]}