{"nodes":[{"pos":[6,23],"content":"required metadata","linkify":"required metadata","nodes":[{"content":"required metadata","pos":[0,17]}]},{"content":"title:  | Microsoft Docs description: Some organizations enter journals that contain a single voucher that has more than one customer or vendor, and they also run the Accounts receivable or Accounts payable foreign currency revaluation process.","pos":[25,269],"source":"title:  | Microsoft Docs\ndescription: Some organizations enter journals that contain a single voucher that has more than one customer or vendor, and they also run the Accounts receivable or Accounts payable foreign currency revaluation process."},{"content":"This topic describes the steps that these organizations should follow when they upgrade to Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations version 1611.","pos":[270,412]},{"content":"author: twheeloc manager: AnnBe ms.date: 2016-12-28 16:04:17 ms.topic: article ms.prod: ms.service: Dynamics365Operations ms.technology:","pos":[413,550],"source":"\nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 2016-12-28 16:04:17\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology:"},{"pos":[555,572],"content":"optional metadata","linkify":"optional metadata","nodes":[{"content":"optional metadata","pos":[0,17]}]},{"pos":[576,585],"content":"keywords:","linkify":"keywords:","nodes":[{"content":"keywords:","pos":[0,9]}]},{"pos":[589,596],"content":"ROBOTS:","linkify":"ROBOTS:","nodes":[{"content":"ROBOTS:","pos":[0,7]}]},{"content":"audience: Application User","pos":[598,624]},{"pos":[627,638],"content":"ms.devlang:","linkify":"ms.devlang:","nodes":[{"content":"ms.devlang:","pos":[0,11]}]},{"pos":[640,718],"content":"ms.reviewer: 2231 ms.suite: Released- Dynamics 365 for Operations version 1611","source":"ms.reviewer: 2231\nms.suite: Released- Dynamics 365 for Operations version 1611"},{"pos":[721,735],"content":"ms.tgt_pltfrm:","linkify":"ms.tgt_pltfrm:","nodes":[{"content":"ms.tgt_pltfrm:","pos":[0,14]}]},{"pos":[737,821],"content":"ms.custom: 265364 ms.assetid: fbbd6cbf-3aae-4f65-99b0-f7eb944ea34f ms.region: Global","source":"ms.custom: 265364\nms.assetid: fbbd6cbf-3aae-4f65-99b0-f7eb944ea34f\nms.region: Global"},{"pos":[824,836],"content":"ms.industry:","linkify":"ms.industry:","nodes":[{"content":"ms.industry:","pos":[0,12]}]},{"content":"ms.author: saraschi","pos":[838,857]},{"content":"Some organizations enter journals that contain a single voucher that has more than one customer or vendor, and they also run the Accounts receivable or Accounts payable foreign currency revaluation process.","pos":[868,1074]},{"content":"This topic describes the steps that these organizations should follow when they upgrade to Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations version 1611.","pos":[1075,1217]},{"content":"Follow these steps when you upgrade to Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations version 1611.","pos":[1219,1309]},{"content":"Before you upgrade to Dynamics 365 for Operations, run the foreign currency revaluation processes for Accounts receivable and Accounts payable.","pos":[1315,1458]},{"content":"Set the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Method<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Invoice date<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[1459,1504],"source":" Set the **Method** field to **Invoice date**."},{"content":"A revaluation transaction is created that reverses the last foreign currency revaluation.","pos":[1505,1594]},{"content":"Therefore, the open transactions are valued at their original accounting currency.","pos":[1595,1677]},{"content":"Upgrade to Dynamics 365 for Operations version 1611.","pos":[1682,1734]},{"content":"Run the Accounts receivable and Accounts payable foreign currency revaluation processes again.","pos":[1739,1833]},{"content":"This time, set the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Method<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Standard<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[1834,1886],"source":" This time, set the **Method** field to **Standard**."},{"content":"A new revaluation transaction is created that is based on the current exchange rates.","pos":[1887,1972]},{"content":"This transaction records the unrealized gain/loss and the correct summary ledger account.","pos":[1973,2062]}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle:  | Microsoft Docs\ndescription: Some organizations enter journals that contain a single voucher that has more than one customer or vendor, and they also run the Accounts receivable or Accounts payable foreign currency revaluation process. This topic describes the steps that these organizations should follow when they upgrade to Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations version 1611.\nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 2016-12-28 16:04:17\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# keywords: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: 2231\nms.suite: Released- Dynamics 365 for Operations version 1611\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 265364\nms.assetid: fbbd6cbf-3aae-4f65-99b0-f7eb944ea34f\nms.region: Global\n# ms.industry: \nms.author: saraschi\n\n---\n\n# \n\nSome organizations enter journals that contain a single voucher that has more than one customer or vendor, and they also run the Accounts receivable or Accounts payable foreign currency revaluation process. This topic describes the steps that these organizations should follow when they upgrade to Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations version 1611.\n\nFollow these steps when you upgrade to Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations version 1611.\n\n1.  Before you upgrade to Dynamics 365 for Operations, run the foreign currency revaluation processes for Accounts receivable and Accounts payable. Set the **Method** field to **Invoice date**. A revaluation transaction is created that reverses the last foreign currency revaluation. Therefore, the open transactions are valued at their original accounting currency.\n2.  Upgrade to Dynamics 365 for Operations version 1611.\n3.  Run the Accounts receivable and Accounts payable foreign currency revaluation processes again. This time, set the **Method** field to **Standard**. A new revaluation transaction is created that is based on the current exchange rates. This transaction records the unrealized gain/loss and the correct summary ledger account.\n\n\n"}