{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,88],"content":"Posting with derived depreciation books | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Posting with derived depreciation books | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,56]}]},{"pos":[102,163],"content":"This article describes how to use derived depreciation books.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"This article describes how to use derived depreciation books.","pos":[0,61]}]},{"pos":[332,371],"content":"AssetBookTable, LedgerJournalTransAsset","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"AssetBookTable, LedgerJournalTransAsset","pos":[0,39]}]},{"pos":[620,659],"content":"Posting with derived depreciation books","linkify":"Posting with derived depreciation books","nodes":[{"content":"Posting with derived depreciation books","pos":[0,39]}]},{"content":"When you post transactions for a value model that contains derived depreciation books, the derived depreciation book transactions are posted automatically from journals, purchase orders, or free text invoices.","pos":[661,870]},{"content":"If you prepare the primary value model transactions in the Fixed assets journal, however, you can view and modify the amounts of the derived transactions before you post them.","pos":[871,1046]},{"content":"Acquisition is often used as the transaction type for the derived depreciation book.","pos":[1051,1135]},{"content":"You use this when the value model and the derived depreciation book should be applied to the fixed asset from the time of acquisition of the fixed asset.","pos":[1136,1289]},{"content":"Other values for the transaction type also can apply.","pos":[1294,1347]},{"content":"For example, if the value model and the derived depreciation book have the same intervals regarding sale or disposal, all fixed asset transaction types are available for the setup of a derived depreciation book.","pos":[1348,1559]},{"pos":[1563,1574],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Caution<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**Caution**"},{"content":"Depreciation posted in the derived depreciation book will be the same amount as was posted for the value model.","pos":[2135,2246]},{"content":"If the depreciation methods are different between the value model and the depreciation book, you should not generate depreciation transactions using the derived process.","pos":[2247,2416]},{"content":"Example Refer to the following information to see how to set up acquisition transactions using derived depreciation books.","pos":[2420,2542]},{"content":"Create the value model in the Value models form and the depreciation book in the Depreciation books page.","pos":[2547,2652]},{"content":"The value model for accounting: VM, Current posting layer","pos":[2661,2718]},{"content":"The depreciation book for tax purposes: DB","pos":[2727,2769]},{"content":"In the Value models form for VM, click the Derived depreciation books tab, and select DB in the Depreciation book field, and Acquisition in the Transaction type field.","pos":[2775,2942]},{"content":"The value model and depreciation book then can be attached to specific fixed assets.","pos":[2944,3028]},{"content":"When an acquisition is posted for a fixed asset with value model VM, the acquisition is posted not only on VM, but also on the derived depreciation book DB.","pos":[3029,3185]},{"content":"The fixed asset can then be depreciated in the value model and the depreciation book.","pos":[3186,3271]},{"pos":[3274,3282],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**Note**"},{"content":"If you do not use derived depreciation books, you must post the acquisition of the fixed asset for both value model VM and depreciation book DB.","pos":[3572,3716]},{"pos":[3722,3730],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[3741,3835],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Derived depreciation books<ept id=\"p1\">](https://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/derived-depreciation-books/)</ept>","source":"[Derived depreciation books](https://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/derived-depreciation-books/)"}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Posting with derived depreciation books | Microsoft Docs\ndescription: This article describes how to use derived depreciation books.\nauthor: annbe\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 2015-09-10 20:18:06\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nkeywords: AssetBookTable, LedgerJournalTransAsset\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \n# ms.reviewer: \nms.suite: Released- Dynamics AX 7.0.0\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 2981\nms.assetid: 70539590-6237-42bc-a986-fc373cb961c7\n# ms.region: \n# ms.industry: \nms.author: twheeloc\n\n---\n\n# Posting with derived depreciation books\n\nWhen you post transactions for a value model that contains derived depreciation books, the derived depreciation book transactions are posted automatically from journals, purchase orders, or free text invoices. If you prepare the primary value model transactions in the Fixed assets journal, however, you can view and modify the amounts of the derived transactions before you post them.\n-   Acquisition is often used as the transaction type for the derived depreciation book. You use this when the value model and the derived depreciation book should be applied to the fixed asset from the time of acquisition of the fixed asset.\n-   Other values for the transaction type also can apply. For example, if the value model and the derived depreciation book have the same intervals regarding sale or disposal, all fixed asset transaction types are available for the setup of a derived depreciation book.\n\n| **Caution**                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                               |\n|-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| Depreciation posted in the derived depreciation book will be the same amount as was posted for the value model. If the depreciation methods are different between the value model and the depreciation book, you should not generate depreciation transactions using the derived process. |\n\nExample Refer to the following information to see how to set up acquisition transactions using derived depreciation books.\n1.  Create the value model in the Value models form and the depreciation book in the Depreciation books page.\n    -   The value model for accounting: VM, Current posting layer\n    -   The depreciation book for tax purposes: DB\n\n2.  In the Value models form for VM, click the Derived depreciation books tab, and select DB in the Depreciation book field, and Acquisition in the Transaction type field.\n\nThe value model and depreciation book then can be attached to specific fixed assets. When an acquisition is posted for a fixed asset with value model VM, the acquisition is posted not only on VM, but also on the derived depreciation book DB. The fixed asset can then be depreciated in the value model and the depreciation book.\n| **Note**                                                                                                                                         |\n|--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| If you do not use derived depreciation books, you must post the acquisition of the fixed asset for both value model VM and depreciation book DB. |\n\n\n\nSee also\n--------\n\n[Derived depreciation books](https://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/derived-depreciation-books/)\n\n"}