{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,60],"content":"Order holds | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Order holds | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,28]}]},{"pos":[74,152],"content":"This topic describes holds on orders using Retail and commerce in Dynamics AX.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"This topic describes holds on orders using Retail and commerce in Dynamics AX.","pos":[0,78]}]},{"pos":[581,592],"content":"Order holds","linkify":"Order holds","nodes":[{"content":"Order holds","pos":[0,11]}]},{"content":"An order can be put on hold for various reasons.","pos":[594,642]},{"content":"For example, you might put an order on hold until the customer address or payment method can be verified, or until a manager can review the customer’s credit limit.","pos":[643,807]},{"content":"During the sales process, there are times when sales orders must be put on hold.","pos":[808,888]},{"content":"For example, a sales order might be put on hold because of issues with a customer payment, because of suspected fraud, or because a manager must review the order.","pos":[889,1051]},{"content":"When a sales order is put on hold, an order hold code is assigned to the sales order to indicate the reason for the hold.","pos":[1052,1173]},{"content":"Sales order hold codes are configured at <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Sales and marketing<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Setup<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Sales orders<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph3\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Order holds codes<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>.","pos":[1174,1303],"source":" Sales order hold codes are configured at **Sales and marketing** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Sales orders** &gt; **Order holds codes**."},{"content":"A sales order can be put on hold manually at the time of order creation or later.","pos":[1304,1385]},{"content":"Additionally, an order can be put on hold automatically, based on fraud rules.","pos":[1386,1464]},{"content":"While a sales order is on hold, you might have to update it with more information.","pos":[1465,1547]},{"content":"Alternatively, you might want to check out the sales order as you continue to work on it.","pos":[1548,1637]},{"content":"You can check out a sales order, check it back in, and even override the checkout of another user by using the order hold workbench (<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Retail and commerce<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Customers<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Order holds<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>).","pos":[1638,1836],"source":" You can check out a sales order, check it back in, and even override the checkout of another user by using the order hold workbench (**Retail and commerce** &gt; **Customers** &gt; **Order holds**)."},{"content":"When an order is ready to be completed, you must remove the hold before you can complete the order process.","pos":[1837,1944]}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Order holds | Microsoft Docs\ndescription: This topic describes holds on orders using Retail and commerce in Dynamics AX.\nauthor: annbe\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 2016-04-07 19:46:08\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# keywords: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: 2041\nms.suite: Released- Dynamics AX 7.0.0\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 79132\nms.assetid: 86ef09f7-0a38-4c95-8e27-50222340cf0f\nms.region: global\nms.industry: Retail\nms.author: josaw1\n\n---\n\n# Order holds\n\nAn order can be put on hold for various reasons. For example, you might put an order on hold until the customer address or payment method can be verified, or until a manager can review the customer’s credit limit. During the sales process, there are times when sales orders must be put on hold. For example, a sales order might be put on hold because of issues with a customer payment, because of suspected fraud, or because a manager must review the order. When a sales order is put on hold, an order hold code is assigned to the sales order to indicate the reason for the hold. Sales order hold codes are configured at **Sales and marketing** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Sales orders** &gt; **Order holds codes**. A sales order can be put on hold manually at the time of order creation or later. Additionally, an order can be put on hold automatically, based on fraud rules. While a sales order is on hold, you might have to update it with more information. Alternatively, you might want to check out the sales order as you continue to work on it. You can check out a sales order, check it back in, and even override the checkout of another user by using the order hold workbench (**Retail and commerce** &gt; **Customers** &gt; **Order holds**). When an order is ready to be completed, you must remove the hold before you can complete the order process.\n\n"}