{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Electronic reporting sample vendor checks\ndescription: This topic provides general information about how to use the Electronic reporting sample check formats.\nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 05/09/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \n# ms.reviewer: twheeloc \n# ms.search.scope: \n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \n# ms.custom: \nms.assetid: \nms.search.region: Global \n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: twheeloc\nms.dyn365.intro: 2017/06/01\nms.dyn365.version:\n\n---\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n# Electronic reporting sample check formats\n\nYou can use Electronic reporting to format vendor checks. Many bank-specific and check provider–specific check formats are available in the market. Sample check formats have been included in the Electronic reporting tool repository.\n\n## What check formats are currently supported?\n\nYou should always go to the Shared asset library on Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS) and view the most up-to-date list of available files that have an asset type of **GER configuration**. The next section, “What do I have to set up?,” includes a link to a topic that explains how to create an LCS repository so that you can review available configurations and import selected configurations.\n\nMicrosoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition includes a sample format where the check is on top, followed by two remittance sections. It also includes a sample format where the check is in the middle, between two remittance sections. These sample formats correspond to Deluxe business checks formats.\n\n## What do I have to set up?\n\n- Before you can print checks by using Electronic reporting, at least one active check configuration must be imported into your Electronic reporting configurations. For instructions, see [Download Electronic reporting configurations from Lifecycle Services](/dev-itpro/analytics/download-electronic-reporting-configuration-lcs.md).\n- When you configure Cash and bank management checks for the bank account, select the **Generic electronic Export format** check box, and select the appropriate check format as an export format configuration.\n- You must also specify the number of slip lines that will be printed on the remittance. Be sure to include the header rows when you calculate this number.\n- When you generate payments for the configured bank account in the payment journal, the checks will be printed by using the specified format.\n","nodes":[{"pos":[32,73],"content":"Electronic reporting sample vendor checks","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Electronic reporting sample vendor checks","pos":[0,41]}]},{"pos":[87,190],"content":"This topic provides general information about how to use the Electronic reporting sample check formats.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"This topic provides general information about how to use the Electronic reporting sample check formats.","pos":[0,103]}]},{"pos":[664,705],"content":"Electronic reporting sample check formats","linkify":"Electronic reporting sample check formats","nodes":[{"content":"Electronic reporting sample check formats","pos":[0,41]}]},{"content":"You can use Electronic reporting to format vendor checks.","pos":[707,764]},{"content":"Many bank-specific and check provider–specific check formats are available in the market.","pos":[765,854]},{"content":"Sample check formats have been included in the Electronic reporting tool repository.","pos":[855,939]},{"pos":[944,987],"content":"What check formats are currently supported?","linkify":"What check formats are currently supported?","nodes":[{"content":"What check formats are currently supported?","pos":[0,43]}]},{"content":"You should always go to the Shared asset library on Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS) and view the most up-to-date list of available files that have an asset type of <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>GER configuration<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[989,1187],"source":"You should always go to the Shared asset library on Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS) and view the most up-to-date list of available files that have an asset type of **GER configuration**."},{"content":"The next section, “What do I have to set up?,” includes a link to a topic that explains how to create an LCS repository so that you can review available configurations and import selected configurations.","pos":[1188,1391]},{"content":"Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition includes a sample format where the check is on top, followed by two remittance sections.","pos":[1393,1551]},{"content":"It also includes a sample format where the check is in the middle, between two remittance sections.","pos":[1552,1651]},{"content":"These sample formats correspond to Deluxe business checks formats.","pos":[1652,1718]},{"pos":[1723,1748],"content":"What do I have to set up?","linkify":"What do I have to set up?","nodes":[{"content":"What do I have to set up?","pos":[0,25]}]},{"content":"Before you can print checks by using Electronic reporting, at least one active check configuration must be imported into your Electronic reporting configurations.","pos":[1752,1914]},{"content":"For instructions, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Download Electronic reporting configurations from Lifecycle Services<ept id=\"p1\">](/dev-itpro/analytics/download-electronic-reporting-configuration-lcs.md)</ept>.","pos":[1915,2081],"source":" For instructions, see [Download Electronic reporting configurations from Lifecycle Services](/dev-itpro/analytics/download-electronic-reporting-configuration-lcs.md)."},{"pos":[2084,2290],"content":"When you configure Cash and bank management checks for the bank account, select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Generic electronic Export format<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> check box, and select the appropriate check format as an export format configuration.","source":"When you configure Cash and bank management checks for the bank account, select the **Generic electronic Export format** check box, and select the appropriate check format as an export format configuration."},{"content":"You must also specify the number of slip lines that will be printed on the remittance.","pos":[2293,2379]},{"content":"Be sure to include the header rows when you calculate this number.","pos":[2380,2446]},{"content":"When you generate payments for the configured bank account in the payment journal, the checks will be printed by using the specified format.","pos":[2449,2589]}]}