{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Microsoft FastTrack for Dynamics 365 overview\ndescription: Microsoft FastTrack for Dynamics 365 is our customer success service designed to help you move to Dynamics 365 smoothly and confidently, so you can realize business value faster. \nauthor: margoc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 05/12/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \n# ms.reviewer: 11\nms.search.scope: Operations, Core\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 267934\nms.assetid: 26681541-bee2-4f54-92bd-f549e3b414c1\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: margoc\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-11-30\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 1611\n\n---\n\n# Microsoft FastTrack for Dynamics 365 overview\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nMicrosoft FastTrack for Dynamics 365 is our customer success service designed to help you move to Dynamics 365 smoothly and confidently, so you can realize business value faster. When you participate in the FastTrack program, you will receive guidance on best practices and how to plan for successful rollouts. You will also learn ways to enable new users and expand capabilities – all at your own pace. Additionally, you will have access to Microsoft engineering resources committed to make your experience with Dynamics 365 a success.  \n\n## Eligibility: Microsoft FastTrack for Dynamics 365\n\n**Product offering: Dynamics 365, Enterprise edition**\n\n| **Minimum seats**                                                                  | **Eligible SKUs, Apps, or Plans** |\n|--------------------------------------------------------------------------------|-------------------------------|\n| 250 combined eligible App or Plan user subscription licenses                   | Sales <br> Field service <br>Customer service <br> Project service automation<br>Plan 1<br>Plan 2 with a commitment to implement Sales, Field Service, Customer Service, or Project Service Automation apps                         |\n| 20 combined eligible App or Plan user subscription licenses, or the equivalent | Operations<br>Plan 2, with a commitment to implement the Operations app<br><br>**Note:** 2.5 device subscription licenses are considered the equivalent of one Finance and Operations user subscription license   \n\n**Product offering: Dynamics CRM Online**\n\n| Minimum seats              | Eligible SKUs, Apps, or Plans |\n|----------------------------|-------------------------------|\n| 250 combined eligible SKUs | Enterprise<br>Professional<br>Basic                    |\n\n**Tiered services for Finance and Operations**\n\n| **Number of seats**                                                                         | **Tech talks** | **Workshops**                      | **Touchpoints**   | **FastTrack engineering resources** |\n|-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|------------|--------------------------------|---------------|---------------------------------|\n| 20-149 combined eligible App or Plan user subscription licenses, or the equivalent      | **✓**      | Pre Go-live milestone workshop | Not available | Not available                   |\n| 150 or more combined eligible App or Plan user subscription licenses, or the equivalent | **✓**          | **✓**                              | **✓**             | **✓**                               |\n\n\n## Overview: Microsoft FastTrack for Dynamics 365\nDuring FastTrack engagements, the Dynamics FastTrack engineering team will offer customers opportunities to get practical guidance on cloud deployment, help with usage and adoption, and assist with removing blockers during implementation through the following interactions:\n\n-   **Regular touchpoints** are typically 30-minute calls that continue throughout the duration of the engagements. Small technical proof points are sometimes provided to help remove customer roadblocks.\n-   **Workshops** are interactive outcome-based activities, and may involve automation and tooling. Customers and partners can provide input prior to the workshops and customize them for their engagements.\n-   **Tech talks** focus on providing technical depth and best practices that empower both customers and partners with knowledge that is specific to the subject areas. These talks often provide an overview of available tooling and/or content.\n\nAll sessions are delivered remotely by the FastTrack engineering team. We have time zone-based resources to cover major markets in the Americas, EMEA, and APAC. [![FastTrack diagram](./media/fasttrack-ops-1024x438.png)](./media/fasttrack-ops.png)\n\n## Workshops\nWorkshops are interactive outcome-based activities, and may involve automation and tooling. Customers and partners can provide input prior to the workshops and customize them for their engagements.\n\n#### Kickoff workshop\n\nThe Kickoff workshop is designed to initiate FastTrack engagements and provide introduction to services available through FastTrack and onboarding guidance. Topics are likely to include:\n\n-   Team introductions\n-   FastTrack for Finance and Operations overview\n-   Project goals and objectives\n-   Engagement scope, schedule, and adoption targets\n-   Responsibilities among customers, partners, and the Microsoft FastTrack engineering team\n-   Explanation on how services are delivered, where and when to seek help from the Microsoft FastTrack engineering team\n-   Introduction to Dynamics Lifecycle Service (LCS) and Finance and Operations Microsoft docs site\n-   Pre-activation checklist\n-   Environment planning\n-   Regular touchpoint schedule\n\nThe typical format is a one-hour Skype call. The recommended attendees include key stakeholders from customer, partner, and Microsoft teams.\n\n### Governance workshop\n\nThe Governance workshop is designed to provide planning and governance recommendations based on project needs and best practices from other cloud deployments. Topics are likely to include:\n\n-   Project team structure – customer and partner teams\n-   Implementation approach\n-   Project timeline and key milestones\n-   Risk register – known risk and mitigation plans\n-   Guidance on user training, adoption, and change management\n-   How to manage product issues and reach out to Microsoft\n    -   Microsoft Support for Finance and Operations\n    -   LCS cloud-powered support\n\nThe typical format is a 1.5-hour Skype call. The recommended attendees include key stakeholders from customer and partner teams. Project managers are mandatory.\n\n### Solution workshop\n\nThe Solution workshop is designed to provide guidance on solution design alignment with our public cloud deployment approach, a review of the product roadmap, and project goals and schedule. Topics are likely to include:\n\n-   Solution overview\n-   Conceptual architecture\n-   Key customizations and extensions\n-   Integration approach\n-   Data management\n    -   Configuration management\n    -   Data migration approach\n-   Test strategy\n-   Performance testing (if required)\n-   BI/reporting strategy\n-   ISV solutions\n-   Environment plans\n\nThe typical format is a 1.5-hour Skype call. The recommended attendees include key stakeholders from customer and partner teams. Solution architects, functional leads, and technical leads are mandatory.\n\n### Build workshop\n\nThe Build workshop is designed to review the development approach, build progress, quality, risks, and blockers. Topics are likely to include:\n\n-   Progress on development\n-   Progress on system configuration\n-   Integration\n-   Reporting/BI status\n-   Test results\n-   Bug stats\n-   Performance results\n-   Development risks and mitigations\n\nThe typical format is a 1.5-hour Skype call. The recommended attendees include key stakeholders from customer and partner teams. Solution architects and technical leads are mandatory.\n\n### Pre go-live readiness workshop\n\nThe Pre go-live readiness workshop is designed to ensure that there are no last-minute blockers during cutover and go-live. Topics are likely to include:\n\n-   Go-live scope confirmation\n-   Bug and build status\n-   Blocking issue review\n-   User training and organization change management status\n-   Cutover plan and final data migration\n-   Hyper-care plan\n-   Risk and mitigation review\n-   Customer go/no-go criteria\n-   Recap support process\n\nThe typical format is 1.5-hour Skype call. The recommended attendees include key business users and subject matter experts. Hyper-care team leads are mandatory.\n\n### Post go-live review workshop\n\nThe Post go-live review workshop is designed to wrap up the FastTrack engagement. Topics are likely to include:\n\n-   Review goals and objectives\n-   Discuss lessons learned\n-   Review aged Support items\n-   Hand over open issues to Support teams\n-   Support overview content\n-   Pro-Direct Support overview (if applicable)\n\nThe typical format is a 1.5-hour Skype call. The recommended attendees include key stakeholders from customer, partner, and Microsoft teams. Project managers are mandatory.\n\n## Tech talks\nTech talks focus on providing technical depth and best practices that empower both customers and partners with knowledge that is specific to the subject areas. These talks often provide an overview of available tooling and content.\n\nSome of the tech talks are recorded, and the recordings are available on the [Microsoft Dynamics 365 YouTube channel](https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCJGCg4rB3QSs8y_1FquelBQ).\n\n### Lifecycle Services (LCS) usage tech talk\n\nThe Lifecycle Services usage tech talk is designed to introduce customers to LCS. Key topics might include:\n\n-   Introduction to LCS\n-   LCS scope, schedule, and adoption targets\n-   Customer, partner, and Microsoft team usage scenarios\n-   Common usage and related best practices\n-   How to stay on top of new features/services available\n-   Further learning opportunities\n\nThe typical format is a one-hour Skype call. The recommended attendees include key stakeholders from the customer, partner, and Microsoft teams.\n\n### Tenant/Visual Studio online configuration tech talk\n\nThe Tenant/Visual Studio Online configuration tech talk is designed to provide guidance on how to configure tenant and Visual Studio Online. Key topics might include:\n\n-   Connect from LCS\n-   Best practices in configuration\n-   Common pitfalls\n-   Continued learning\n\nThe typical format is a one-hour Skype call. The recommended attendees include technical resources from customer and partner teams.\n\n### Environment plan tech talk\n\nThe Environment plan tech talk is designed to provide guidance on how to plan and use environments. Key topics might include:\n\n-   Environment planning\n-   Optimal utilization of the default environments in the standard offer\n-   How to purchase add-ons\n-   ISV approach\n-   Performance testing\n-   Configuration management\n\nThe typical format is a one-hour Skype call. The recommended attendees include technical resources from customer and partner teams.\n\n### Development Application Lifecycle Management (ALM) tech talk\n\nThe Development ALM tech talk is designed to provide guidance on ALM best practices. Key topics might include:\n\n-   Packaging and release management\n-   Build orchestration – builds and build VMs\n-   Source control\n-   Branching\n-   Developer VMs\n-   Automated testing\n\nThe typical format is a one-hour Skype call. The recommended attendees include technical resources from customer and partner teams.\n\n### Integration guidelines tech talk\n\nThe Integration guidelines tech talk is designed to provide guidance on key integration topics throughout implementation. Key topics might include:\n\n-   Integration approaches for the cloud\n-   Recurring integrations\n-   File-based integrations\n-   Role of data entities in integrations\n-   Integration platform choices\n\nThe typical format is a one-hour Skype call. The recommended attendees include technical resources from customer and partner teams.\n\n### Reporting and Business Intelligence (BI) guidance tech talk\n\nThe Reporting and BI guidance tech talk is designed to provide guidance on leveraging key analytics capabilities of Finance and Operations. Key topics might include:\n\n-   Entity store\n-   Power BI\n-   Configuration\n-   Content packs – building and consuming\n-   Common pitfalls\n-   Continued learning\n\nThe typical format is a one-hour Skype call. The recommended attendees include technical resources from the customer and partner teams.\n\n### Data management tech talk\n\nThe Data management tech talk is designed to provide guidance on how to migrate and/or manage data entities and packages. Key topics might include:\n\n-   Data entities\n-   Data packages\n-   Process data packages\n-   Configuration management using data packages\n-   Data migration\n-   ETL approach and tool (DIXF)\n-   Masters\n-   Transactions\n-   Delta processing\n\nThe typical format is a 1.5-hour Skype call. The recommended attendees include technical resources from customer and partner teams.\n\n### Performance testing tech talk\n\nThe Performance testing tech talk is designed to provide guidance on planning and executing performance testing. Key topics might include:\n\n-   Defining a performance test plan\n-   Taking a trace with Trace Parser and analyzing it\n-   Taking a trace and using it for data expansion\n-   Introduction to the Performance SDK and multiuser testing with Visual Studio Online\n-   Performance timer (optional)\n-   Further learning opportunities\n\nThe typical format is a one-hour Skype call. The recommended attendees include technical resources from customer and partner teams.\n\n### Servicing tech talk\n\nThe Servicing tech talk is designed to provide guidance on the servicing options available to customers. Key topics might include:\n\n-   Overview of the servicing story\n-   DSE team\n-   Deploying hotfixes\n-   Submitting a service request\n-   Cloud powered support\n\nThe typical format is a one-hour Skype call. The recommended attendees include project managers and technical resources from customer and partner teams.\n","nodes":[{"pos":[32,77],"content":"Microsoft FastTrack for Dynamics 365 overview","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Microsoft FastTrack for Dynamics 365 overview","pos":[0,45]}]},{"pos":[91,269],"content":"Microsoft FastTrack for Dynamics 365 is our customer success service designed to help you move to Dynamics 365 smoothly and confidently, so you can realize business value faster.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Microsoft FastTrack for Dynamics 365 is our customer success service designed to help you move to Dynamics 365 smoothly and confidently, so you can realize business value faster.","pos":[0,178]}]},{"pos":[765,810],"content":"Microsoft FastTrack for Dynamics 365 overview","linkify":"Microsoft FastTrack for Dynamics 365 overview","nodes":[{"content":"Microsoft FastTrack for Dynamics 365 overview","pos":[0,45]}]},{"content":"Microsoft FastTrack for Dynamics 365 is our customer success service designed to help you move to Dynamics 365 smoothly and confidently, so you can realize business value faster.","pos":[856,1034]},{"content":"When you participate in the FastTrack program, you will receive guidance on best practices and how to plan for successful rollouts.","pos":[1035,1166]},{"content":"You will also learn ways to enable new users and expand capabilities – all at your own pace.","pos":[1167,1259]},{"content":"Additionally, you will have access to Microsoft engineering resources committed to make your experience with Dynamics 365 a success.","pos":[1260,1392]},{"pos":[1399,1448],"content":"Eligibility: Microsoft FastTrack for Dynamics 365","linkify":"Eligibility: Microsoft FastTrack for Dynamics 365","nodes":[{"content":"Eligibility: Microsoft FastTrack for Dynamics 365","pos":[0,49]}]},{"pos":[1450,1504],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Product offering: Dynamics 365, Enterprise edition<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**Product offering: Dynamics 365, Enterprise edition**"},{"pos":[1508,1525],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Minimum seats<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**Minimum seats**"},{"pos":[1593,1626],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Eligible SKUs, Apps, or Plans<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**Eligible SKUs, Apps, or Plans**"},{"content":"250 combined eligible App or Plan user subscription licenses","pos":[1746,1806]},{"content":"Sales","pos":[1827,1832]},{"content":"Field service","pos":[1838,1851]},{"content":"Customer service","pos":[1856,1872]},{"content":"Project service automation","pos":[1878,1904]},{"content":"Plan 1","pos":[1908,1914]},{"content":"Plan 2 with a commitment to implement Sales, Field Service, Customer Service, or Project Service Automation apps","pos":[1918,2030]},{"content":"20 combined eligible App or Plan user subscription licenses, or the equivalent","pos":[2059,2137]},{"content":"Operations","pos":[2140,2150]},{"content":"Plan 2, with a commitment to implement the Operations app","pos":[2154,2211]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> 2.5 device subscription licenses are considered the equivalent of one Finance and Operations user subscription license","pos":[2219,2347],"source":"**Note:** 2.5 device subscription licenses are considered the equivalent of one Finance and Operations user subscription license"},{"pos":[2352,2393],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Product offering: Dynamics CRM Online<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**Product offering: Dynamics CRM Online**"},{"content":"Minimum seats","pos":[2397,2410]},{"content":"Eligible SKUs, Apps, or Plans","pos":[2426,2455]},{"content":"250 combined eligible SKUs","pos":[2523,2549]},{"content":"Enterprise","pos":[2552,2562]},{"content":"Professional","pos":[2566,2578]},{"content":"Basic","pos":[2582,2587]},{"pos":[2610,2656],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tiered services for Finance and Operations<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**Tiered services for Finance and Operations**"},{"pos":[2660,2679],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Number of seats<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**Number of seats**"},{"pos":[2754,2768],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tech talks<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**Tech talks**"},{"pos":[2771,2784],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Workshops<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**Workshops**"},{"pos":[2808,2823],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Touchpoints<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**Touchpoints**"},{"pos":[2828,2863],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>FastTrack engineering resources<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**FastTrack engineering resources**"},{"content":"20-149 combined eligible App or Plan user subscription licenses, or the equivalent","pos":[3056,3138]},{"pos":[3146,3151],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>✓<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**✓**"},{"content":"Pre Go-live milestone workshop","pos":[3159,3189]},{"content":"Not available","pos":[3192,3205]},{"content":"Not available","pos":[3208,3221]},{"content":"150 or more combined eligible App or Plan user subscription licenses, or the equivalent","pos":[3244,3331]},{"pos":[3334,3339],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>✓<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**✓**"},{"pos":[3351,3356],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>✓<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**✓**"},{"pos":[3388,3393],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>✓<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**✓**"},{"pos":[3408,3413],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>✓<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**✓**"},{"pos":[3451,3497],"content":"Overview: Microsoft FastTrack for Dynamics 365","linkify":"Overview: Microsoft FastTrack for Dynamics 365","nodes":[{"content":"Overview: Microsoft FastTrack for Dynamics 365","pos":[0,46]}]},{"content":"During FastTrack engagements, the Dynamics FastTrack engineering team will offer customers opportunities to get practical guidance on cloud deployment, help with usage and adoption, and assist with removing blockers during implementation through the following interactions:","pos":[3498,3771]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Regular touchpoints<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> are typically 30-minute calls that continue throughout the duration of the engagements.","pos":[3777,3888],"source":"**Regular touchpoints** are typically 30-minute calls that continue throughout the duration of the engagements."},{"content":"Small technical proof points are sometimes provided to help remove customer roadblocks.","pos":[3889,3976]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Workshops<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> are interactive outcome-based activities, and may involve automation and tooling.","pos":[3981,4076],"source":"**Workshops** are interactive outcome-based activities, and may involve automation and tooling."},{"content":"Customers and partners can provide input prior to the workshops and customize them for their engagements.","pos":[4077,4182]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tech talks<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> focus on providing technical depth and best practices that empower both customers and partners with knowledge that is specific to the subject areas.","pos":[4187,4350],"source":"**Tech talks** focus on providing technical depth and best practices that empower both customers and partners with knowledge that is specific to the subject areas."},{"content":"These talks often provide an overview of available tooling and/or content.","pos":[4351,4425]},{"content":"All sessions are delivered remotely by the FastTrack engineering team.","pos":[4427,4497]},{"content":"We have time zone-based resources to cover major markets in the Americas, EMEA, and APAC.","pos":[4498,4587]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>FastTrack diagram<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/fasttrack-ops-1024x438.png)](./media/fasttrack-ops.png)</ept>","pos":[4588,4673],"source":"[![FastTrack diagram](./media/fasttrack-ops-1024x438.png)](./media/fasttrack-ops.png)"},{"pos":[4678,4687],"content":"Workshops","linkify":"Workshops","nodes":[{"content":"Workshops","pos":[0,9]}]},{"content":"Workshops are interactive outcome-based activities, and may involve automation and tooling.","pos":[4688,4779]},{"content":"Customers and partners can provide input prior to the workshops and customize them for their engagements.","pos":[4780,4885]},{"pos":[4892,4908],"content":"Kickoff workshop","linkify":"Kickoff workshop","nodes":[{"content":"Kickoff workshop","pos":[0,16]}]},{"content":"The Kickoff workshop is designed to initiate FastTrack engagements and provide introduction to services available through FastTrack and onboarding guidance.","pos":[4910,5066]},{"content":"Topics are likely to include:","pos":[5067,5096]},{"content":"Team introductions","pos":[5102,5120]},{"content":"FastTrack for Finance and Operations overview","pos":[5125,5170]},{"content":"Project goals and objectives","pos":[5175,5203]},{"content":"Engagement scope, schedule, and adoption targets","pos":[5208,5256]},{"content":"Responsibilities among customers, partners, and the Microsoft FastTrack engineering team","pos":[5261,5349]},{"content":"Explanation on how services are delivered, where and when to seek help from the Microsoft FastTrack engineering team","pos":[5354,5470]},{"content":"Introduction to Dynamics Lifecycle Service (LCS) and Finance and Operations Microsoft docs site","pos":[5475,5570]},{"content":"Pre-activation checklist","pos":[5575,5599]},{"content":"Environment planning","pos":[5604,5624]},{"content":"Regular touchpoint schedule","pos":[5629,5656]},{"content":"The typical format is a one-hour Skype call.","pos":[5658,5702]},{"content":"The recommended attendees include key stakeholders from customer, partner, and Microsoft teams.","pos":[5703,5798]},{"pos":[5804,5823],"content":"Governance workshop","linkify":"Governance workshop","nodes":[{"content":"Governance workshop","pos":[0,19]}]},{"content":"The Governance workshop is designed to provide planning and governance recommendations based on project needs and best practices from other cloud deployments.","pos":[5825,5983]},{"content":"Topics are likely to include:","pos":[5984,6013]},{"content":"Project team structure – customer and partner teams","pos":[6019,6070]},{"content":"Implementation approach","pos":[6075,6098]},{"content":"Project timeline and key milestones","pos":[6103,6138]},{"content":"Risk register – known risk and mitigation plans","pos":[6143,6190]},{"content":"Guidance on user training, adoption, and change management","pos":[6195,6253]},{"content":"How to manage product issues and reach out to Microsoft","pos":[6258,6313]},{"content":"Microsoft Support for Finance and Operations","pos":[6322,6366]},{"content":"LCS cloud-powered support","pos":[6375,6400]},{"content":"The typical format is a 1.5-hour Skype call.","pos":[6402,6446]},{"content":"The recommended attendees include key stakeholders from customer and partner teams.","pos":[6447,6530]},{"content":"Project managers are mandatory.","pos":[6531,6562]},{"pos":[6568,6585],"content":"Solution workshop","linkify":"Solution workshop","nodes":[{"content":"Solution workshop","pos":[0,17]}]},{"content":"The Solution workshop is designed to provide guidance on solution design alignment with our public cloud deployment approach, a review of the product roadmap, and project goals and schedule.","pos":[6587,6777]},{"content":"Topics are likely to include:","pos":[6778,6807]},{"content":"Solution overview","pos":[6813,6830]},{"content":"Conceptual architecture","pos":[6835,6858]},{"content":"Key customizations and extensions","pos":[6863,6896]},{"content":"Integration approach","pos":[6901,6921]},{"content":"Data management","pos":[6926,6941]},{"content":"Configuration management","pos":[6950,6974]},{"content":"Data migration approach","pos":[6983,7006]},{"content":"Test strategy","pos":[7011,7024]},{"content":"Performance testing (if required)","pos":[7029,7062]},{"content":"BI/reporting strategy","pos":[7067,7088]},{"content":"ISV solutions","pos":[7093,7106]},{"content":"Environment plans","pos":[7111,7128]},{"content":"The typical format is a 1.5-hour Skype call.","pos":[7130,7174]},{"content":"The recommended attendees include key stakeholders from customer and partner teams.","pos":[7175,7258]},{"content":"Solution architects, functional leads, and technical leads are mandatory.","pos":[7259,7332]},{"pos":[7338,7352],"content":"Build workshop","linkify":"Build workshop","nodes":[{"content":"Build workshop","pos":[0,14]}]},{"content":"The Build workshop is designed to review the development approach, build progress, quality, risks, and blockers.","pos":[7354,7466]},{"content":"Topics are likely to include:","pos":[7467,7496]},{"content":"Progress on development","pos":[7502,7525]},{"content":"Progress on system configuration","pos":[7530,7562]},{"content":"Integration","pos":[7567,7578]},{"content":"Reporting/BI status","pos":[7583,7602]},{"content":"Test results","pos":[7607,7619]},{"content":"Bug stats","pos":[7624,7633]},{"content":"Performance results","pos":[7638,7657]},{"content":"Development risks and mitigations","pos":[7662,7695]},{"content":"The typical format is a 1.5-hour Skype call.","pos":[7697,7741]},{"content":"The recommended attendees include key stakeholders from customer and partner teams.","pos":[7742,7825]},{"content":"Solution architects and technical leads are mandatory.","pos":[7826,7880]},{"pos":[7886,7916],"content":"Pre go-live readiness workshop","linkify":"Pre go-live readiness workshop","nodes":[{"content":"Pre go-live readiness workshop","pos":[0,30]}]},{"content":"The Pre go-live readiness workshop is designed to ensure that there are no last-minute blockers during cutover and go-live.","pos":[7918,8041]},{"content":"Topics are likely to include:","pos":[8042,8071]},{"content":"Go-live scope confirmation","pos":[8077,8103]},{"content":"Bug and build status","pos":[8108,8128]},{"content":"Blocking issue review","pos":[8133,8154]},{"content":"User training and organization change management status","pos":[8159,8214]},{"content":"Cutover plan and final data migration","pos":[8219,8256]},{"content":"Hyper-care plan","pos":[8261,8276]},{"content":"Risk and mitigation review","pos":[8281,8307]},{"content":"Customer go/no-go criteria","pos":[8312,8338]},{"content":"Recap support process","pos":[8343,8364]},{"content":"The typical format is 1.5-hour Skype call.","pos":[8366,8408]},{"content":"The recommended attendees include key business users and subject matter experts.","pos":[8409,8489]},{"content":"Hyper-care team leads are mandatory.","pos":[8490,8526]},{"pos":[8532,8560],"content":"Post go-live review workshop","linkify":"Post go-live review workshop","nodes":[{"content":"Post go-live review workshop","pos":[0,28]}]},{"content":"The Post go-live review workshop is designed to wrap up the FastTrack engagement.","pos":[8562,8643]},{"content":"Topics are likely to include:","pos":[8644,8673]},{"content":"Review goals and objectives","pos":[8679,8706]},{"content":"Discuss lessons learned","pos":[8711,8734]},{"content":"Review aged Support items","pos":[8739,8764]},{"content":"Hand over open issues to Support teams","pos":[8769,8807]},{"content":"Support overview content","pos":[8812,8836]},{"content":"Pro-Direct Support overview (if applicable)","pos":[8841,8884]},{"content":"The typical format is a 1.5-hour Skype call.","pos":[8886,8930]},{"content":"The recommended attendees include key stakeholders from customer, partner, and Microsoft teams.","pos":[8931,9026]},{"content":"Project managers are mandatory.","pos":[9027,9058]},{"pos":[9063,9073],"content":"Tech talks","linkify":"Tech talks","nodes":[{"content":"Tech talks","pos":[0,10]}]},{"content":"Tech talks focus on providing technical depth and best practices that empower both customers and partners with knowledge that is specific to the subject areas.","pos":[9074,9233]},{"content":"These talks often provide an overview of available tooling and content.","pos":[9234,9305]},{"pos":[9307,9483],"content":"Some of the tech talks are recorded, and the recordings are available on the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Dynamics 365 YouTube channel<ept id=\"p1\">](https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCJGCg4rB3QSs8y_1FquelBQ)</ept>.","source":"Some of the tech talks are recorded, and the recordings are available on the [Microsoft Dynamics 365 YouTube channel](https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCJGCg4rB3QSs8y_1FquelBQ)."},{"pos":[9489,9529],"content":"Lifecycle Services (LCS) usage tech talk","linkify":"Lifecycle Services (LCS) usage tech talk","nodes":[{"content":"Lifecycle Services (LCS) usage tech talk","pos":[0,40]}]},{"content":"The Lifecycle Services usage tech talk is designed to introduce customers to LCS.","pos":[9531,9612]},{"content":"Key topics might include:","pos":[9613,9638]},{"content":"Introduction to LCS","pos":[9644,9663]},{"content":"LCS scope, schedule, and adoption targets","pos":[9668,9709]},{"content":"Customer, partner, and Microsoft team usage scenarios","pos":[9714,9767]},{"content":"Common usage and related best practices","pos":[9772,9811]},{"content":"How to stay on top of new features/services available","pos":[9816,9869]},{"content":"Further learning opportunities","pos":[9874,9904]},{"content":"The typical format is a one-hour Skype call.","pos":[9906,9950]},{"content":"The recommended attendees include key stakeholders from the customer, partner, and Microsoft teams.","pos":[9951,10050]},{"pos":[10056,10107],"content":"Tenant/Visual Studio online configuration tech talk","linkify":"Tenant/Visual Studio online configuration tech talk","nodes":[{"content":"Tenant/Visual Studio online configuration tech talk","pos":[0,51]}]},{"content":"The Tenant/Visual Studio Online configuration tech talk is designed to provide guidance on how to configure tenant and Visual Studio Online.","pos":[10109,10249]},{"content":"Key topics might include:","pos":[10250,10275]},{"content":"Connect from LCS","pos":[10281,10297]},{"content":"Best practices in configuration","pos":[10302,10333]},{"content":"Common pitfalls","pos":[10338,10353]},{"content":"Continued learning","pos":[10358,10376]},{"content":"The typical format is a one-hour Skype call.","pos":[10378,10422]},{"content":"The recommended attendees include technical resources from customer and partner teams.","pos":[10423,10509]},{"pos":[10515,10541],"content":"Environment plan tech talk","linkify":"Environment plan tech talk","nodes":[{"content":"Environment plan tech talk","pos":[0,26]}]},{"content":"The Environment plan tech talk is designed to provide guidance on how to plan and use environments.","pos":[10543,10642]},{"content":"Key topics might include:","pos":[10643,10668]},{"content":"Environment planning","pos":[10674,10694]},{"content":"Optimal utilization of the default environments in the standard offer","pos":[10699,10768]},{"content":"How to purchase add-ons","pos":[10773,10796]},{"content":"ISV approach","pos":[10801,10813]},{"content":"Performance testing","pos":[10818,10837]},{"content":"Configuration management","pos":[10842,10866]},{"content":"The typical format is a one-hour Skype call.","pos":[10868,10912]},{"content":"The recommended attendees include technical resources from customer and partner teams.","pos":[10913,10999]},{"pos":[11005,11065],"content":"Development Application Lifecycle Management (ALM) tech talk","linkify":"Development Application Lifecycle Management (ALM) tech talk","nodes":[{"content":"Development Application Lifecycle Management (ALM) tech talk","pos":[0,60]}]},{"content":"The Development ALM tech talk is designed to provide guidance on ALM best practices.","pos":[11067,11151]},{"content":"Key topics might include:","pos":[11152,11177]},{"content":"Packaging and release management","pos":[11183,11215]},{"content":"Build orchestration – builds and build VMs","pos":[11220,11262]},{"content":"Source control","pos":[11267,11281]},{"content":"Branching","pos":[11286,11295]},{"content":"Developer VMs","pos":[11300,11313]},{"content":"Automated testing","pos":[11318,11335]},{"content":"The typical format is a one-hour Skype call.","pos":[11337,11381]},{"content":"The recommended attendees include technical resources from customer and partner teams.","pos":[11382,11468]},{"pos":[11474,11506],"content":"Integration guidelines tech talk","linkify":"Integration guidelines tech talk","nodes":[{"content":"Integration guidelines tech talk","pos":[0,32]}]},{"content":"The Integration guidelines tech talk is designed to provide guidance on key integration topics throughout implementation.","pos":[11508,11629]},{"content":"Key topics might include:","pos":[11630,11655]},{"content":"Integration approaches for the cloud","pos":[11661,11697]},{"content":"Recurring integrations","pos":[11702,11724]},{"content":"File-based integrations","pos":[11729,11752]},{"content":"Role of data entities in integrations","pos":[11757,11794]},{"content":"Integration platform choices","pos":[11799,11827]},{"content":"The typical format is a one-hour Skype call.","pos":[11829,11873]},{"content":"The recommended attendees include technical resources from customer and partner teams.","pos":[11874,11960]},{"pos":[11966,12025],"content":"Reporting and Business Intelligence (BI) guidance tech talk","linkify":"Reporting and Business Intelligence (BI) guidance tech talk","nodes":[{"content":"Reporting and Business Intelligence (BI) guidance tech talk","pos":[0,59]}]},{"content":"The Reporting and BI guidance tech talk is designed to provide guidance on leveraging key analytics capabilities of Finance and Operations.","pos":[12027,12166]},{"content":"Key topics might include:","pos":[12167,12192]},{"content":"Entity store","pos":[12198,12210]},{"content":"Power BI","pos":[12215,12223]},{"content":"Configuration","pos":[12228,12241]},{"content":"Content packs – building and consuming","pos":[12246,12284]},{"content":"Common pitfalls","pos":[12289,12304]},{"content":"Continued learning","pos":[12309,12327]},{"content":"The typical format is a one-hour Skype call.","pos":[12329,12373]},{"content":"The recommended attendees include technical resources from the customer and partner teams.","pos":[12374,12464]},{"pos":[12470,12495],"content":"Data management tech talk","linkify":"Data management tech talk","nodes":[{"content":"Data management tech talk","pos":[0,25]}]},{"content":"The Data management tech talk is designed to provide guidance on how to migrate and/or manage data entities and packages.","pos":[12497,12618]},{"content":"Key topics might include:","pos":[12619,12644]},{"content":"Data entities","pos":[12650,12663]},{"content":"Data packages","pos":[12668,12681]},{"content":"Process data packages","pos":[12686,12707]},{"content":"Configuration management using data packages","pos":[12712,12756]},{"content":"Data migration","pos":[12761,12775]},{"content":"ETL approach and tool (DIXF)","pos":[12780,12808]},{"content":"Masters","pos":[12813,12820]},{"content":"Transactions","pos":[12825,12837]},{"content":"Delta processing","pos":[12842,12858]},{"content":"The typical format is a 1.5-hour Skype call.","pos":[12860,12904]},{"content":"The recommended attendees include technical resources from customer and partner teams.","pos":[12905,12991]},{"pos":[12997,13026],"content":"Performance testing tech talk","linkify":"Performance testing tech talk","nodes":[{"content":"Performance testing tech talk","pos":[0,29]}]},{"content":"The Performance testing tech talk is designed to provide guidance on planning and executing performance testing.","pos":[13028,13140]},{"content":"Key topics might include:","pos":[13141,13166]},{"content":"Defining a performance test plan","pos":[13172,13204]},{"content":"Taking a trace with Trace Parser and analyzing it","pos":[13209,13258]},{"content":"Taking a trace and using it for data expansion","pos":[13263,13309]},{"content":"Introduction to the Performance SDK and multiuser testing with Visual Studio Online","pos":[13314,13397]},{"content":"Performance timer (optional)","pos":[13402,13430]},{"content":"Further learning opportunities","pos":[13435,13465]},{"content":"The typical format is a one-hour Skype call.","pos":[13467,13511]},{"content":"The recommended attendees include technical resources from customer and partner teams.","pos":[13512,13598]},{"pos":[13604,13623],"content":"Servicing tech talk","linkify":"Servicing tech talk","nodes":[{"content":"Servicing tech talk","pos":[0,19]}]},{"content":"The Servicing tech talk is designed to provide guidance on the servicing options available to customers.","pos":[13625,13729]},{"content":"Key topics might include:","pos":[13730,13755]},{"content":"Overview of the servicing story","pos":[13761,13792]},{"content":"DSE team","pos":[13797,13805]},{"content":"Deploying hotfixes","pos":[13810,13828]},{"content":"Submitting a service request","pos":[13833,13861]},{"content":"Cloud powered support","pos":[13866,13887]},{"content":"The typical format is a one-hour Skype call.","pos":[13889,13933]},{"content":"The recommended attendees include project managers and technical resources from customer and partner teams.","pos":[13934,14041]}]}