{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Migrate from AX 2012 to Finance and Operations \ndescription: This article provides an overview of the product and warehouse management migration options within Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition July 2017 update.\nauthor: BibiSp\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 04/04/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form:  InventLocationWHSProcessEnablement, WHSLocationProfile, InventTableStorageDimensionGroupChange, InventUpdateBlockedItem, WHSParameters, WHSReservationHierarchy, WHSUOMSeqGroupTable\n# ROBOTS: \n# audience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: bis\n# ms.search.scope: AX 7.0.0, Operations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 1714054\nms.assetid: 79a1a3b9-3a36-4162-8839-ec39b5e26602\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.industry: \nms.author: perlynne\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n---\n\n# Migrate from AX 2012 to Finance and Operations\n\nThis topic provides an overview of the product and warehouse management migration options within Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition July 2017 update.\n\nIntroduction\n------------\n\nDuring an upgrade to Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition July 2017 update, products are blocked if they are associated with a storage dimension group that has settings that don't match the requirements for storage dimension group settings in Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition July 2017 update. However, after the upgrade, you can use a set of migration options in the **Change storage dimension group for items** process to unblock products that were blocked during upgrade. You can then process transactions for those products. Some of your items might already be associated with storage dimension groups where the Site, Warehouse, and Location inventory dimensions are active and physically tracked. In this case, you can use the **Change storage dimension group for items** process to enable those items to be used in warehouse management processes. This feature is useful if you want to use the warehouse management functionality for existing items.\n\n## Upgrading to Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition July 2017 update, when AX 2012 R3 WMSII is used\nDynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition July 2017 update, no longer supports the legacy **WMSII** module from Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012. Instead, you can use the new **Warehouse management** module. For more information, see [Warehouse management home page](https://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/warehouse-management/). In previous versions, the Location and Pallet ID inventory dimensions could be selected for financial inventory. However, as part of the upgrade process, the Pallet ID inventory dimension can no longer be enabled for financial inventory. All products that are associated with a storage dimension group that uses the Pallet ID inventory dimension will be blocked and won't be processed.\n\n### Enabling items in Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition July 2017 update\n\nIn Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition July 2017 update, items that will be used as part of warehouse management processes must be associated with a storage dimension group where the **Use warehouse management processes** parameter is selected. When this setting is selected, the Site, Warehouse, Inventory status, Location, and License plate inventory dimensions become active. You can change to this type of storage dimension group only for items that are already associated with storage dimension groups where the Location inventory dimension is active.\n\n### Items that are blocked for inventory updates\n\nTo view the list of released products that were blocked during upgrade and can't be processed, click **Inventory management** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Inventory** &gt; **Items blocked for inventory updates**.\n\n### Reapplying blocked products\n\nTo unblock products that were blocked during upgrade, you must select a new storage dimension group for the products. Note that you can change the storage dimension group even if open inventory transactions exist. To use items that were blocked during upgrade, you have two options:\n\n-   Change the storage dimension group for the item to a storage dimension group that uses only the Site, Warehouse, and Location inventory dimensions. As a result of this change, the Pallet ID inventory dimension is no longer used.\n-   Change the storage dimension group for the item to a storage dimension group that uses the warehouse management processes. As a result of this change, the License plate inventory dimension is now used.\n\n### Migration processes\n\nIn Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition July 2017 update, item tracking is part of the warehouse management processes. For these processes, all warehouses and their locations must be associated with a location profile. Conceptually, if you want to use warehouse management processes, two processes must be handled:\n\n-   Existing warehouses must be enabled to use warehouse management processes.\n-   Existing released products must be associated with a new storage dimension group that uses warehouse management processes.\n\nIf the source storage dimension groups use the Pallet ID inventory dimension, the locations of existing on-hand inventory that used the Pallet ID inventory dimension must be associated with a location profile where the **Use license plate tracking** parameter is selected. If the existing warehouses should not be enabled to use warehouse management processes, you can change the storage dimension groups of the existing on-hand inventory to groups that handle only the Site, Warehouse, and Location inventory dimensions.\n\n### Using the warehouse management processes\n\nBefore you can use released products in the **Warehouse management** module, the products must use a storage dimension group where the **Use warehouse management processes** parameter is selected.\n\n#### Enable warehouses to use warehouse management processes\n\n1.  Create at least one new location profile.\n2.  Click **Warehouse management** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Enable warehouse management processes** &gt; **Enable warehouse setup**.\n3.  On the **Enable warehouse setup** page, add the warehouses that should be enabled. You can complete this step either directly on the page or by using the Microsoft Office integration.\n4.  Assign a location profile to all the locations. You can easily complete this step by using the Microsoft Office integration directly from the page. You can either export and import the data, or use the data entity processing in [Data management](https://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/data-management-and-integration-through-data-entity/).\n5.  Validate the changes. As part of the validation process, various validations of data integrity occur. As part of a larger upgrade process, issues that occur might have to be adjusted on the source implementation. In this case, an additional data upgrade will be required.\n6.  Process the changes.\n\n#### Change the storage dimension group for items, so that it uses warehouse management processes\n\n1.  Create a new **Inventory status** value, and assign it as the **Default inventory status ID** value in the **Warehouse management parameters** settings.\n2.  Create a new storage dimension group where the **Use warehouse management processes** parameter is selected.\n3.  On the **Reservation hierarchy** page, define a new reservation hierarchy according to the item’s storage and tracking dimension groups.\n4.  Create one or more unit sequence groups that include at least the same units that are used for the items' inventory units.\n5.  Click **Warehouse management** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Enable warehouse management processes** &gt; **Change storage dimension group for items**.\n6.  On the **Change storage dimension group for items** page, add the item numbers, storage dimension groups, and unit sequence groups. You can complete this step directly on the page, by using the Microsoft Office integration, or by using the data entity process in [Data management](https://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/data-management-and-integration-through-data-entity/).\n7.  Validate the changes. As part of the validation process, various validations of data integrity occur. As part of a larger upgrade process, issues that occur might have to be adjusted on the source implementation. In this case, additional data upgrade will be required.\n8.  Process the changes. An update of all the inventory dimensions can take a while. You can monitor the progress by using the batch jobs tasks.\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[32,78],"content":"Migrate from AX 2012 to Finance and Operations","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Migrate from AX 2012 to Finance and Operations","pos":[0,46]}]},{"pos":[93,269],"content":"This article provides an overview of the product and warehouse management migration options within Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition July 2017 update.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"This article provides an overview of the product and warehouse management migration options within Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition July 2017 update.","pos":[0,176]}]},{"pos":[950,996],"content":"Migrate from AX 2012 to Finance and Operations","linkify":"Migrate from AX 2012 to Finance and Operations","nodes":[{"content":"Migrate from AX 2012 to Finance and Operations","pos":[0,46]}]},{"content":"This topic provides an overview of the product and warehouse management migration options within Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition July 2017 update.","pos":[998,1172]},{"pos":[1174,1186],"content":"Introduction","linkify":"Introduction","nodes":[{"content":"Introduction","pos":[0,12]}]},{"content":"During an upgrade to Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition July 2017 update, products are blocked if they are associated with a storage dimension group that has settings that don't match the requirements for storage dimension group settings in Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition July 2017 update.","pos":[1201,1554]},{"content":"However, after the upgrade, you can use a set of migration options in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Change storage dimension group for items<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> process to unblock products that were blocked during upgrade.","pos":[1555,1735],"source":" However, after the upgrade, you can use a set of migration options in the **Change storage dimension group for items** process to unblock products that were blocked during upgrade."},{"content":"You can then process transactions for those products.","pos":[1736,1789]},{"content":"Some of your items might already be associated with storage dimension groups where the Site, Warehouse, and Location inventory dimensions are active and physically tracked.","pos":[1790,1962]},{"content":"In this case, you can use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Change storage dimension group for items<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> process to enable those items to be used in warehouse management processes.","pos":[1963,2113],"source":" In this case, you can use the **Change storage dimension group for items** process to enable those items to be used in warehouse management processes."},{"content":"This feature is useful if you want to use the warehouse management functionality for existing items.","pos":[2114,2214]},{"pos":[2219,2339],"content":"Upgrading to Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition July 2017 update, when AX 2012 R3 WMSII is used","linkify":"Upgrading to Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition July 2017 update, when AX 2012 R3 WMSII is used","nodes":[{"content":"Upgrading to Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition July 2017 update, when AX 2012 R3 WMSII is used","pos":[0,120]}]},{"content":"Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition July 2017 update, no longer supports the legacy <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>WMSII<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> module from Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012.","pos":[2340,2497],"source":"Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition July 2017 update, no longer supports the legacy **WMSII** module from Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012."},{"content":"Instead, you can use the new <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Warehouse management<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> module.","pos":[2498,2559],"source":" Instead, you can use the new **Warehouse management** module."},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Warehouse management home page<ept id=\"p1\">](https://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/warehouse-management/)</ept>.","pos":[2560,2679],"source":" For more information, see [Warehouse management home page](https://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/warehouse-management/)."},{"content":"In previous versions, the Location and Pallet ID inventory dimensions could be selected for financial inventory.","pos":[2680,2792]},{"content":"However, as part of the upgrade process, the Pallet ID inventory dimension can no longer be enabled for financial inventory.","pos":[2793,2917]},{"content":"All products that are associated with a storage dimension group that uses the Pallet ID inventory dimension will be blocked and won't be processed.","pos":[2918,3065]},{"pos":[3071,3165],"content":"Enabling items in Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition July 2017 update","linkify":"Enabling items in Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition July 2017 update","nodes":[{"content":"Enabling items in Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition July 2017 update","pos":[0,94]}]},{"content":"In Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition July 2017 update, items that will be used as part of warehouse management processes must be associated with a storage dimension group where the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Use warehouse management processes<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> parameter is selected.","pos":[3167,3435],"source":"In Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition July 2017 update, items that will be used as part of warehouse management processes must be associated with a storage dimension group where the **Use warehouse management processes** parameter is selected."},{"content":"When this setting is selected, the Site, Warehouse, Inventory status, Location, and License plate inventory dimensions become active.","pos":[3436,3569]},{"content":"You can change to this type of storage dimension group only for items that are already associated with storage dimension groups where the Location inventory dimension is active.","pos":[3570,3747]},{"pos":[3753,3797],"content":"Items that are blocked for inventory updates","linkify":"Items that are blocked for inventory updates","nodes":[{"content":"Items that are blocked for inventory updates","pos":[0,44]}]},{"pos":[3799,4004],"content":"To view the list of released products that were blocked during upgrade and can't be processed, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Inventory management<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Setup<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Inventory<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph3\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Items blocked for inventory updates<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>.","source":"To view the list of released products that were blocked during upgrade and can't be processed, click **Inventory management** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Inventory** &gt; **Items blocked for inventory updates**."},{"pos":[4010,4037],"content":"Reapplying blocked products","linkify":"Reapplying blocked products","nodes":[{"content":"Reapplying blocked products","pos":[0,27]}]},{"content":"To unblock products that were blocked during upgrade, you must select a new storage dimension group for the products.","pos":[4039,4156]},{"content":"Note that you can change the storage dimension group even if open inventory transactions exist.","pos":[4157,4252]},{"content":"To use items that were blocked during upgrade, you have two options:","pos":[4253,4321]},{"content":"Change the storage dimension group for the item to a storage dimension group that uses only the Site, Warehouse, and Location inventory dimensions.","pos":[4327,4474]},{"content":"As a result of this change, the Pallet ID inventory dimension is no longer used.","pos":[4475,4555]},{"content":"Change the storage dimension group for the item to a storage dimension group that uses the warehouse management processes.","pos":[4560,4682]},{"content":"As a result of this change, the License plate inventory dimension is now used.","pos":[4683,4761]},{"pos":[4767,4786],"content":"Migration processes","linkify":"Migration processes","nodes":[{"content":"Migration processes","pos":[0,19]}]},{"content":"In Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition July 2017 update, item tracking is part of the warehouse management processes.","pos":[4788,4929]},{"content":"For these processes, all warehouses and their locations must be associated with a location profile.","pos":[4930,5029]},{"content":"Conceptually, if you want to use warehouse management processes, two processes must be handled:","pos":[5030,5125]},{"content":"Existing warehouses must be enabled to use warehouse management processes.","pos":[5131,5205]},{"content":"Existing released products must be associated with a new storage dimension group that uses warehouse management processes.","pos":[5210,5332]},{"content":"If the source storage dimension groups use the Pallet ID inventory dimension, the locations of existing on-hand inventory that used the Pallet ID inventory dimension must be associated with a location profile where the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Use license plate tracking<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> parameter is selected.","pos":[5334,5606],"source":"If the source storage dimension groups use the Pallet ID inventory dimension, the locations of existing on-hand inventory that used the Pallet ID inventory dimension must be associated with a location profile where the **Use license plate tracking** parameter is selected."},{"content":"If the existing warehouses should not be enabled to use warehouse management processes, you can change the storage dimension groups of the existing on-hand inventory to groups that handle only the Site, Warehouse, and Location inventory dimensions.","pos":[5607,5855]},{"pos":[5861,5901],"content":"Using the warehouse management processes","linkify":"Using the warehouse management processes","nodes":[{"content":"Using the warehouse management processes","pos":[0,40]}]},{"pos":[5903,6099],"content":"Before you can use released products in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Warehouse management<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> module, the products must use a storage dimension group where the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Use warehouse management processes<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> parameter is selected.","source":"Before you can use released products in the **Warehouse management** module, the products must use a storage dimension group where the **Use warehouse management processes** parameter is selected."},{"pos":[6106,6161],"content":"Enable warehouses to use warehouse management processes","linkify":"Enable warehouses to use warehouse management processes","nodes":[{"content":"Enable warehouses to use warehouse management processes","pos":[0,55]}]},{"content":"Create at least one new location profile.","pos":[6167,6208]},{"pos":[6213,6338],"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Warehouse management<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Setup<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Enable warehouse management processes<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph3\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Enable warehouse setup<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>.","source":"Click **Warehouse management** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Enable warehouse management processes** &gt; **Enable warehouse setup**."},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Enable warehouse setup<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, add the warehouses that should be enabled.","pos":[6343,6425],"source":"On the **Enable warehouse setup** page, add the warehouses that should be enabled."},{"content":"You can complete this step either directly on the page or by using the Microsoft Office integration.","pos":[6426,6526]},{"content":"Assign a location profile to all the locations.","pos":[6531,6578]},{"content":"You can easily complete this step by using the Microsoft Office integration directly from the page.","pos":[6579,6678]},{"content":"You can either export and import the data, or use the data entity processing in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Data management<ept id=\"p1\">](https://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/data-management-and-integration-through-data-entity/)</ept>.","pos":[6679,6868],"source":" You can either export and import the data, or use the data entity processing in [Data management](https://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/data-management-and-integration-through-data-entity/)."},{"content":"Validate the changes.","pos":[6873,6894]},{"content":"As part of the validation process, various validations of data integrity occur.","pos":[6895,6974]},{"content":"As part of a larger upgrade process, issues that occur might have to be adjusted on the source implementation.","pos":[6975,7085]},{"content":"In this case, an additional data upgrade will be required.","pos":[7086,7144]},{"content":"Process the changes.","pos":[7149,7169]},{"pos":[7176,7268],"content":"Change the storage dimension group for items, so that it uses warehouse management processes","linkify":"Change the storage dimension group for items, so that it uses warehouse management processes","nodes":[{"content":"Change the storage dimension group for items, so that it uses warehouse management processes","pos":[0,92]}]},{"pos":[7274,7426],"content":"Create a new <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Inventory status<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> value, and assign it as the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Default inventory status ID<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> value in the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Warehouse management parameters<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> settings.","source":"Create a new **Inventory status** value, and assign it as the **Default inventory status ID** value in the **Warehouse management parameters** settings."},{"pos":[7431,7539],"content":"Create a new storage dimension group where the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Use warehouse management processes<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> parameter is selected.","source":"Create a new storage dimension group where the **Use warehouse management processes** parameter is selected."},{"pos":[7544,7680],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Reservation hierarchy<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, define a new reservation hierarchy according to the item’s storage and tracking dimension groups.","source":"On the **Reservation hierarchy** page, define a new reservation hierarchy according to the item’s storage and tracking dimension groups."},{"content":"Create one or more unit sequence groups that include at least the same units that are used for the items' inventory units.","pos":[7685,7807]},{"pos":[7812,7955],"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Warehouse management<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Setup<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Enable warehouse management processes<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph3\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Change storage dimension group for items<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>.","source":"Click **Warehouse management** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Enable warehouse management processes** &gt; **Change storage dimension group for items**."},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Change storage dimension group for items<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, add the item numbers, storage dimension groups, and unit sequence groups.","pos":[7960,8091],"source":"On the **Change storage dimension group for items** page, add the item numbers, storage dimension groups, and unit sequence groups."},{"content":"You can complete this step directly on the page, by using the Microsoft Office integration, or by using the data entity process in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Data management<ept id=\"p1\">](https://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/data-management-and-integration-through-data-entity/)</ept>.","pos":[8092,8332],"source":" You can complete this step directly on the page, by using the Microsoft Office integration, or by using the data entity process in [Data management](https://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/data-management-and-integration-through-data-entity/)."},{"content":"Validate the changes.","pos":[8337,8358]},{"content":"As part of the validation process, various validations of data integrity occur.","pos":[8359,8438]},{"content":"As part of a larger upgrade process, issues that occur might have to be adjusted on the source implementation.","pos":[8439,8549]},{"content":"In this case, additional data upgrade will be required.","pos":[8550,8605]},{"content":"Process the changes.","pos":[8610,8630]},{"content":"An update of all the inventory dimensions can take a while.","pos":[8631,8690]},{"content":"You can monitor the progress by using the batch jobs tasks.","pos":[8691,8750]}]}