{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Reconcile freight in transportation management\ndescription: This article describes the freight reconciliation process.\nauthor: YuyuScheller\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 04/04/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: TMSAuditMaster, TMSFreightBillInvoiceReconcile, TMSFreightBillSummary, TMSFreightBillType, TMSFreightMatchReason, TMSInvoiceTable\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \n# ms.reviewer: 2084\nms.search.scope: AX 7.0.0, Operations, Core\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 89983\nms.assetid: bc34a9b1-0c11-4797-b463-25409cf98ca8\nms.search.region: Global\nms.search.industry: Distribution\nms.author: yuyus\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Reconcile freight in transportation management\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThis article describes the freight reconciliation process.\n\nFreight reconciliation can be done manually, or it can be set up to occur automatically. To use automatic freight reconciliation, you must set up an audit master where you can define criteria that determine which freight bills are matched automatically.\n\n## The freight reconciliation process\nFreight rates are calculated by the rate engine that is associated with the relevant shipping carrier. When a load is confirmed, a freight bill is generated, and the freight rates are transferred to it. The freight rates are apportioned as miscellaneous charges to the relevant source document (purchase order, sales order, and/or transfer order), depending on the setup that is used for the regular billing process. The freight reconciliation process (which is also known as the matching process) can start as soon as the freight invoice arrives from the shipping carrier. The invoice can be received electronically or on paper. If the invoice is received on paper, you can generate an electronic invoice by using the freight bill as a template. \n\n[![Freight reconcilation process](./media/freight-reconcilation-process.jpg)](./media/freight-reconcilation-process.jpg)\n\n## Manual reconciliation\nIf you're reconciling freight manually, you must match each invoice line with the freight bill line or lines for the load that is being invoiced. You do this matching on the **Freight bill and invoice matching** page. If the amount on the invoice line doesn’t match the freight bill amount, you must select a reconciliation reason for the difference. If there are multiple reasons for reconciliation, you can split the unmatched amount across them. The reconciliation reason determines how the difference amounts are posted in the general ledger. When the reconciliation of the whole invoice amount is accounted for, it's submitted for approval, and then the journal is posted. The following illustration shows how to generate a freight invoice and do freight reconciliation in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations. \n[![Freight reconcilation tasks in Dynamics AX](./media/processflowforfreightreconciliation.jpg)](./media/processflowforfreightreconciliation.jpg)\n## Automatic reconciliation\nTo use automatic reconciliation, you must specify the schedule for reconciliation, and the invoices and shipping carriers to use. The matching of the invoice lines and freight bills is done according to the setup of the audit master and freight bill type. After you run the automatic reconciliation, you must handle any invoices that the system can't match. You must then process these invoices manually before you can post all the invoices for payment.\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[32,78],"content":"Reconcile freight in transportation management","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Reconcile freight in transportation management","pos":[0,46]}]},{"pos":[92,150],"content":"This article describes the freight reconciliation process.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"This article describes the freight reconciliation process.","pos":[0,58]}]},{"pos":[801,847],"content":"Reconcile freight in transportation management","linkify":"Reconcile freight in transportation management","nodes":[{"content":"Reconcile freight in transportation management","pos":[0,46]}]},{"content":"This article describes the freight reconciliation process.","pos":[893,951]},{"content":"Freight reconciliation can be done manually, or it can be set up to occur automatically.","pos":[953,1041]},{"content":"To use automatic freight reconciliation, you must set up an audit master where you can define criteria that determine which freight bills are matched automatically.","pos":[1042,1206]},{"pos":[1211,1245],"content":"The freight reconciliation process","linkify":"The freight reconciliation process","nodes":[{"content":"The freight reconciliation process","pos":[0,34]}]},{"content":"Freight rates are calculated by the rate engine that is associated with the relevant shipping carrier.","pos":[1246,1348]},{"content":"When a load is confirmed, a freight bill is generated, and the freight rates are transferred to it.","pos":[1349,1448]},{"content":"The freight rates are apportioned as miscellaneous charges to the relevant source document (purchase order, sales order, and/or transfer order), depending on the setup that is used for the regular billing process.","pos":[1449,1662]},{"content":"The freight reconciliation process (which is also known as the matching process) can start as soon as the freight invoice arrives from the shipping carrier.","pos":[1663,1819]},{"content":"The invoice can be received electronically or on paper.","pos":[1820,1875]},{"content":"If the invoice is received on paper, you can generate an electronic invoice by using the freight bill as a template.","pos":[1876,1992]},{"pos":[1995,2115],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Freight reconcilation process<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/freight-reconcilation-process.jpg)](./media/freight-reconcilation-process.jpg)</ept>","source":"[![Freight reconcilation process](./media/freight-reconcilation-process.jpg)](./media/freight-reconcilation-process.jpg)"},{"pos":[2120,2141],"content":"Manual reconciliation","linkify":"Manual reconciliation","nodes":[{"content":"Manual reconciliation","pos":[0,21]}]},{"content":"If you're reconciling freight manually, you must match each invoice line with the freight bill line or lines for the load that is being invoiced.","pos":[2142,2287]},{"content":"You do this matching on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Freight bill and invoice matching<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[2288,2359],"source":" You do this matching on the **Freight bill and invoice matching** page."},{"content":"If the amount on the invoice line doesn’t match the freight bill amount, you must select a reconciliation reason for the difference.","pos":[2360,2492]},{"content":"If there are multiple reasons for reconciliation, you can split the unmatched amount across them.","pos":[2493,2590]},{"content":"The reconciliation reason determines how the difference amounts are posted in the general ledger.","pos":[2591,2688]},{"content":"When the reconciliation of the whole invoice amount is accounted for, it's submitted for approval, and then the journal is posted.","pos":[2689,2819]},{"content":"The following illustration shows how to generate a freight invoice and do freight reconciliation in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations.","pos":[2820,2958]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Freight reconcilation tasks in Dynamics AX<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/processflowforfreightreconciliation.jpg)](./media/processflowforfreightreconciliation.jpg)</ept>","pos":[2960,3105],"source":"[![Freight reconcilation tasks in Dynamics AX](./media/processflowforfreightreconciliation.jpg)](./media/processflowforfreightreconciliation.jpg)"},{"pos":[3109,3133],"content":"Automatic reconciliation","linkify":"Automatic reconciliation","nodes":[{"content":"Automatic reconciliation","pos":[0,24]}]},{"content":"To use automatic reconciliation, you must specify the schedule for reconciliation, and the invoices and shipping carriers to use.","pos":[3134,3263]},{"content":"The matching of the invoice lines and freight bills is done according to the setup of the audit master and freight bill type.","pos":[3264,3389]},{"content":"After you run the automatic reconciliation, you must handle any invoices that the system can't match.","pos":[3390,3491]},{"content":"You must then process these invoices manually before you can post all the invoices for payment.","pos":[3492,3587]}]}