{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,54],"content":"Hybrid customer orders","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Hybrid customer orders","pos":[0,22]}]},{"pos":[68,249],"content":"A hybrid customer order is a single order, which contains products that can be carried out of the store by the customer, as well as products that will be picked up or shipped later.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"A hybrid customer order is a single order, which contains products that can be carried out of the store by the customer, as well as products that will be picked up or shipped later.","pos":[0,181]}]},{"pos":[760,782],"content":"Hybrid customer orders","linkify":"Hybrid customer orders","nodes":[{"content":"Hybrid customer orders","pos":[0,22]}]},{"content":"A hybrid customer order is a single order, which contains products that can be carried out of the store by the customer, as well as products that will be picked up or shipped later.","pos":[784,965]},{"content":"In Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations - Retail, you can select either carry out all products or carry out selected products for a customer order.","pos":[967,1115]},{"content":"The product lines that are marked as carry out are automatically invoiced after the order is created, similarly this is the same for an order that is to be picked-up after the order is created.","pos":[1116,1309]},{"content":"The amount due on hybrid orders is determined by adding the deposit percentage on pick and ship product lines with the full amount of the carry out lines.","pos":[1310,1464]},{"content":"For hybrid orders, the system switches between customer order mode and cash and carry mode as follows:","pos":[1465,1567]},{"pos":[1573,1694],"content":"If all products in the cart are set to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Carry out delivery<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, the order will be handled as a Cash and Carry transaction.","source":"If all products in the cart are set to **Carry out delivery**, the order will be handled as a Cash and Carry transaction."},{"pos":[1699,1838],"content":"If any or all lines in the cart are set to either <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Pick<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>ship delivery<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, the order will be handled as a Customer order transaction.","source":"If any or all lines in the cart are set to either **Pick** or **ship delivery**, the order will be handled as a Customer order transaction."},{"content":"If a cart line is selected and <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Pick selected<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Ship selected<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, or <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Carry out selected<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> is selected, only the specific cart line is set with that delivery method.","pos":[1840,2009],"source":"If a cart line is selected and **Pick selected**, **Ship selected**, or **Carry out selected** is selected, only the specific cart line is set with that delivery method."},{"content":"In that case, the downstream flow of the operation continues as usual.","pos":[2010,2080]},{"content":"However, if <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Pick selected<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Ship selected<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, or <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Carry out selected<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> is selected without a cart line being selected, a new page opens that lists all the cart lines.","pos":[2081,2252],"source":" However, if **Pick selected**, **Ship selected**, or **Carry out selected** is selected without a cart line being selected, a new page opens that lists all the cart lines."},{"content":"On that screen, you can select multiple lines at once for setting the delivery method.","pos":[2253,2339]},{"content":"When you use that method for selecting lines, any previous delivery method that has been assigned to the line will be overridden.","pos":[2340,2469]},{"pos":[2471,2479],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[2490,2545],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Customer orders overview<ept id=\"p1\">](customer-orders-overview.md)</ept>","source":"[Customer orders overview](customer-orders-overview.md)"}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Hybrid customer orders\ndescription: A hybrid customer order is a single order, which contains products that can be carried out of the store by the customer, as well as products that will be picked up or shipped later.\nauthor: josaw1\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 2016-12-02 19 - 53 - 25\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \n# ms.reviewer: 41\nms.search.scope: Operations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 261164\nms.assetid: bbbc6ca7-8321-446d-8800-f2c2aae6cac1\nms.search.region: global\nms.search.industry: Retail\nms.author: anpurush\nms.dyn365.ops.intro: Nov-16\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 1611\n\n---\n\n# Hybrid customer orders\n\nA hybrid customer order is a single order, which contains products that can be carried out of the store by the customer, as well as products that will be picked up or shipped later.\n\nIn Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations - Retail, you can select either carry out all products or carry out selected products for a customer order. The product lines that are marked as carry out are automatically invoiced after the order is created, similarly this is the same for an order that is to be picked-up after the order is created. The amount due on hybrid orders is determined by adding the deposit percentage on pick and ship product lines with the full amount of the carry out lines. For hybrid orders, the system switches between customer order mode and cash and carry mode as follows:\n\n-   If all products in the cart are set to **Carry out delivery**, the order will be handled as a Cash and Carry transaction.\n-   If any or all lines in the cart are set to either **Pick** or **ship delivery**, the order will be handled as a Customer order transaction.\n\nIf a cart line is selected and **Pick selected**, **Ship selected**, or **Carry out selected** is selected, only the specific cart line is set with that delivery method. In that case, the downstream flow of the operation continues as usual. However, if **Pick selected**, **Ship selected**, or **Carry out selected** is selected without a cart line being selected, a new page opens that lists all the cart lines. On that screen, you can select multiple lines at once for setting the delivery method. When you use that method for selecting lines, any previous delivery method that has been assigned to the line will be overridden.\n\nSee also\n--------\n\n[Customer orders overview](customer-orders-overview.md)\n\n"}