{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Conditional sales tax for protested promissory notes or bills of exchange\ndescription: For legal entities in Spain, if a promissory note payment for a vendor or a bill of exchange payment for a customer is settled against an invoice that includes conditional tax, and you protest the settlement, the cancellation of conditional tax is registered with a voucher that is related to the settlement cancellation voucher.\nauthor: ShylaThompson\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 04/25/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: annbe\nms.search.scope: Operations, Core\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 271503\nms.assetid: 6b2a8a42-3c23-4e20-98aa-d3babfd893ab\nms.search.region: Spain\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: v-elgolu\nms.dyn365.ops.intro: Version 1611\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-11-30\n\n---\n\n# Conditional sales tax for protested promissory notes or bills of exchange\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nFor legal entities in Spain, if a promissory note payment for a vendor or a bill of exchange payment for a customer is settled against an invoice that includes conditional tax, and you protest the settlement, the cancellation of conditional tax is registered with a voucher that is related to the settlement cancellation voucher.\n\n*Conditional sales tax* is sales tax that is paid proportionally to the actual amount that is paid on an invoice. For more information about conditional tax, see [Sales tax overview](../general-ledger/indirect-taxes-overview.md). A *promissory note* is a written agreement in which the maker of the note promises to pay a specific amount at a specific time. A *bill of exchange* is a written or electronic order from a customer that specifies that another party (usually a bank) should pay a stated amount to the company. For more information about bills of exchange, see [Set up bills of exchange](../accounts-receivable/set-up-bills-exchange.md).\n\n## Conditional sales tax for protested promissory notes\nWhen a user posts a Redraw promissory note journal, transactions that were previously posted are reversed if a promissory note was settled against a vendor invoice. If the invoice included conditional tax when it was settled against a promissory note, a tax transaction for the conditional tax is posted. For legal entities in Spain, if the promissory note was settled against an invoice that includes conditional tax, the tax transaction is reversed when a Redraw promissory note journal is posted. To view reverse transactions, go to **Voucher transactions** &gt; **Related vouchers**.\n\n## Conditional sales tax for protested bills of exchange\nWhen a user posts a Protest bill of exchange journal, transactions that were previously posted are reversed if a bill of exchange was settled against a customer invoice. If the invoice included conditional tax when it was settled against a bill of exchange, a tax transaction for the conditional tax is posted. For legal entities in Spain, if the bill of exchange was settled against an invoice that includes conditional tax, the tax transaction is reversed when a Protest bill of exchange journal is posted. To view reverse transactions, go to **Voucher transactions** &gt; **Related vouchers**.\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[32,105],"content":"Conditional sales tax for protested promissory notes or bills of exchange","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Conditional sales tax for protested promissory notes or bills of exchange","pos":[0,73]}]},{"pos":[119,448],"content":"For legal entities in Spain, if a promissory note payment for a vendor or a bill of exchange payment for a customer is settled against an invoice that includes conditional tax, and you protest the settlement, the cancellation of conditional tax is registered with a voucher that is related to the settlement cancellation voucher.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"For legal entities in Spain, if a promissory note payment for a vendor or a bill of exchange payment for a customer is settled against an invoice that includes conditional tax, and you protest the settlement, the cancellation of conditional tax is registered with a voucher that is related to the settlement cancellation voucher.","pos":[0,329]}]},{"pos":[957,1030],"content":"Conditional sales tax for protested promissory notes or bills of exchange","linkify":"Conditional sales tax for protested promissory notes or bills of exchange","nodes":[{"content":"Conditional sales tax for protested promissory notes or bills of exchange","pos":[0,73]}]},{"content":"For legal entities in Spain, if a promissory note payment for a vendor or a bill of exchange payment for a customer is settled against an invoice that includes conditional tax, and you protest the settlement, the cancellation of conditional tax is registered with a voucher that is related to the settlement cancellation voucher.","pos":[1075,1404]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Conditional sales tax<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> is sales tax that is paid proportionally to the actual amount that is paid on an invoice.","pos":[1406,1519],"source":"*Conditional sales tax* is sales tax that is paid proportionally to the actual amount that is paid on an invoice."},{"content":"For more information about conditional tax, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Sales tax overview<ept id=\"p1\">](../general-ledger/indirect-taxes-overview.md)</ept>.","pos":[1520,1635],"source":" For more information about conditional tax, see [Sales tax overview](../general-ledger/indirect-taxes-overview.md)."},{"content":"A <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>promissory note<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> is a written agreement in which the maker of the note promises to pay a specific amount at a specific time.","pos":[1636,1763],"source":" A *promissory note* is a written agreement in which the maker of the note promises to pay a specific amount at a specific time."},{"content":"A <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>bill of exchange<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> is a written or electronic order from a customer that specifies that another party (usually a bank) should pay a stated amount to the company.","pos":[1764,1927],"source":" A *bill of exchange* is a written or electronic order from a customer that specifies that another party (usually a bank) should pay a stated amount to the company."},{"content":"For more information about bills of exchange, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Set up bills of exchange<ept id=\"p1\">](../accounts-receivable/set-up-bills-exchange.md)</ept>.","pos":[1928,2054],"source":" For more information about bills of exchange, see [Set up bills of exchange](../accounts-receivable/set-up-bills-exchange.md)."},{"pos":[2059,2111],"content":"Conditional sales tax for protested promissory notes","linkify":"Conditional sales tax for protested promissory notes","nodes":[{"content":"Conditional sales tax for protested promissory notes","pos":[0,52]}]},{"content":"When a user posts a Redraw promissory note journal, transactions that were previously posted are reversed if a promissory note was settled against a vendor invoice.","pos":[2112,2276]},{"content":"If the invoice included conditional tax when it was settled against a promissory note, a tax transaction for the conditional tax is posted.","pos":[2277,2416]},{"content":"For legal entities in Spain, if the promissory note was settled against an invoice that includes conditional tax, the tax transaction is reversed when a Redraw promissory note journal is posted.","pos":[2417,2611]},{"content":"To view reverse transactions, go to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Voucher transactions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Related vouchers<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[2612,2699],"source":" To view reverse transactions, go to **Voucher transactions** &gt; **Related vouchers**."},{"pos":[2704,2757],"content":"Conditional sales tax for protested bills of exchange","linkify":"Conditional sales tax for protested bills of exchange","nodes":[{"content":"Conditional sales tax for protested bills of exchange","pos":[0,53]}]},{"content":"When a user posts a Protest bill of exchange journal, transactions that were previously posted are reversed if a bill of exchange was settled against a customer invoice.","pos":[2758,2927]},{"content":"If the invoice included conditional tax when it was settled against a bill of exchange, a tax transaction for the conditional tax is posted.","pos":[2928,3068]},{"content":"For legal entities in Spain, if the bill of exchange was settled against an invoice that includes conditional tax, the tax transaction is reversed when a Protest bill of exchange journal is posted.","pos":[3069,3266]},{"content":"To view reverse transactions, go to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Voucher transactions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Related vouchers<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[3267,3354],"source":" To view reverse transactions, go to **Voucher transactions** &gt; **Related vouchers**."}]}