{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,73],"content":"Workflow system overview | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Workflow system overview | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,41]}]},{"pos":[87,171],"content":"This article describes the workflow system in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"This article describes the workflow system in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations.","pos":[0,84]}]},{"pos":[607,631],"content":"Workflow system overview","linkify":"Workflow system overview","nodes":[{"content":"Workflow system overview","pos":[0,24]}]},{"content":"This article describes the workflow system in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations.","pos":[633,717]},{"pos":[719,736],"content":"What is workflow?","linkify":"What is workflow?","nodes":[{"content":"What is workflow?","pos":[0,17]}]},{"pos":[756,842],"content":"The term <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>workflow<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> can be defined in two ways: as a system and as a business process.","source":"The term *workflow* can be defined in two ways: as a system and as a business process."},{"pos":[847,867],"content":"Workflow is a system","linkify":"Workflow is a system","nodes":[{"content":"Workflow is a system","pos":[0,20]}]},{"content":"Workflow is a system that is installed with Dynamics 365 for Operations and that runs on the Application Object Server (AOS).","pos":[869,994]},{"content":"The workflow system provides functionality that you can use to create individual workflows, or business processes.","pos":[995,1109]},{"pos":[1115,1145],"content":"Workflow is a business process","linkify":"Workflow is a business process","nodes":[{"content":"Workflow is a business process","pos":[0,30]}]},{"content":"A workflow represents a business process.","pos":[1147,1188]},{"content":"It defines how a document flows, or moves, through the system by showing who must complete a task, make a decision, or approve a document.","pos":[1189,1327]},{"content":"For example, the following figure shows a workflow for expense reports.","pos":[1328,1399]},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Workflow with elements that are assigned to users<ph id=\"ph2\">](./media/workflow_user.gif)</ph> To better understand this workflow, suppose that Sam submits an expense report for USD 7,000.","pos":[1400,1573],"source":"![Workflow with elements that are assigned to users](./media/workflow_user.gif) To better understand this workflow, suppose that Sam submits an expense report for USD 7,000."},{"content":"In this scenario, Ivan must review the receipts that Sam routes to him.","pos":[1574,1645]},{"content":"Then Frank and Sue must approve the expense report.","pos":[1646,1697]},{"content":"Now suppose that Sam submits an expense report for USD 11,000.","pos":[1698,1760]},{"content":"In this scenario, Ivan must review the receipts, and Frank, Sue, and Ann must approve the expense report.","pos":[1761,1866]},{"content":"Benefits of using the workflow system","pos":[1867,1904],"source":"\nBenefits of using the workflow system"},{"content":"There are several benefits of using the workflow system in your organization:","pos":[1944,2021]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Consistent processes<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – You can define how specific documents, such as purchase requisitions and expense reports, are processed.","pos":[2026,2157],"source":"**Consistent processes** – You can define how specific documents, such as purchase requisitions and expense reports, are processed."},{"content":"By using the workflow system, you ensure that documents are processed and approved in a consistent and efficient manner.","pos":[2158,2278]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Process visibility<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – You can track the status, history, and performance metrics of workflow instances.","pos":[2283,2389],"source":"**Process visibility** – You can track the status, history, and performance metrics of workflow instances."},{"content":"This helps you determine whether changes should be made to the workflow to improve efficiency.","pos":[2390,2484]},{"pos":[2489,2629],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Centralized work list<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Users can view a centralized work list that displays the workflow tasks and approvals that are assigned to them.","source":"**Centralized work list** – Users can view a centralized work list that displays the workflow tasks and approvals that are assigned to them."}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Workflow system overview | Microsoft Docs\ndescription: This article describes the workflow system in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations.\nauthor: sericks007\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 2016-02-29 15:10:28\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# keywords: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: 71\nms.suite: Released- Dynamics AX 7.0.0\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 56381\nms.assetid: fe239aeb-1837-4afb-864b-6fa6351868d5\nms.region: Global\n# ms.industry: \nms.author: tjvass\n\n---\n\n# Workflow system overview\n\nThis article describes the workflow system in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Operations.\n\nWhat is workflow?\n-----------------\n\nThe term *workflow* can be defined in two ways: as a system and as a business process.\n### Workflow is a system\n\nWorkflow is a system that is installed with Dynamics 365 for Operations and that runs on the Application Object Server (AOS). The workflow system provides functionality that you can use to create individual workflows, or business processes.\n\n### Workflow is a business process\n\nA workflow represents a business process. It defines how a document flows, or moves, through the system by showing who must complete a task, make a decision, or approve a document. For example, the following figure shows a workflow for expense reports. ![Workflow with elements that are assigned to users](./media/workflow_user.gif) To better understand this workflow, suppose that Sam submits an expense report for USD 7,000. In this scenario, Ivan must review the receipts that Sam routes to him. Then Frank and Sue must approve the expense report. Now suppose that Sam submits an expense report for USD 11,000. In this scenario, Ivan must review the receipts, and Frank, Sue, and Ann must approve the expense report.\nBenefits of using the workflow system\n-------------------------------------\n\nThere are several benefits of using the workflow system in your organization:\n-   **Consistent processes** – You can define how specific documents, such as purchase requisitions and expense reports, are processed. By using the workflow system, you ensure that documents are processed and approved in a consistent and efficient manner.\n-   **Process visibility** – You can track the status, history, and performance metrics of workflow instances. This helps you determine whether changes should be made to the workflow to improve efficiency.\n-   **Centralized work list** – Users can view a centralized work list that displays the workflow tasks and approvals that are assigned to them.\n\n\n\n"}