{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Product number nomenclature\ndescription: This topic describes how you can set up a product number nomenclature to replace the fixed format, [Product master number - Configuration - Size - Color - Style], with a targeted format that includes the product master number, active product dimensions, and text delimiters of your choice. You can also build a nomenclature to identify configurations that are created by the constraint-based product configurator. These nomenclatures can contain attributes of your choice.\nauthor: YuyuScheller\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 04/04/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: EcoResNomenclature, EcoResProductDimensionGroup, EcoResProductVariantMaintainWorkspace, PCProductConfigurationModelDetails\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \n# ms.reviewer: 121\nms.search.scope: Operations, Core\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 220104\nms.assetid: 31c9efb4-b5f6-4af3-b884-8f1e128469bd\nms.search.region: global\nms.search.industry: Manufacturing\nms.author: yuyus\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-11-30\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 1611\n\n---\n\n# Product number nomenclature\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThis topic describes how you can set up a product number nomenclature to replace the fixed format, [Product master number - Configuration - Size - Color - Style], with a targeted format that includes the product master number, active product dimensions, and text delimiters of your choice. You can also build a nomenclature to identify configurations that are created by the constraint-based product configurator. These nomenclatures can contain attributes of your choice.\n\nThe new product variant number nomenclature lets you include segments in your product variant identifiers. These segments can include the product master number, product dimensions, number sequences, text constants, and attributes. This functionality lets you quickly find a specific product variant when you create a sales order or purchase order.\n\n## Nomenclature of predefined product variants\nProduct variants are generated for product masters according to one of three configuration technologies:\n\n-   Predefined variants\n-   Constraint-based\n-   Dimension-based\n\nEach product variant has a number, and the product variant identification nomenclature lets you select the segments that will be included in each product variant number. You can select the following segments on the **Product nomenclature** page.\n\n-   Product master number\n-   Number sequence value\n-   Text constant\n-   Product dimensions\n    -   Configuration\n    -   Color\n    -   Size\n    -   Style\n\nAfter a product variant identification nomenclature is defined, it can be associated with a product dimension group. Consequently, all product masters referencing this product dimension group will be assigned product variant numbers according to the nomenclature. It is also possible to assign a product variant identification nomenclature directly to a product master, in which case the product variants belonging to this master will be assigned product variant numbers according to the nomenclature.\n\n### Example\n\nA T-shirt (TS1234) is produced in 3 different sizes (S, M, L), 4 different colors (Red, Green, Blue, Yellow), and 2 styles (Polo, V) giving a total of 24 possible product variants. A product variant identification nomenclature is created with the following segments:\n\n1.  Product master number\n2.  Text constant: '-'\n3.  Color\n4.  Text constant: '-'\n5.  Size\n6.  Text constant: '-'\n7.  Style\n\nThe product variant number for the Red, Small, Polo will be: TS1234-Red-Small-Polo.\n\n## Nomenclature of constraintbased configurations\nFor constraint-based configurations, a dedicated nomenclature can be built for the configuration product dimension. You can select the following segments on the **Product nomenclature** page.\n\n-   Number sequence value\n-   Text constant\n-   Attribute value \n\nEach component in a product configuration model can have its own configuration nomenclature. Only attributes belonging to the component may be used. Attributes from subcomponents or user requirements are not available.\n\n### Example\n\nA product configuration model has a root component with two attributes.\n\n-   Material (Plastic, Wood, Steel)\n-   Length (10...100)\n\nA configuration nomenclature is defined using the following segments:\n\n1.  Attribute value: Material\n2.  Text constant: 'AAA'\n3.  Attribute value: Length\n\nThe configuration ID for wood material with a length of 78 will get the following configuration ID: WoodAAA78.\n\n## Nomenclature of dimensionbased configurations\nFor dimension-based configurations, a dedicated nomenclature can be built for the configuration product dimension. You can select the following segments on the **Product nomenclature** page.\n\n-   Number sequence value\n-   Text constant\n-   Configuration group item\n\nA configuration nomenclature can be defined for a bill of materials (BOM).\n\n### Example\n\nA bill of materials has 4 BOM lines divided into 2 configuration groups.\n\n-   BOM line: M0007, Standard cabinet\n    -   Configuration group: Cabinet\n-   BOM line: M0008, High end cabinet\n    -   Configuration group: Cabinet\n-   BOM line: M0021, Front grill cloth\n    -   Configuration group: Front grill\n-   BOM line: M0022, Front grill metal\n    -   Configuration group: Front grill\n\nA configuration nomenclature is defined using the following segments:\n\n1.  Configuration group: Cabinet\n2.  Text constant: '&'\n3.  Configuration group: Front grill\n\nThe configuration ID for a standard cabinet with cloth front grill will be: M0007&M0021.\n\n## Nomenclature of a combination of product variants and configurations\nWhen you use either constraint-based or dimension-based configuration technology to configure product variants for a product master, the product variants can get product variant numbers that include the nomenclature from the configuration dimension. Follow these steps to configure variants:\n\n1.  Define a product variant number nomenclature that includes the configuration dimension on the **Product nomenclature** page.\n2.  Assign this nomenclature to a product dimension group with the configuration dimension.\n3.  Define a configuration nomenclature for the components or BOMs that will be used for configuring the product variants.\n\n### Example for constraint-based configurations\n\nIn this example, you can use a product variant number nomenclature that consists of the following segments:\n\n1.  Product master number\n2.  Text constant '\\_'\n3.  Configuration\n\nThe configuration nomenclature can consist of the following segments:\n\n1.  Attribute value: Material\n2.  Text constant: 'AAA'\n3.  Attribute value: Length\n\nYou can enter the following values for segments:\n\n-   Product master number = M0099\n-   Material = Plastic\n-   Length = 12\n\nThe product variant number will become: M0099\\_PlasticAAA12.\n\n### Example for dimension-based configurations\n\nIn this example, you can use a product variant number nomenclature that consists of the following segments:\n\n1.  Product master number\n2.  Text constant '//'\n3.  Configuration\n\nThe configuration nomenclature can consist of the following segments:\n\n1.  Configuration group: Cabinet\n2.  Text constant: '&'\n3.  Configuration group: Front grill\n\nYou can enter the following values for segments:\n\n-   Product master number = D0123\n-   Cabinet = M0008\n-   Front grill = M0022\n\nThe product variant number will become: D0123//M0008&M0022.\n\n## Numbering conflicts\nIt is possible to set up product variant number nomenclature that does not result in unique product variant numbers. For example, this could happen if one active product dimension is not included in the nomenclature for a product master that uses the predefined variant configuration technology. Conflicts are handled differently for the different configuration technologies.\n\n### Predefined variants\n\nAn error will occur if you try to manually or automatically generate product variants where one or more ends up with the same product variant number. In order to avoid this, you should use all active product dimensions in the product dimension group, or include a number sequence to ensure that the product variant numbers are unique.\n\n### Constraint-based configurations\n\nDepending on the nomenclature, the system may attempt to assign a non-unique product variant number to a configuration. In this case, the system will use the number sequence for the configuration dimension as the product variant number instead. If this happens, you will receive a warning. In order to avoid this, you should include enough attributes in the nomenclature to ensure uniqueness, and make sure that the **Reuse** option is turned on for the component.\n\n### Dimension-based configurations\n\nThe configuration process includes a step in which the system will suggest a configuration value according to the nomenclature. In this step, you can manually change the configuration value. When you save the configuration, the system will check whether the configuration value is unique. If this is not the case, an error will be displayed. You must enter a unique configuration value in order to save the configuration.\n\n\n\nSee also\n--------\n\n[Create a product number nomenclature for predefined product variants (Task guide)](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/create-a-product-number-nomenclature-for-predefined-product-variants/)\n\n[Create a product number nomenclature for configured product variants (Task guide)](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/create-a-product-number-nomenclature-for-configured-product-variants/)\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[32,59],"content":"Product number nomenclature","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Product number nomenclature","pos":[0,27]}]},{"pos":[73,545],"content":"This topic describes how you can set up a product number nomenclature to replace the fixed format, [Product master number - Configuration - Size - Color - Style], with a targeted format that includes the product master number, active product dimensions, and text delimiters of your choice. You can also build a nomenclature to identify configurations that are created by the constraint-based product configurator. These nomenclatures can contain attributes of your choice.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"This topic describes how you can set up a product number nomenclature to replace the fixed format, [Product master number - Configuration - Size - Color - Style], with a targeted format that includes the product master number, active product dimensions, and text delimiters of your choice. You can also build a nomenclature to identify configurations that are created by the constraint-based product configurator. These nomenclatures can contain attributes of your choice.","pos":[0,472],"nodes":[{"content":"This topic describes how you can set up a product number nomenclature to replace the fixed format, [Product master number - Configuration - Size - Color - Style], with a targeted format that includes the product master number, active product dimensions, and text delimiters of your choice.","pos":[0,289]},{"content":"You can also build a nomenclature to identify configurations that are created by the constraint-based product configurator.","pos":[290,413]},{"content":"These nomenclatures can contain attributes of your choice.","pos":[414,472]}]}]},{"pos":[1184,1211],"content":"Product number nomenclature","linkify":"Product number nomenclature","nodes":[{"content":"Product number nomenclature","pos":[0,27]}]},{"content":"This topic describes how you can set up a product number nomenclature to replace the fixed format, [Product master number - Configuration - Size - Color - Style], with a targeted format that includes the product master number, active product dimensions, and text delimiters of your choice.","pos":[1257,1546]},{"content":"You can also build a nomenclature to identify configurations that are created by the constraint-based product configurator.","pos":[1547,1670]},{"content":"These nomenclatures can contain attributes of your choice.","pos":[1671,1729]},{"content":"The new product variant number nomenclature lets you include segments in your product variant identifiers.","pos":[1731,1837]},{"content":"These segments can include the product master number, product dimensions, number sequences, text constants, and attributes.","pos":[1838,1961]},{"content":"This functionality lets you quickly find a specific product variant when you create a sales order or purchase order.","pos":[1962,2078]},{"pos":[2083,2126],"content":"Nomenclature of predefined product variants","linkify":"Nomenclature of predefined product variants","nodes":[{"content":"Nomenclature of predefined product variants","pos":[0,43]}]},{"content":"Product variants are generated for product masters according to one of three configuration technologies:","pos":[2127,2231]},{"content":"Predefined variants","pos":[2237,2256]},{"content":"Constraint-based","pos":[2261,2277]},{"content":"Dimension-based","pos":[2282,2297]},{"content":"Each product variant has a number, and the product variant identification nomenclature lets you select the segments that will be included in each product variant number.","pos":[2299,2468]},{"content":"You can select the following segments on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Product nomenclature<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[2469,2544],"source":" You can select the following segments on the **Product nomenclature** page."},{"content":"Product master number","pos":[2550,2571]},{"content":"Number sequence value","pos":[2576,2597]},{"content":"Text constant","pos":[2602,2615]},{"content":"Product dimensions","pos":[2620,2638]},{"content":"Configuration","pos":[2647,2660]},{"content":"Color","pos":[2669,2674]},{"content":"Size","pos":[2683,2687]},{"content":"Style","pos":[2696,2701]},{"content":"After a product variant identification nomenclature is defined, it can be associated with a product dimension group.","pos":[2703,2819]},{"content":"Consequently, all product masters referencing this product dimension group will be assigned product variant numbers according to the nomenclature.","pos":[2820,2966]},{"content":"It is also possible to assign a product variant identification nomenclature directly to a product master, in which case the product variants belonging to this master will be assigned product variant numbers according to the nomenclature.","pos":[2967,3204]},{"pos":[3210,3217],"content":"Example","linkify":"Example","nodes":[{"content":"Example","pos":[0,7]}]},{"content":"A T-shirt (TS1234) is produced in 3 different sizes (S, M, L), 4 different colors (Red, Green, Blue, Yellow), and 2 styles (Polo, V) giving a total of 24 possible product variants.","pos":[3219,3399]},{"content":"A product variant identification nomenclature is created with the following segments:","pos":[3400,3485]},{"content":"Product master number","pos":[3491,3512]},{"content":"Text constant: '-'","pos":[3517,3535]},{"content":"Color","pos":[3540,3545]},{"content":"Text constant: '-'","pos":[3550,3568]},{"content":"Size","pos":[3573,3577]},{"content":"Text constant: '-'","pos":[3582,3600]},{"content":"Style","pos":[3605,3610]},{"content":"The product variant number for the Red, Small, Polo will be: TS1234-Red-Small-Polo.","pos":[3612,3695]},{"pos":[3700,3746],"content":"Nomenclature of constraintbased configurations","linkify":"Nomenclature of constraintbased configurations","nodes":[{"content":"Nomenclature of constraintbased configurations","pos":[0,46]}]},{"content":"For constraint-based configurations, a dedicated nomenclature can be built for the configuration product dimension.","pos":[3747,3862]},{"content":"You can select the following segments on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Product nomenclature<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[3863,3938],"source":" You can select the following segments on the **Product nomenclature** page."},{"content":"Number sequence value","pos":[3944,3965]},{"content":"Text constant","pos":[3970,3983]},{"content":"Attribute value","pos":[3988,4003]},{"content":"Each component in a product configuration model can have its own configuration nomenclature.","pos":[4006,4098]},{"content":"Only attributes belonging to the component may be used.","pos":[4099,4154]},{"content":"Attributes from subcomponents or user requirements are not available.","pos":[4155,4224]},{"pos":[4230,4237],"content":"Example","linkify":"Example","nodes":[{"content":"Example","pos":[0,7]}]},{"content":"A product configuration model has a root component with two attributes.","pos":[4239,4310]},{"content":"Material (Plastic, Wood, Steel)","pos":[4316,4347]},{"content":"Length (10...100)","pos":[4352,4369]},{"content":"A configuration nomenclature is defined using the following segments:","pos":[4371,4440]},{"content":"Attribute value: Material","pos":[4446,4471]},{"content":"Text constant: 'AAA'","pos":[4476,4496]},{"content":"Attribute value: Length","pos":[4501,4524]},{"content":"The configuration ID for wood material with a length of 78 will get the following configuration ID: WoodAAA78.","pos":[4526,4636]},{"pos":[4641,4686],"content":"Nomenclature of dimensionbased configurations","linkify":"Nomenclature of dimensionbased configurations","nodes":[{"content":"Nomenclature of dimensionbased configurations","pos":[0,45]}]},{"content":"For dimension-based configurations, a dedicated nomenclature can be built for the configuration product dimension.","pos":[4687,4801]},{"content":"You can select the following segments on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Product nomenclature<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[4802,4877],"source":" You can select the following segments on the **Product nomenclature** page."},{"content":"Number sequence value","pos":[4883,4904]},{"content":"Text constant","pos":[4909,4922]},{"content":"Configuration group item","pos":[4927,4951]},{"content":"A configuration nomenclature can be defined for a bill of materials (BOM).","pos":[4953,5027]},{"pos":[5033,5040],"content":"Example","linkify":"Example","nodes":[{"content":"Example","pos":[0,7]}]},{"content":"A bill of materials has 4 BOM lines divided into 2 configuration groups.","pos":[5042,5114]},{"content":"BOM line: M0007, Standard cabinet","pos":[5120,5153]},{"content":"Configuration group: Cabinet","pos":[5162,5190]},{"content":"BOM line: M0008, High end cabinet","pos":[5195,5228]},{"content":"Configuration group: Cabinet","pos":[5237,5265]},{"content":"BOM line: M0021, Front grill cloth","pos":[5270,5304]},{"content":"Configuration group: Front grill","pos":[5313,5345]},{"content":"BOM line: M0022, Front grill metal","pos":[5350,5384]},{"content":"Configuration group: Front grill","pos":[5393,5425]},{"content":"A configuration nomenclature is defined using the following segments:","pos":[5427,5496]},{"content":"Configuration group: Cabinet","pos":[5502,5530]},{"content":"Text constant: '&amp;'","pos":[5535,5553],"source":"Text constant: '&'"},{"content":"Configuration group: Front grill","pos":[5558,5590]},{"content":"The configuration ID for a standard cabinet with cloth front grill will be: M0007&amp;M0021.","pos":[5592,5680],"source":"The configuration ID for a standard cabinet with cloth front grill will be: M0007&M0021."},{"pos":[5685,5753],"content":"Nomenclature of a combination of product variants and configurations","linkify":"Nomenclature of a combination of product variants and configurations","nodes":[{"content":"Nomenclature of a combination of product variants and configurations","pos":[0,68]}]},{"content":"When you use either constraint-based or dimension-based configuration technology to configure product variants for a product master, the product variants can get product variant numbers that include the nomenclature from the configuration dimension.","pos":[5754,6003]},{"content":"Follow these steps to configure variants:","pos":[6004,6045]},{"pos":[6051,6175],"content":"Define a product variant number nomenclature that includes the configuration dimension on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Product nomenclature<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","source":"Define a product variant number nomenclature that includes the configuration dimension on the **Product nomenclature** page."},{"content":"Assign this nomenclature to a product dimension group with the configuration dimension.","pos":[6180,6267]},{"content":"Define a configuration nomenclature for the components or BOMs that will be used for configuring the product variants.","pos":[6272,6390]},{"pos":[6396,6439],"content":"Example for constraint-based configurations","linkify":"Example for constraint-based configurations","nodes":[{"content":"Example for constraint-based configurations","pos":[0,43]}]},{"content":"In this example, you can use a product variant number nomenclature that consists of the following segments:","pos":[6441,6548]},{"content":"Product master number","pos":[6554,6575]},{"content":"Text constant '<ph id=\"ph1\">\\_</ph>'","pos":[6580,6598],"source":"Text constant '\\_'"},{"content":"Configuration","pos":[6603,6616]},{"content":"The configuration nomenclature can consist of the following segments:","pos":[6618,6687]},{"content":"Attribute value: Material","pos":[6693,6718]},{"content":"Text constant: 'AAA'","pos":[6723,6743]},{"content":"Attribute value: Length","pos":[6748,6771]},{"content":"You can enter the following values for segments:","pos":[6773,6821]},{"content":"Product master number = M0099","pos":[6827,6856]},{"content":"Material = Plastic","pos":[6861,6879]},{"content":"Length = 12","pos":[6884,6895]},{"content":"The product variant number will become: M0099<ph id=\"ph1\">\\_</ph>PlasticAAA12.","pos":[6897,6957],"source":"The product variant number will become: M0099\\_PlasticAAA12."},{"pos":[6963,7005],"content":"Example for dimension-based configurations","linkify":"Example for dimension-based configurations","nodes":[{"content":"Example for dimension-based configurations","pos":[0,42]}]},{"content":"In this example, you can use a product variant number nomenclature that consists of the following segments:","pos":[7007,7114]},{"content":"Product master number","pos":[7120,7141]},{"content":"Text constant '//'","pos":[7146,7164]},{"content":"Configuration","pos":[7169,7182]},{"content":"The configuration nomenclature can consist of the following segments:","pos":[7184,7253]},{"content":"Configuration group: Cabinet","pos":[7259,7287]},{"content":"Text constant: '&amp;'","pos":[7292,7310],"source":"Text constant: '&'"},{"content":"Configuration group: Front grill","pos":[7315,7347]},{"content":"You can enter the following values for segments:","pos":[7349,7397]},{"content":"Product master number = D0123","pos":[7403,7432]},{"content":"Cabinet = M0008","pos":[7437,7452]},{"content":"Front grill = M0022","pos":[7457,7476]},{"content":"The product variant number will become: D0123//M0008&amp;M0022.","pos":[7478,7537],"source":"The product variant number will become: D0123//M0008&M0022."},{"pos":[7542,7561],"content":"Numbering conflicts","linkify":"Numbering conflicts","nodes":[{"content":"Numbering conflicts","pos":[0,19]}]},{"content":"It is possible to set up product variant number nomenclature that does not result in unique product variant numbers.","pos":[7562,7678]},{"content":"For example, this could happen if one active product dimension is not included in the nomenclature for a product master that uses the predefined variant configuration technology.","pos":[7679,7857]},{"content":"Conflicts are handled differently for the different configuration technologies.","pos":[7858,7937]},{"pos":[7943,7962],"content":"Predefined variants","linkify":"Predefined variants","nodes":[{"content":"Predefined variants","pos":[0,19]}]},{"content":"An error will occur if you try to manually or automatically generate product variants where one or more ends up with the same product variant number.","pos":[7964,8113]},{"content":"In order to avoid this, you should use all active product dimensions in the product dimension group, or include a number sequence to ensure that the product variant numbers are unique.","pos":[8114,8298]},{"pos":[8304,8335],"content":"Constraint-based configurations","linkify":"Constraint-based configurations","nodes":[{"content":"Constraint-based configurations","pos":[0,31]}]},{"content":"Depending on the nomenclature, the system may attempt to assign a non-unique product variant number to a configuration.","pos":[8337,8456]},{"content":"In this case, the system will use the number sequence for the configuration dimension as the product variant number instead.","pos":[8457,8581]},{"content":"If this happens, you will receive a warning.","pos":[8582,8626]},{"content":"In order to avoid this, you should include enough attributes in the nomenclature to ensure uniqueness, and make sure that the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Reuse<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option is turned on for the component.","pos":[8627,8801],"source":" In order to avoid this, you should include enough attributes in the nomenclature to ensure uniqueness, and make sure that the **Reuse** option is turned on for the component."},{"pos":[8807,8837],"content":"Dimension-based configurations","linkify":"Dimension-based configurations","nodes":[{"content":"Dimension-based configurations","pos":[0,30]}]},{"content":"The configuration process includes a step in which the system will suggest a configuration value according to the nomenclature.","pos":[8839,8966]},{"content":"In this step, you can manually change the configuration value.","pos":[8967,9029]},{"content":"When you save the configuration, the system will check whether the configuration value is unique.","pos":[9030,9127]},{"content":"If this is not the case, an error will be displayed.","pos":[9128,9180]},{"content":"You must enter a unique configuration value in order to save the configuration.","pos":[9181,9260]},{"pos":[9264,9272],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[9283,9473],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Create a product number nomenclature for predefined product variants (Task guide)<ept id=\"p1\">](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/create-a-product-number-nomenclature-for-predefined-product-variants/)</ept>","source":"[Create a product number nomenclature for predefined product variants (Task guide)](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/create-a-product-number-nomenclature-for-predefined-product-variants/)"},{"pos":[9475,9665],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Create a product number nomenclature for configured product variants (Task guide)<ept id=\"p1\">](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/create-a-product-number-nomenclature-for-configured-product-variants/)</ept>","source":"[Create a product number nomenclature for configured product variants (Task guide)](http://ax.help.dynamics.com/en/wiki/create-a-product-number-nomenclature-for-configured-product-variants/)"}]}