{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,107],"content":"Determine the optimal combination of overlapping discounts | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Determine the optimal combination of overlapping discounts | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,75]}]},{"pos":[121,509],"content":"When discounts overlap, you must determine the combination of overlapping discounts that will produce the lowest transaction total or the highest total discount. When the discount amount varies according to the price of the products that are purchased, such as in the common “Buy 1, get 1 X percent off” (BOGO) retail discount, this process becomes an issue of combinatorial optimization.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"When discounts overlap, you must determine the combination of overlapping discounts that will produce the lowest transaction total or the highest total discount. When the discount amount varies according to the price of the products that are purchased, such as in the common “Buy 1, get 1 X percent off” (BOGO) retail discount, this process becomes an issue of combinatorial optimization.","pos":[0,388],"nodes":[{"content":"When discounts overlap, you must determine the combination of overlapping discounts that will produce the lowest transaction total or the highest total discount.","pos":[0,161]},{"content":"When the discount amount varies according to the price of the products that are purchased, such as in the common “Buy 1, get 1 X percent off” (BOGO) retail discount, this process becomes an issue of combinatorial optimization.","pos":[162,388]}]}]},{"pos":[958,1016],"content":"Determine the optimal combination of overlapping discounts","linkify":"Determine the optimal combination of overlapping discounts","nodes":[{"content":"Determine the optimal combination of overlapping discounts","pos":[0,58]}]},{"content":"When discounts overlap, you must determine the combination of overlapping discounts that will produce the lowest transaction total or the highest total discount.","pos":[1018,1179]},{"content":"When the discount amount varies according to the price of the products that are purchased, such as in the common “Buy 1, get 1 X percent off” (BOGO) retail discount, this process becomes an issue of combinatorial optimization.","pos":[1180,1406]},{"content":"This article applies to Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 R3 with KB 3105973 (released November 2, 2015) or later, and to the February 2016 release of Microsoft Dynamics AX.","pos":[1408,1574]},{"content":"To determine the combination overlapping discounts to apply in a timely manner, and to continue to provide the rich discounting functionality that is available in Microsoft Dynamics AX for Retail, we have introduced a method for applying overlapping discounts.","pos":[1575,1835]},{"content":"We call this new method <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>marginal value ranking<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[1836,1887],"source":" We call this new method **marginal value ranking**."},{"content":"Marginal value ranking is used when the time that is required in order to evaluate the possible combinations of overlapping discounts exceeds a threshold that is configurable on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Retail parameters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page in Dynamics AX.","pos":[1888,2112],"source":" Marginal value ranking is used when the time that is required in order to evaluate the possible combinations of overlapping discounts exceeds a threshold that is configurable on the **Retail parameters** page in Dynamics AX."},{"content":"In the marginal value ranking method, a value is calculated for each overlapping discount by using the discount’s value on the shared products.","pos":[2113,2256]},{"content":"The overlapped discounts are then applied from the highest relative value to the lowest relative value.","pos":[2257,2360]},{"content":"For details about the new method, see the “Marginal value” section, later in this article.","pos":[2361,2451]},{"content":"Marginal value ranking isn’t used when the discount amounts for a product aren’t affected by another product in the transaction.","pos":[2452,2580]},{"content":"For example, this method isn’t used for two simple discounts, or for a simple discount and a single product quantity discount.","pos":[2581,2707]},{"pos":[2712,2729],"content":"Discount examples","linkify":"Discount examples","nodes":[{"content":"Discount examples","pos":[0,17]}]},{"content":"In Dynamics AX, you can create an unlimited number of retail discounts on a common set of products.","pos":[2730,2829]},{"content":"However, because there is no limit, performance issues can occur when you try to calculate the discounts that should be used on the various products.","pos":[2830,2979]},{"content":"The following examples illustrate this issue in more detail.","pos":[2980,3040]},{"content":"In example 1, we start with two products and two overlapping discounts.","pos":[3041,3112]},{"content":"Then, in example 2, we show how the issue evolves as more products are added.","pos":[3113,3190]},{"pos":[3196,3237],"content":"Example 1: Two products and two discounts","linkify":"Example 1: Two products and two discounts","nodes":[{"content":"Example 1: Two products and two discounts","pos":[0,41]}]},{"content":"In this example, two products are required in order to qualify for each discount, and the discounts can’t be combined.","pos":[3239,3357]},{"content":"The discounts in this example are <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Best price<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> discounts.","pos":[3358,3417],"source":" The discounts in this example are **Best price** discounts."},{"content":"Both products qualify for both discounts.","pos":[3418,3459]},{"content":"Here are the two discounts.","pos":[3460,3487]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Overlapping discount combo 01<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-01.jpg)](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-01.jpg)</ept> For any two products, the better of these two discounts depends on the prices of the two products.","pos":[3488,3707],"source":"[![Overlapping discount combo 01](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-01.jpg)](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-01.jpg) For any two products, the better of these two discounts depends on the prices of the two products."},{"content":"When the price of both products is equal or almost equal, discount 1 is better.","pos":[3708,3787]},{"content":"When the price of one product is significantly less than the price of the other product, discount 2 is better.","pos":[3788,3898]},{"content":"Here is the mathematical rule for evaluating these two discounts against each other: <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Overlapping discount combo 02<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-02.jpg)](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-02.jpg)</ept> Note that when the price of product 1 is equal to two-thirds of the price of product 2, the two discounts are equal.","pos":[3899,4221],"source":" Here is the mathematical rule for evaluating these two discounts against each other: [![Overlapping discount combo 02](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-02.jpg)](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-02.jpg) Note that when the price of product 1 is equal to two-thirds of the price of product 2, the two discounts are equal."},{"content":"In this example, the effective discount percentage for discount 1 varies from a few percent (when the prices of the two products are far apart) to a maximum of 25 percent (when the two products have the same price).","pos":[4222,4437]},{"content":"The effective discount percentage for discount 2 is fixed.","pos":[4438,4496]},{"content":"It’s always 20 percent.","pos":[4497,4520]},{"content":"Because the effective discount percentage for discount 1 has a range that can be more than or less than discount 2, the best discount depends on the prices of the two products that must be discounted.","pos":[4521,4721]},{"content":"In this example, the calculation is completed quickly, because only two discounts are applied on only two products.","pos":[4722,4837]},{"content":"There are only two possible combinations: one application of discount 1 or one application of discount 2.","pos":[4838,4943]},{"content":"There are no permutations to calculate.","pos":[4944,4983]},{"content":"The value of each discount is calculated by using both products, and the best discount is used.","pos":[4984,5079]},{"pos":[5085,5127],"content":"Example 2: Four products and two discounts","linkify":"Example 2: Four products and two discounts","nodes":[{"content":"Example 2: Four products and two discounts","pos":[0,42]}]},{"content":"Next, we will use four products and the same two discounts.","pos":[5129,5188]},{"content":"All four products qualify for both discounts.","pos":[5189,5234]},{"content":"There are twelve possible combinations.","pos":[5235,5274]},{"content":"In the end, two discounts will be applied to the transaction in one of three combinations: two applications of discount 1, two applications of discount 2, or one application of discount 1 and one application of discount 2.","pos":[5275,5497]},{"content":"To illustrate the possible combinations, we will look at two different sets of four products that have different prices:","pos":[5498,5618]},{"content":"All four products have the same price, $15.00.","pos":[5624,5670]},{"content":"In this case, the best discount combination is two applications of discount 1.","pos":[5671,5749]},{"content":"Two products will be full price, and two will be 50 percent off.","pos":[5750,5814]},{"content":"The discounted total for the transaction is $45 (15 + 15 + 7.50 + 7.50), which is $15 (25 percent) off the undiscounted total of $60.","pos":[5815,5948]},{"content":"Discount 2 is only $12 (20 percent).","pos":[5949,5985]},{"content":"Two products are $20 each, one product is $15, and one product is $5.","pos":[5990,6059]},{"content":"In this case, the best discount combination is one application of discount 2 and one application of discount 1.","pos":[6060,6171]},{"content":"The following tables illustrates the discounts.","pos":[6172,6219]},{"content":"To read the tables, use one product from a row and one product from a column.","pos":[6221,6298]},{"content":"For example, in the table for discount 1, when you combine the two $20 products, you get $10 off.","pos":[6299,6396]},{"content":"In the table for discount 2, when you combine the $15 product and the $5 product, you get $4 off.","pos":[6397,6494]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Overlapping discount combo 03<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-03.jpg)](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-03.jpg)</ept> First, we find the largest discount that is available from any two products by using either discount.","pos":[6495,6717],"source":"[![Overlapping discount combo 03](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-03.jpg)](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-03.jpg) First, we find the largest discount that is available from any two products by using either discount."},{"content":"The two tables show the discount amount for all combinations of the two products.","pos":[6718,6799]},{"content":"The shaded portions of the tables represent either cases where a product is paired with itself, which we can’t do, or a reverse pairing of two products that produces the same discount amount and can be ignored.","pos":[6800,7010]},{"content":"By looking at the tables, you can see that discount 1 for the two $20 items is the largest discount that is available for either discount on all four products.","pos":[7011,7170]},{"content":"(This discount is highlighted in green in the first table.) That leaves only the $15 product and the $5 product.","pos":[7171,7283]},{"content":"By looking at the two tables again, you can see that, for these two products, discount 1 gives a $2.50 discount, whereas discount 2 gives a $4 discount.","pos":[7284,7436]},{"content":"Therefore, we select discount 2.","pos":[7437,7469]},{"content":"The total discount is $14.","pos":[7470,7496]},{"content":"To make this discussion easier to visualize, here are two additional tables that show the effective discount percentage for all possible two-product combinations for both discount 1 and discount 2.","pos":[7497,7694]},{"content":"Only half the list of combinations is included, because, for these two discounts, the order in which the two products are put into the discount doesn’t matter.","pos":[7695,7854]},{"content":"The highest effective discount (25 percent) is highlighted in green, and the lowest effective discount (10 percent) is highlighted in red.","pos":[7855,7993]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Overlapping discount combo 04<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-04.jpg)](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-04.jpg)</ept> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> When prices vary, and two or more discount compete, the only way to guarantee the best combination of discounts is to evaluate both discounts and compare them.","pos":[7994,8284],"source":"[![Overlapping discount combo 04](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-04.jpg)](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-04.jpg) **Note:** When prices vary, and two or more discount compete, the only way to guarantee the best combination of discounts is to evaluate both discounts and compare them."},{"pos":[8289,8316],"content":"Total possible combinations","linkify":"Total possible combinations","nodes":[{"content":"Total possible combinations","pos":[0,27]}]},{"content":"This section continues the example from the previous section.","pos":[8317,8378]},{"content":"We will add more products and another discount, and see how many combinations must be calculated and compared.","pos":[8379,8489]},{"content":"The following table shows the number of possible discount combinations as the product quantity increases.","pos":[8490,8595]},{"content":"The table shows what happens both when there are two overlapping discounts, as in the previous example, and when there are three overlapping discounts.","pos":[8596,8747]},{"content":"The number of possible discount combinations that must be evaluated soon exceeds what even a fast computer can calculate and compare quickly enough to be acceptable for retail transactions.","pos":[8748,8937]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Overlapping discount combo 05<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-05.jpg)](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-05.jpg)</ept> When even larger quantities or more overlapping discounts are applied, the total number of possible discount combinations quickly goes into the millions, and the time that is required in order to evaluate and select the best possible combination quickly becomes noticeable.","pos":[8938,9332],"source":"[![Overlapping discount combo 05](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-05.jpg)](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-05.jpg) When even larger quantities or more overlapping discounts are applied, the total number of possible discount combinations quickly goes into the millions, and the time that is required in order to evaluate and select the best possible combination quickly becomes noticeable."},{"content":"Some optimizations have been done in the retail price engine to reduce the total number of combinations that must be evaluated.","pos":[9333,9460]},{"content":"However, because the number overlapping discounts and the quantities in a transaction aren’t limited, a large number of combinations will always have to be evaluated whenever there are overlapping discounts.","pos":[9461,9668]},{"content":"This issue is the issue that the marginal value ranking method addresses.","pos":[9669,9742]},{"pos":[9747,9768],"content":"Marginal value method","linkify":"Marginal value method","nodes":[{"content":"Marginal value method","pos":[0,21]}]},{"content":"To resolve the issue of an exponentially increasing number of combinations that must be evaluated, an optimization exists that calculates the value per shared product of each discount on the set of products that two or more discounts can be applied to.","pos":[9769,10021]},{"content":"We refer to this value as the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>marginal value<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> of the discount for the shared products.","pos":[10022,10111],"source":" We refer to this value as the **marginal value** of the discount for the shared products."},{"content":"The marginal value is the average per product increase in the total discount amount when the shared products are included in each discount.","pos":[10112,10251]},{"content":"The marginal value is calculated by taking the total discount amount (DTotal), subtracting the discount amount without the shared products (DMinus<ph id=\"ph1\">\\\\</ph> Shared), and dividing that difference by the number of shared products (ProductsShared).","pos":[10252,10489],"source":" The marginal value is calculated by taking the total discount amount (DTotal), subtracting the discount amount without the shared products (DMinus\\\\ Shared), and dividing that difference by the number of shared products (ProductsShared)."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Overlapping discount combo 06<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-06.jpg)](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-06.jpg)</ept> After the marginal value of each discount on a shared set of products is calculated, the discounts are applied to the shared products in order, exhaustively, from highest marginal value to lowest marginal value.","pos":[10490,10822],"source":"[![Overlapping discount combo 06](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-06.jpg)](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-06.jpg) After the marginal value of each discount on a shared set of products is calculated, the discounts are applied to the shared products in order, exhaustively, from highest marginal value to lowest marginal value."},{"content":"For this method, all remaining discount possibilities aren’t compared every time after a single instance of a discount is applied.","pos":[10823,10953]},{"content":"Instead, the overlapping discounts are compared one time and then applied in order.","pos":[10954,11037]},{"content":"No additional comparisons are done.","pos":[11038,11073]},{"content":"You can configure the threshold to switch to the marginal value method on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Discount<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab of the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Retail parameters<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page.","pos":[11074,11203],"source":" You can configure the threshold to switch to the marginal value method on the **Discount** tab of the **Retail parameters** page."},{"content":"The acceptable time to calculate the total discount varies across retail industries.","pos":[11204,11288]},{"content":"However, this time generally falls in the range of tens of milliseconds to one second.","pos":[11289,11375]}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Determine the optimal combination of overlapping discounts | Microsoft Docs\ndescription: When discounts overlap, you must determine the combination of overlapping discounts that will produce the lowest transaction total or the highest total discount. When the discount amount varies according to the price of the products that are purchased, such as in the common “Buy 1, get 1 X percent off” (BOGO) retail discount, this process becomes an issue of combinatorial optimization.\nauthor: kfend\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 2016-06-08 17:38:06\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# keywords: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: kfend\nms.suite: Released- Dynamics AX application 7.0.1\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 89643\nms.assetid: cb794325-3c6b-4623-9304-cee8367930ff\nms.region: global\nms.industry: Retail\nms.author: kfend\n\n---\n\n# Determine the optimal combination of overlapping discounts\n\nWhen discounts overlap, you must determine the combination of overlapping discounts that will produce the lowest transaction total or the highest total discount. When the discount amount varies according to the price of the products that are purchased, such as in the common “Buy 1, get 1 X percent off” (BOGO) retail discount, this process becomes an issue of combinatorial optimization.\n\nThis article applies to Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 R3 with KB 3105973 (released November 2, 2015) or later, and to the February 2016 release of Microsoft Dynamics AX. To determine the combination overlapping discounts to apply in a timely manner, and to continue to provide the rich discounting functionality that is available in Microsoft Dynamics AX for Retail, we have introduced a method for applying overlapping discounts. We call this new method **marginal value ranking**. Marginal value ranking is used when the time that is required in order to evaluate the possible combinations of overlapping discounts exceeds a threshold that is configurable on the **Retail parameters** page in Dynamics AX. In the marginal value ranking method, a value is calculated for each overlapping discount by using the discount’s value on the shared products. The overlapped discounts are then applied from the highest relative value to the lowest relative value. For details about the new method, see the “Marginal value” section, later in this article. Marginal value ranking isn’t used when the discount amounts for a product aren’t affected by another product in the transaction. For example, this method isn’t used for two simple discounts, or for a simple discount and a single product quantity discount.\n\n## Discount examples\nIn Dynamics AX, you can create an unlimited number of retail discounts on a common set of products. However, because there is no limit, performance issues can occur when you try to calculate the discounts that should be used on the various products. The following examples illustrate this issue in more detail. In example 1, we start with two products and two overlapping discounts. Then, in example 2, we show how the issue evolves as more products are added.\n\n### Example 1: Two products and two discounts\n\nIn this example, two products are required in order to qualify for each discount, and the discounts can’t be combined. The discounts in this example are **Best price** discounts. Both products qualify for both discounts. Here are the two discounts. [![Overlapping discount combo 01](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-01.jpg)](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-01.jpg) For any two products, the better of these two discounts depends on the prices of the two products. When the price of both products is equal or almost equal, discount 1 is better. When the price of one product is significantly less than the price of the other product, discount 2 is better. Here is the mathematical rule for evaluating these two discounts against each other: [![Overlapping discount combo 02](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-02.jpg)](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-02.jpg) Note that when the price of product 1 is equal to two-thirds of the price of product 2, the two discounts are equal. In this example, the effective discount percentage for discount 1 varies from a few percent (when the prices of the two products are far apart) to a maximum of 25 percent (when the two products have the same price). The effective discount percentage for discount 2 is fixed. It’s always 20 percent. Because the effective discount percentage for discount 1 has a range that can be more than or less than discount 2, the best discount depends on the prices of the two products that must be discounted. In this example, the calculation is completed quickly, because only two discounts are applied on only two products. There are only two possible combinations: one application of discount 1 or one application of discount 2. There are no permutations to calculate. The value of each discount is calculated by using both products, and the best discount is used.\n\n### Example 2: Four products and two discounts\n\nNext, we will use four products and the same two discounts. All four products qualify for both discounts. There are twelve possible combinations. In the end, two discounts will be applied to the transaction in one of three combinations: two applications of discount 1, two applications of discount 2, or one application of discount 1 and one application of discount 2. To illustrate the possible combinations, we will look at two different sets of four products that have different prices:\n\n-   All four products have the same price, $15.00. In this case, the best discount combination is two applications of discount 1. Two products will be full price, and two will be 50 percent off. The discounted total for the transaction is $45 (15 + 15 + 7.50 + 7.50), which is $15 (25 percent) off the undiscounted total of $60. Discount 2 is only $12 (20 percent).\n-   Two products are $20 each, one product is $15, and one product is $5. In this case, the best discount combination is one application of discount 2 and one application of discount 1. The following tables illustrates the discounts.\n\nTo read the tables, use one product from a row and one product from a column. For example, in the table for discount 1, when you combine the two $20 products, you get $10 off. In the table for discount 2, when you combine the $15 product and the $5 product, you get $4 off. [![Overlapping discount combo 03](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-03.jpg)](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-03.jpg) First, we find the largest discount that is available from any two products by using either discount. The two tables show the discount amount for all combinations of the two products. The shaded portions of the tables represent either cases where a product is paired with itself, which we can’t do, or a reverse pairing of two products that produces the same discount amount and can be ignored. By looking at the tables, you can see that discount 1 for the two $20 items is the largest discount that is available for either discount on all four products. (This discount is highlighted in green in the first table.) That leaves only the $15 product and the $5 product. By looking at the two tables again, you can see that, for these two products, discount 1 gives a $2.50 discount, whereas discount 2 gives a $4 discount. Therefore, we select discount 2. The total discount is $14. To make this discussion easier to visualize, here are two additional tables that show the effective discount percentage for all possible two-product combinations for both discount 1 and discount 2. Only half the list of combinations is included, because, for these two discounts, the order in which the two products are put into the discount doesn’t matter. The highest effective discount (25 percent) is highlighted in green, and the lowest effective discount (10 percent) is highlighted in red. [![Overlapping discount combo 04](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-04.jpg)](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-04.jpg) **Note:** When prices vary, and two or more discount compete, the only way to guarantee the best combination of discounts is to evaluate both discounts and compare them.\n\n## Total possible combinations\nThis section continues the example from the previous section. We will add more products and another discount, and see how many combinations must be calculated and compared. The following table shows the number of possible discount combinations as the product quantity increases. The table shows what happens both when there are two overlapping discounts, as in the previous example, and when there are three overlapping discounts. The number of possible discount combinations that must be evaluated soon exceeds what even a fast computer can calculate and compare quickly enough to be acceptable for retail transactions. [![Overlapping discount combo 05](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-05.jpg)](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-05.jpg) When even larger quantities or more overlapping discounts are applied, the total number of possible discount combinations quickly goes into the millions, and the time that is required in order to evaluate and select the best possible combination quickly becomes noticeable. Some optimizations have been done in the retail price engine to reduce the total number of combinations that must be evaluated. However, because the number overlapping discounts and the quantities in a transaction aren’t limited, a large number of combinations will always have to be evaluated whenever there are overlapping discounts. This issue is the issue that the marginal value ranking method addresses.\n\n## Marginal value method\nTo resolve the issue of an exponentially increasing number of combinations that must be evaluated, an optimization exists that calculates the value per shared product of each discount on the set of products that two or more discounts can be applied to. We refer to this value as the **marginal value** of the discount for the shared products. The marginal value is the average per product increase in the total discount amount when the shared products are included in each discount. The marginal value is calculated by taking the total discount amount (DTotal), subtracting the discount amount without the shared products (DMinus\\\\ Shared), and dividing that difference by the number of shared products (ProductsShared). [![Overlapping discount combo 06](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-06.jpg)](./media/overlapping-discount-combo-06.jpg) After the marginal value of each discount on a shared set of products is calculated, the discounts are applied to the shared products in order, exhaustively, from highest marginal value to lowest marginal value. For this method, all remaining discount possibilities aren’t compared every time after a single instance of a discount is applied. Instead, the overlapping discounts are compared one time and then applied in order. No additional comparisons are done. You can configure the threshold to switch to the marginal value method on the **Discount** tab of the **Retail parameters** page. The acceptable time to calculate the total discount varies across retail industries. However, this time generally falls in the range of tens of milliseconds to one second.\n\n"}