{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,74],"content":"Consolidated batch orders | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Consolidated batch orders | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,42]}]},{"pos":[88,152],"content":"This article describes the concept of consolidated batch orders.","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"This article describes the concept of consolidated batch orders.","pos":[0,64]}]},{"pos":[328,403],"content":"PmfAddToConsOrder, PmfBulkItemConv, PmfBulkPackOnHand, PmfConsOrderListPage","needQuote":true,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"PmfAddToConsOrder, PmfBulkItemConv, PmfBulkPackOnHand, PmfConsOrderListPage","pos":[0,75]}]},{"pos":[675,700],"content":"Consolidated batch orders","linkify":"Consolidated batch orders","nodes":[{"content":"Consolidated batch orders","pos":[0,25]}]},{"content":"This article describes the concept of consolidated batch orders.","pos":[702,766]},{"content":"A bulk item that is produced is considered a parent item, whereas a packed item is considered a child item.","pos":[768,875]},{"content":"The relation between the bulk item and the packed item is expressed in a bulk item conversion.","pos":[876,970]},{"content":"This bulk item conversion is defined on the bulk item itself.","pos":[971,1032]},{"content":"Packed items can be packaged into containers of either a single size or multiple sizes that are considered one unit.","pos":[1033,1149]},{"content":"By consolidating the orders for a bulk item, you can see all the related batch orders in a single view that can help you determine any remaining work that must be completed.","pos":[1150,1323]},{"content":"A consolidated batch order can contain any combination of the following orders:","pos":[1324,1403]},{"content":"A single bulk order and multiple packed orders","pos":[1409,1455]},{"content":"Multiple bulk orders and multiple packed orders","pos":[1460,1507]},{"content":"Multiple bulk orders and a single packed order","pos":[1512,1558]},{"content":"Only packed orders","pos":[1563,1581]}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Consolidated batch orders | Microsoft Docs\ndescription: This article describes the concept of consolidated batch orders.\nauthor: YuyuScheller\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 2015-12-07 09:17:20\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nkeywords: PmfAddToConsOrder, PmfBulkItemConv, PmfBulkPackOnHand, PmfConsOrderListPage\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: YuyuScheller\nms.suite: Released- Dynamics AX 7.0.0\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 19291\nms.assetid: 4d886060-7277-41a3-8205-4444cbfbf9aa\nms.region: Global\nms.industry: Manufacturing\nms.author: yuyus\n\n---\n\n# Consolidated batch orders\n\nThis article describes the concept of consolidated batch orders.\n\nA bulk item that is produced is considered a parent item, whereas a packed item is considered a child item. The relation between the bulk item and the packed item is expressed in a bulk item conversion. This bulk item conversion is defined on the bulk item itself. Packed items can be packaged into containers of either a single size or multiple sizes that are considered one unit. By consolidating the orders for a bulk item, you can see all the related batch orders in a single view that can help you determine any remaining work that must be completed. A consolidated batch order can contain any combination of the following orders:\n\n-   A single bulk order and multiple packed orders\n-   Multiple bulk orders and multiple packed orders\n-   Multiple bulk orders and a single packed order\n-   Only packed orders\n\n\n"}