{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Distribute and complete a questionnaire\ndescription: This topic explains how distribute the questionnaires that you design, so that they are available to the person or group of people who will complete them. \nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics365Operations\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: KMConnectionType, KMKnowledgeCollectorPlanningTabel, SysEmailParameters\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: twheeloc\nms.search.scope: AX 7.0.0, Operations, Core\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 17424\nms.assetid: fd8d867a-2446-400a-b91f-ad4085427470\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: twheeloc\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0, Talent July 2017 update\n\n---\n\n# Distribute and complete a questionnaire\n\nThis topic explains how distribute the questionnaires that you design, so that they are available to the person or group of people who will complete them. \n\nThere are multiple ways to distribute a questionnaire:\n\n-   Mark the questionnaire as active. The questionnaire is then available to all employees, unless a questionnaire group is set up to restrict access to it.\n-   Assign rights to a questionnaire group. The questionnaire is then available to all members of the selected group.\n-   Create planned answer sessions. The questionnaire is then available only to a particular person.\n-   Create a schedule. The questionnaire can then be available to multiple people.\n\n## Marking a questionnaire as active\nBy setting the **Active** field to **Yes** on the **Questionnaires** page, you make the questionnaire available for all employees to complete. Respondents can complete the questionnaire multiple times. This functionality is useful if you want to gather continual feedback throughout the year. For example, you can make a questionnaire that employees use to give feedback about the lunch service in the cafeteria.\n\n## Questionnaire groups\nYou can set up questionnaire groups and then include the respondents that a questionnaire should be distributed to. \n\nYou can create questionnaire groups from the following pages:\n\n-   **Questionnaire groups** – Only individuals in a questionnaire group can complete a selected questionnaire. For example, your intended audience is contractors, so you create a questionnaire group that is specific to those respondents.\n-   **Questionnaire group members** – You can add people to the questionnaire groups.\n\nTo assign a questionnaire group to a questionnaire, on the **Questionnaires** page, click **User rights**. After the questionnaire is saved as active, the members of the questionnaire group can complete the questionnaire. This functionality is helpful if you want to test a questionnaire on a select group of people before you roll it out to a larger group, or if you want to target a questionnaire to a very specific audience.\n\n## Planned answer sessions in a questionnaire\nPlanned answer sessions are questionnaires that you've designed and selected the respondents for. \n\n**Note:** Before you can set up planned answer sessions, you must design a questionnaire. \n\nOn the **Planned answer session** page, you can create a planned answer session for an individual employee. The list on the page displays all planned questionnaires. \n\nPlanned answer sessions are also used on the **Questionnaire schedules** page, where you can plan questionnaires for multiple people:\n\n-   Employees\n-   Course participants\n-   Organizational units\n\nEach person can answer the questionnaire only one time.\n\n## Scheduling a questionnaire\nYou can optionally schedule a questionnaire for multiple respondents.\n\n### Planning types\n\nPlanning types are required if you want to schedule planned answer sessions for multiple respondents. Planning types are used to classify questionnaire schedules. For example, you can schedule questionnaires for the following purposes:\n\n-   Evaluation\n-   Survey\n-   Testing\n\nYou can specify planning types for a questionnaire schedule on the **Questionnaire schedules** page.\n\n### Reference types for questionnaire\n\nYou can use reference types to enter criteria for the respondents that you might select when you schedule a questionnaire. \n\nUse the **Reference types** page to set up reference types for a questionnaire. Each reference type corresponds to a table in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise Edition. When you create questionnaire schedules, you can specify individual records in the table or a range of records that the questionnaire will be associated with. \n\nFor example, if you select the Courses table, you can decide which specific course the questionnaire will be for. When you set up a reference for the Courses table, some fields and buttons on the **Courses** page become available.\n\n### Questionnaire schedules\n\nYou can use questionnaire schedules to generate multiple planned answer sessions for a group of users, based on a reference type. Create a schedule on the **Questionnaire schedules** page. Select the planning type to categorize the schedule, and also select the reference type that should be used to query the system for specific users. For example, if you set the reference type to the Courses table, you can select a specific course in the **Reference** field. \n\nClick **Setup details** to select the questionnaire and other criteria. For example, specify the instructor's name as a criterion if the questionnaire is an evaluation of the instructor. After you've finished entering the setup details, the system generates planned answer sessions for the users that are included in the query. \n\nClick **Planned answer sessions** to view the answer sessions for the schedule. You can then manually create additional planned answer sessions or delete planned answer sessions that haven't been answered. \n\nClick **Functions** &gt; **Start** to make the questionnaire available to the users in related planned answer sessions. Click **Answers** to view the completed responses to the questionnaire. You can optionally copy the questionnaire schedule settings, planned answer sessions, and answers to a new questionnaire schedule.\n\n## Notifying respondents about questionnaires that are available to them\nWhen you distribute a questionnaire, you must notify respondents that questionnaires are available to them. \n\n**Note:** Respondents must be users in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise Edition to complete a questionnaire.\n\n### Notifying respondents about a planned answer session\n\nIf you use a planned answer session, you must notify the person directly, such as by telephone or email.\n\n### Notifying respondents about a scheduling\n\nUse the **Questionnaire schedules** page to prepare and send email to all respondents who are assigned to the questionnaire. Enter the email text on the **E-mail for employee self service** tab. After the schedule has been started, click **Functions** &gt; **Send e-mail** to generate and send the email to the respondents. Respondents can then sign in to the website and complete the questionnaire. \n\n**Note:** Before you can use the email functionality, your IT administrator must enter the email settings on the **E-mail parameters** page.\n\n## Ending a scheduled questionnaire\nYou can end a scheduled questionnaire after all respondents have completed their assigned answer sessions. After a scheduled questionnaire is ended, you can't copy its settings to a new schedule. \n\n**Note:** If one or more respondents haven't completed the questionnaire, but you still want to end the scheduling, you must first delete those respondents from the list on the **Planned answer session** page. You can then end the schedule.\n\n## Completing questionnaires\nAfter you've designed and distributed a questionnaire, the questionnaire can be completed by selected respondents. You can complete the questionnaires that are available to you from two locations:\n\n-   In the navigation pane, click **Questionnaires** &gt; **Distribute** &gt; **Complete a questionnaire**.\n-   In Employee self-service, click **Questionnaires to complete**.\n\nQuestionnaires can made be available to specific users or groups of users, or to all users in a network.\n\nSee also\n--------\n\n[Designing questionnaires](design-questionnaires.md)\n\n[Using questionnaires](questionnaires.md)\n\n[Viewing and evaluating the results of questionnaires](evaluate-questionnaire-results.md)\n\n","nodes":[{"content":"Distribute and complete a questionnaire","nodes":[{"pos":[0,39],"content":"Distribute and complete a questionnaire","nodes":[{"content":"Distribute and complete a questionnaire","pos":[0,39]}]}],"pos":[31,71],"yaml":true},{"content":"This topic explains how distribute the questionnaires that you design, so that they are available to the person or group of people who will complete them.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,154],"content":"This topic explains how distribute the questionnaires that you design, so that they are available to the person or group of people who will complete them.","nodes":[{"content":"This topic explains how distribute the questionnaires that you design, so that they are available to the person or group of people who will complete them.","pos":[0,154]}]}],"pos":[84,239],"yaml":true},{"pos":[849,888],"content":"Distribute and complete a questionnaire","linkify":"Distribute and complete a questionnaire","nodes":[{"content":"Distribute and complete a questionnaire","pos":[0,39]}]},{"content":"This topic explains how distribute the questionnaires that you design, so that they are available to the person or group of people who will complete them.","pos":[890,1044]},{"content":"There are multiple ways to distribute a questionnaire:","pos":[1047,1101]},{"content":"Mark the questionnaire as active.","pos":[1107,1140]},{"content":"The questionnaire is then available to all employees, unless a questionnaire group is set up to restrict access to it.","pos":[1141,1259]},{"content":"Assign rights to a questionnaire group.","pos":[1264,1303]},{"content":"The questionnaire is then available to all members of the selected group.","pos":[1304,1377]},{"content":"Create planned answer sessions.","pos":[1382,1413]},{"content":"The questionnaire is then available only to a particular person.","pos":[1414,1478]},{"content":"Create a schedule.","pos":[1483,1501]},{"content":"The questionnaire can then be available to multiple people.","pos":[1502,1561]},{"pos":[1566,1599],"content":"Marking a questionnaire as active","linkify":"Marking a questionnaire as active","nodes":[{"content":"Marking a questionnaire as active","pos":[0,33]}]},{"content":"By setting the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Active<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Yes<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> on the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Questionnaires<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> page, you make the questionnaire available for all employees to complete.","pos":[1600,1742],"source":"By setting the **Active** field to **Yes** on the **Questionnaires** page, you make the questionnaire available for all employees to complete."},{"content":"Respondents can complete the questionnaire multiple times.","pos":[1743,1801]},{"content":"This functionality is useful if you want to gather continual feedback throughout the year.","pos":[1802,1892]},{"content":"For example, you can make a questionnaire that employees use to give feedback about the lunch service in the cafeteria.","pos":[1893,2012]},{"pos":[2017,2037],"content":"Questionnaire groups","linkify":"Questionnaire groups","nodes":[{"content":"Questionnaire groups","pos":[0,20]}]},{"content":"You can set up questionnaire groups and then include the respondents that a questionnaire should be distributed to.","pos":[2038,2153]},{"content":"You can create questionnaire groups from the following pages:","pos":[2156,2217]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Questionnaire groups<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Only individuals in a questionnaire group can complete a selected questionnaire.","pos":[2223,2330],"source":"**Questionnaire groups** – Only individuals in a questionnaire group can complete a selected questionnaire."},{"content":"For example, your intended audience is contractors, so you create a questionnaire group that is specific to those respondents.","pos":[2331,2457]},{"pos":[2462,2543],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Questionnaire group members<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – You can add people to the questionnaire groups.","source":"**Questionnaire group members** – You can add people to the questionnaire groups."},{"content":"To assign a questionnaire group to a questionnaire, on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Questionnaires<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>User rights<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[2545,2651],"source":"To assign a questionnaire group to a questionnaire, on the **Questionnaires** page, click **User rights**."},{"content":"After the questionnaire is saved as active, the members of the questionnaire group can complete the questionnaire.","pos":[2652,2766]},{"content":"This functionality is helpful if you want to test a questionnaire on a select group of people before you roll it out to a larger group, or if you want to target a questionnaire to a very specific audience.","pos":[2767,2972]},{"pos":[2977,3019],"content":"Planned answer sessions in a questionnaire","linkify":"Planned answer sessions in a questionnaire","nodes":[{"content":"Planned answer sessions in a questionnaire","pos":[0,42]}]},{"content":"Planned answer sessions are questionnaires that you've designed and selected the respondents for.","pos":[3020,3117]},{"pos":[3120,3209],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Before you can set up planned answer sessions, you must design a questionnaire.","source":"**Note:** Before you can set up planned answer sessions, you must design a questionnaire."},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Planned answer session<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, you can create a planned answer session for an individual employee.","pos":[3212,3319],"source":"On the **Planned answer session** page, you can create a planned answer session for an individual employee."},{"content":"The list on the page displays all planned questionnaires.","pos":[3320,3377]},{"pos":[3380,3513],"content":"Planned answer sessions are also used on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Questionnaire schedules<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, where you can plan questionnaires for multiple people:","source":"Planned answer sessions are also used on the **Questionnaire schedules** page, where you can plan questionnaires for multiple people:"},{"content":"Employees","pos":[3519,3528]},{"content":"Course participants","pos":[3533,3552]},{"content":"Organizational units","pos":[3557,3577]},{"content":"Each person can answer the questionnaire only one time.","pos":[3579,3634]},{"pos":[3639,3665],"content":"Scheduling a questionnaire","linkify":"Scheduling a questionnaire","nodes":[{"content":"Scheduling a questionnaire","pos":[0,26]}]},{"content":"You can optionally schedule a questionnaire for multiple respondents.","pos":[3666,3735]},{"pos":[3741,3755],"content":"Planning types","linkify":"Planning types","nodes":[{"content":"Planning types","pos":[0,14]}]},{"content":"Planning types are required if you want to schedule planned answer sessions for multiple respondents.","pos":[3757,3858]},{"content":"Planning types are used to classify questionnaire schedules.","pos":[3859,3919]},{"content":"For example, you can schedule questionnaires for the following purposes:","pos":[3920,3992]},{"content":"Evaluation","pos":[3998,4008]},{"content":"Survey","pos":[4013,4019]},{"content":"Testing","pos":[4024,4031]},{"pos":[4033,4133],"content":"You can specify planning types for a questionnaire schedule on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Questionnaire schedules<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","source":"You can specify planning types for a questionnaire schedule on the **Questionnaire schedules** page."},{"pos":[4139,4172],"content":"Reference types for questionnaire","linkify":"Reference types for questionnaire","nodes":[{"content":"Reference types for questionnaire","pos":[0,33]}]},{"content":"You can use reference types to enter criteria for the respondents that you might select when you schedule a questionnaire.","pos":[4174,4296]},{"content":"Use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Reference types<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page to set up reference types for a questionnaire.","pos":[4299,4378],"source":"Use the **Reference types** page to set up reference types for a questionnaire."},{"content":"Each reference type corresponds to a table in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise Edition.","pos":[4379,4495]},{"content":"When you create questionnaire schedules, you can specify individual records in the table or a range of records that the questionnaire will be associated with.","pos":[4496,4654]},{"content":"For example, if you select the Courses table, you can decide which specific course the questionnaire will be for.","pos":[4657,4770]},{"content":"When you set up a reference for the Courses table, some fields and buttons on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Courses<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page become available.","pos":[4771,4887],"source":" When you set up a reference for the Courses table, some fields and buttons on the **Courses** page become available."},{"pos":[4893,4916],"content":"Questionnaire schedules","linkify":"Questionnaire schedules","nodes":[{"content":"Questionnaire schedules","pos":[0,23]}]},{"content":"You can use questionnaire schedules to generate multiple planned answer sessions for a group of users, based on a reference type.","pos":[4918,5047]},{"content":"Create a schedule on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Questionnaire schedules<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[5048,5106],"source":" Create a schedule on the **Questionnaire schedules** page."},{"content":"Select the planning type to categorize the schedule, and also select the reference type that should be used to query the system for specific users.","pos":[5107,5254]},{"content":"For example, if you set the reference type to the Courses table, you can select a specific course in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Reference<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field.","pos":[5255,5380],"source":" For example, if you set the reference type to the Courses table, you can select a specific course in the **Reference** field."},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Setup details<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to select the questionnaire and other criteria.","pos":[5383,5454],"source":"Click **Setup details** to select the questionnaire and other criteria."},{"content":"For example, specify the instructor's name as a criterion if the questionnaire is an evaluation of the instructor.","pos":[5455,5569]},{"content":"After you've finished entering the setup details, the system generates planned answer sessions for the users that are included in the query.","pos":[5570,5710]},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Planned answer sessions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to view the answer sessions for the schedule.","pos":[5713,5792],"source":"Click **Planned answer sessions** to view the answer sessions for the schedule."},{"content":"You can then manually create additional planned answer sessions or delete planned answer sessions that haven't been answered.","pos":[5793,5918]},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Functions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Start<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to make the questionnaire available to the users in related planned answer sessions.","pos":[5921,6040],"source":"Click **Functions** &gt; **Start** to make the questionnaire available to the users in related planned answer sessions."},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Answers<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to view the completed responses to the questionnaire.","pos":[6041,6112],"source":" Click **Answers** to view the completed responses to the questionnaire."},{"content":"You can optionally copy the questionnaire schedule settings, planned answer sessions, and answers to a new questionnaire schedule.","pos":[6113,6243]},{"pos":[6248,6317],"content":"Notifying respondents about questionnaires that are available to them","linkify":"Notifying respondents about questionnaires that are available to them","nodes":[{"content":"Notifying respondents about questionnaires that are available to them","pos":[0,69]}]},{"content":"When you distribute a questionnaire, you must notify respondents that questionnaires are available to them.","pos":[6318,6425]},{"pos":[6428,6565],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Respondents must be users in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise Edition to complete a questionnaire.","source":"**Note:** Respondents must be users in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise Edition to complete a questionnaire."},{"pos":[6571,6623],"content":"Notifying respondents about a planned answer session","linkify":"Notifying respondents about a planned answer session","nodes":[{"content":"Notifying respondents about a planned answer session","pos":[0,52]}]},{"content":"If you use a planned answer session, you must notify the person directly, such as by telephone or email.","pos":[6625,6729]},{"pos":[6735,6775],"content":"Notifying respondents about a scheduling","linkify":"Notifying respondents about a scheduling","nodes":[{"content":"Notifying respondents about a scheduling","pos":[0,40]}]},{"content":"Use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Questionnaire schedules<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page to prepare and send email to all respondents who are assigned to the questionnaire.","pos":[6777,6901],"source":"Use the **Questionnaire schedules** page to prepare and send email to all respondents who are assigned to the questionnaire."},{"content":"Enter the email text on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>E-mail for employee self service<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab.","pos":[6902,6971],"source":" Enter the email text on the **E-mail for employee self service** tab."},{"content":"After the schedule has been started, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Functions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Send e-mail<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to generate and send the email to the respondents.","pos":[6972,7100],"source":" After the schedule has been started, click **Functions** &gt; **Send e-mail** to generate and send the email to the respondents."},{"content":"Respondents can then sign in to the website and complete the questionnaire.","pos":[7101,7176]},{"pos":[7179,7319],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Before you can use the email functionality, your IT administrator must enter the email settings on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>E-mail parameters<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page.","source":"**Note:** Before you can use the email functionality, your IT administrator must enter the email settings on the **E-mail parameters** page."},{"pos":[7324,7356],"content":"Ending a scheduled questionnaire","linkify":"Ending a scheduled questionnaire","nodes":[{"content":"Ending a scheduled questionnaire","pos":[0,32]}]},{"content":"You can end a scheduled questionnaire after all respondents have completed their assigned answer sessions.","pos":[7357,7463]},{"content":"After a scheduled questionnaire is ended, you can't copy its settings to a new schedule.","pos":[7464,7552]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> If one or more respondents haven't completed the questionnaire, but you still want to end the scheduling, you must first delete those respondents from the list on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Planned answer session<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page.","pos":[7555,7764],"source":"**Note:** If one or more respondents haven't completed the questionnaire, but you still want to end the scheduling, you must first delete those respondents from the list on the **Planned answer session** page."},{"content":"You can then end the schedule.","pos":[7765,7795]},{"pos":[7800,7825],"content":"Completing questionnaires","linkify":"Completing questionnaires","nodes":[{"content":"Completing questionnaires","pos":[0,25]}]},{"content":"After you've designed and distributed a questionnaire, the questionnaire can be completed by selected respondents.","pos":[7826,7940]},{"content":"You can complete the questionnaires that are available to you from two locations:","pos":[7941,8022]},{"pos":[8028,8131],"content":"In the navigation pane, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Questionnaires<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Distribute<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Complete a questionnaire<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.","source":"In the navigation pane, click **Questionnaires** &gt; **Distribute** &gt; **Complete a questionnaire**."},{"pos":[8136,8199],"content":"In Employee self-service, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Questionnaires to complete<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"In Employee self-service, click **Questionnaires to complete**."},{"content":"Questionnaires can made be available to specific users or groups of users, or to all users in a network.","pos":[8201,8305]},{"pos":[8307,8315],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[8326,8378],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Designing questionnaires<ept id=\"p1\">](design-questionnaires.md)</ept>","source":"[Designing questionnaires](design-questionnaires.md)"},{"pos":[8380,8421],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Using questionnaires<ept id=\"p1\">](questionnaires.md)</ept>","source":"[Using questionnaires](questionnaires.md)"},{"pos":[8423,8512],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Viewing and evaluating the results of questionnaires<ept id=\"p1\">](evaluate-questionnaire-results.md)</ept>","source":"[Viewing and evaluating the results of questionnaires](evaluate-questionnaire-results.md)"}]}